<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/merged-feed/merged.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS from multiple sources</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/merged-feed/merged.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 23:13:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ultra-processed foods might not be the real villain in our diets – here’s what our research found</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ultra-processed-foods-might-not-be-the-real-villain-in-our-diets-heres-what-our-research-found-261867</link><description>Chocolate and porridge are both popular but only one gets binged. Why? Our psychology plays a bigger role in overeating than food labels alone.</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:42:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Do people dream in color or black and white?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/do-people-dream-in-color-or-black-and-white-256971</link><description>Researchers have found dreams are most likely to occur during the stage of sleep known as rapid eye movement, or REM.</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:46:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Drought can make farmers feel worried and hopeless: Ghana study finds social networks help</title><link>https://theconversation.com/drought-can-make-farmers-feel-worried-and-hopeless-ghana-study-finds-social-networks-help-262627</link><description>Drought adversely affects the mental health of Ghanaian farmers.</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 14:02:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why do smart people get hooked on wellness trends? Personality traits may play a role</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-do-smart-people-get-hooked-on-wellness-trends-personality-traits-may-play-a-role-263041</link><description>Certain personality traits may help explain why some educated, well-intentioned people sometimes reject conventional medicine in favour of fringe practices.</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:35:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Are you really an ISFJ? The truth about personality tests – and why we keep taking them</title><link>https://theconversation.com/are-you-really-an-isfj-the-truth-about-personality-tests-and-why-we-keep-taking-them-261183</link><description>Tests such as Myers-Briggs promise self-discovery – but here’s why you shouldn’t take them too seriously.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 05:11:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1 in 3 teens has thought about suicide this year. Here’s what to look for – and where to get help</title><link>https://theconversation.com/1-in-3-teens-has-thought-about-suicide-this-year-heres-what-to-look-for-and-where-to-get-help-263422</link><description>A suicide attempt doesn’t always involve prior planning or thinking. But there are warnings signs.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 05:18:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why people embrace conspiracy theories: it’s about community, not gullibility</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-people-embrace-conspiracy-theories-its-about-community-not-gullibility-262276</link><description>Far from being isolated outsiders, conspiracy theorists enjoy thriving communities that recruit and organise activism.</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 12:09:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eating disorder symptoms in teens can be traced back to family hardship, new study shows</title><link>https://theconversation.com/eating-disorder-symptoms-in-teens-can-be-traced-back-to-family-hardship-new-study-shows-263529</link><description>It’s a stereotype that eating disorders mainly affect people from wealthy backgrounds.</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 01:28:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Burnt out and radicalised: how workplace exhaustion breeds extremist thinking – new study</title><link>https://theconversation.com/burnt-out-and-radicalised-how-workplace-exhaustion-breeds-extremist-thinking-new-study-261123</link><description>Our research found a link between burnout and support for extremist violence.</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 08:28:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Defendants in sexual assault cases are just as likely to misremember the event as alleged victims – new study</title><link>https://theconversation.com/defendants-in-sexual-assault-cases-are-just-as-likely-to-misremember-the-event-as-alleged-victims-new-study-262841</link><description>In court, scrutiny is normally focused on the alleged victim’s ability to recall details from the event.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 10:05:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Phubbing’: why ignoring your partner for your phone infuriates certain people – and causes them to retaliate</title><link>https://theconversation.com/phubbing-why-ignoring-your-partner-for-your-phone-infuriates-certain-people-and-causes-them-to-retaliate-263963</link><description>Research shows that ‘phubbing’ – ignoring a partner to look at your phone – can lower relationship satisfaction and spark retaliation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 10:50:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why scammers fake illness for cash, according to a psychologist</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-scammers-fake-illness-for-cash-according-to-a-psychologist-263264</link><description>What type of person lies to friends and family about having cancer?</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 20:03:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What does it mean to become an adult? In Namibia, it’s caring for others</title><link>https://theconversation.com/what-does-it-mean-to-become-an-adult-in-namibia-its-caring-for-others-263223</link><description>There is no single way of becoming an adult in the world.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 13:53:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>65,000 Pennsylvania kids have a parent in prison or jail − here’s what research says about the value of in-person visits</title><link>https://theconversation.com/65-000-pennsylvania-kids-have-a-parent-in-prison-or-jail-heres-what-research-says-about-the-value-of-in-person-visits-262185</link><description>In-person visits in prisons and jails can strengthen family relationships and reduce recidivism.</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 12:28:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Not to worry, no giant radioactive wasps here</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735591-500-not-to-worry-no-giant-radioactive-wasps-here/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Feedback remembers Godzilla, and feels a little nervous about the wasp nest found at an old nuclear weapons site in South Carolina</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Powerful images show dark side of South-East Asia’s fishing industry</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495209-powerful-images-show-dark-side-of-south-east-asias-fishing-industry/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Photographer Nicole Tung captures the tough world facing South-East Asia’s fishers and their families in this series of images, which won her the Carmignac Photojournalism Award for fieldwork</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 21:00:18 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>We’ve glimpsed the secret quantum landscape inside all matter</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494508-weve-glimpsed-the-secret-quantum-landscape-inside-all-matter/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A strange kind of geometry governs how particles move inside matter. Now, for the first time, physicists have uncovered its full shape – and it could transform how we design materials</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:00:16 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What we’ve learned about narcissism over the past 30 years</title><link>https://theconversation.com/what-weve-learned-about-narcissism-over-the-past-30-years-258505</link><description>Narcissism is a picture that includes insecurity, emotional sensitivity and surprising fragility.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 14:27:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exoplanet 40 light years from Earth may have right conditions for life</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495349-exoplanet-40-light-years-from-earth-may-have-right-conditions-for-life/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The planet TRAPPIST-1e lies in its star’s Goldilocks zone, where water remains liquid – and an analysis suggests it might have a nitrogen-rich atmosphere like Earth’s</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 17:00:50 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Can a strange new treatment finally relieve chronic sinus infections?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494362-can-a-strange-new-treatment-finally-relieve-chronic-sinus-infections/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Constant loss of smell, facial pain and a blocked nose are a reality for the 10 per cent of people living with chronic rhinosinusitis, a disease long-neglected by research. Targeting the nasal microbiome, though, is offering hope</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:00:19 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Mass hysteria at Heathrow airport – how social contagion works</title><link>https://theconversation.com/mass-hysteria-at-heathrow-airport-how-social-contagion-works-264900</link><description>Heathrow’s Terminal 4 evacuation shows the power of social contagion.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:02:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How our minds trick us into thinking we are being greener than we really are</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-our-minds-trick-us-into-thinking-we-are-being-greener-than-we-really-are-263959</link><description>Adding “green” products to your food basket doesn’t reduce its carbon footprint – even though we think it does.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:37:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Earth’s climate in a state of 'termination shock'?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494279-is-earths-climate-in-a-state-of-termination-shock/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Cleaning up air pollution has saved millions of lives, but it has also given us an inadvertent taste of a nightmare climate scenario. The race is on to understand how bad it could be – and how to swerve the worst effects</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:00:31 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Social media is teaching children how to use AI. How can teachers keep up?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/social-media-is-teaching-children-how-to-use-ai-how-can-teachers-keep-up-264727</link><description>AI is transforming classrooms, yet most learning is informal. Teacher education and clear policies are vital to ensure AI supports equity, trust and pedagogy.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 12:11:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Which perimenopause treatments actually work?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2493005-which-perimenopause-treatments-actually-work/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>For women going through perimenopause, there is no shortage of advice on how to deal with the symptoms – but which strategies show real results, and which are social media hype?</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 17:00:34 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Gravitational waves finally prove Stephen Hawking's black hole theorem</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495377-gravitational-waves-finally-prove-stephen-hawkings-black-hole-theorem/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>An exceptionally loud collision between two black holes has been detected by the LIGO gravitational wave observatory, enabling physicists to test a theorem postulated by Stephen Hawking in 1971</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 17:00:58 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Even in our digital world, materials still matter</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735602-700-even-in-our-digital-world-materials-still-matter/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Next to the flashy realm of AI, materials may seem quaint. But new quantum research could yield revolutionary breakthroughs, with the power to transform our world</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Tim Spector's guide to fermentation is meticulous and persuasive</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735600-300-tim-spectors-guide-to-fermentation-is-meticulous-and-persuasive/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>We know fermented foods do us good, but the ZOE founder's new book still surprises with fascinating facts - and avoids feeling like an ad for his gut supplements, says Helen Thomson</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Why your nose could be the perfect window into your mental state</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735602-500-why-your-nose-could-be-the-perfect-window-into-your-mental-state/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Diagnosing mental health conditions like anxiety and depression can be difficult, but it turns out that your nose could help doctors understand when you are feeling the strain, says Gillian Forrester</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Exciting new research shows ways to defuse the "green backlash"</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735600-100-exciting-new-research-shows-ways-to-defuse-the-green-backlash/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>There is growing opposition to environmental policies around the world, but could researchers have found a way around this, asks Graham Lawton</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Matt Richtel grapples with how modern life is warping adolescence</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735600-400-matt-richtel-grapples-with-how-modern-life-is-warping-adolescence/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Not only are children starting puberty earlier, they face a digital world where, for good and bad, most of their interactions are internalised. How We Grow Up is scary, illuminating and hopeful, says Chris Simms</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Alien: Earth adds surprisingly good TV dimension to veteran sci-fi</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735600-600-alien-earth-adds-surprisingly-good-tv-dimension-to-veteran-sci-fi/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>After 50 years of books, games and movies, what more could the Alien franchise deliver? An inventive TV show, with fresh monsters and new heroes, finds our TV critic Bethan Ackerley</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How to pick the right fertiliser for all your different plants</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735602-600-how-to-pick-the-right-fertiliser-for-all-your-different-plants/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>There are three key nutrients that all plants need – nitrogen, phosphorous and potassium – but in different amounts. So finding fertiliser that suits all your plants might seem tricky, but there is a simple solution, says James Wong</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Telling incoming aliens from space rocks… on a scale of 1 to 10!</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735601-600-telling-incoming-aliens-from-space-rocks-on-a-scale-of-1-to-10/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Feedback is mystified by a new way to assess interstellar visitors and the risks they pose, be they lumps of ice or alien craft. Just pray they don’t top out on the Loeb Scale</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antibody cocktail could work as a universal flu treatment</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495871-antibody-cocktail-could-work-as-a-universal-flu-treatment/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A mix of three antibodies seems to protect mice against several strains of influenza and could one day be useful against seasonal flu or pandemics</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 20:00:06 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>DNA cassette tape can store every song ever recorded</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495758-dna-cassette-tape-can-store-every-song-ever-recorded/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>By combining the information storage capabilities of DNA with a design inspired by a cassette tape, researchers have created a storage medium that can hold 36 petabytes of data</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 20:00:34 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Deflecting a deadly asteroid just got a lot less dangerous</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495795-deflecting-a-deadly-asteroid-just-got-a-lot-less-dangerous/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Our first attempt at shifting the orbit of an asteroid has provided crucial insight into how we could safely deflect a space rock that was hurtling towards Earth</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 11:00:32 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Britain's economy thrived after the withdrawal of the Roman Empire</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495847-britains-economy-thrived-after-the-withdrawal-of-the-roman-empire/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>An archaeological dig in northern England shows iron and lead processing continued and even increased after the departure of the Romans</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 11:00:34 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Why simple tasks like charging your phone rely on quantum measurements</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495951-why-simple-tasks-like-charging-your-phone-rely-on-quantum-measurements/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A hidden world of quantum metrologists ensure that everyday devices perform safely and correctly, but their work is never done</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 15:00:07 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Early Neanderthals hunted ibex on steep mountain slopes</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495962-early-neanderthals-hunted-ibex-on-steep-mountain-slopes/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Ancient remains from a cave in Serbia show that Neanderthals were hunting mountain goats 300,000 years ago, adding to evidence of their ability to adapt to different environments</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 17:00:35 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A weird cloud forms on Mars each year and now we know why</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495985-a-weird-cloud-forms-on-mars-each-year-and-now-we-know-why/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Astronomers have struggled to explain why a long and thin cloud forms above Mars’s Arsia Mons volcano each year, until now</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 18:00:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>AI hype has just shaken up the world’s rich list. What if the boom is really a bubble?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-hype-has-just-shaken-up-the-worlds-rich-list-what-if-the-boom-is-really-a-bubble-265080</link><description>Larry Ellison’s moment in the spotlight has illuminated how extraordinarily exposed the global markets – and Australians’ superannuation – are to the AI boom.</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 05:11:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jupiter is smaller and more squashed than we thought</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496032-jupiter-is-smaller-and-more-squashed-than-we-thought/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The gas giant has been measured for the first time in decades, trimming 8 kilometres from its diameter</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 11:00:39 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Hedonistic habits could turn you into a mosquito magnet</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496103-hedonistic-habits-could-turn-you-into-a-mosquito-magnet/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A study of festivalgoers suggests that drinking beer and sharing a bed makes you more attractive to mosquitoes</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 14:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Child obesity is now more common than undernutrition – what do we do?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496086-child-obesity-is-now-more-common-than-undernutrition-what-do-we-do/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Childhood obesity rates have surpassed those of undernutrition for the first time, suggesting efforts to combat malnutrition will have to shift gears.</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:57:48 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Why OpenAI’s solution to AI hallucinations would kill ChatGPT tomorrow</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-openais-solution-to-ai-hallucinations-would-kill-chatgpt-tomorrow-265107</link><description>The cure is likely to be worse than the disease.</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 15:58:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regulating AI use could stop its runaway energy expansion</title><link>https://theconversation.com/regulating-ai-use-could-stop-its-runaway-energy-expansion-258425</link><description>We are building an AI-powered future that consumes like an industrial past.</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 15:59:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jaguar breaks records by swimming at least 1.3 kilometres</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496123-jaguar-breaks-records-by-swimming-at-least-1-3-kilometres/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A 1.3-kilometre swim by a jaguar is the longest ever confirmed, but the cat's motives for making the journey are unclear</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 18:00:59 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Politicians are pushing AI as a quick fix to Australia’s housing crisis. They’re risking another Robodebt</title><link>https://theconversation.com/politicians-are-pushing-ai-as-a-quick-fix-to-australias-housing-crisis-theyre-risking-another-robodebt-265062</link><description>If governments now see AI as a tool to reform housing planning and assessments, they shouldn’t rush headlong.</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 20:13:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Higher dose of Wegovy ups both weight loss and side effects</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496140-higher-dose-of-wegovy-ups-both-weight-loss-and-side-effects/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Trial participants who received an increased weekly dose of Wegovy lost 19 per cent of their body weight in a year on average, but also saw a higher risk of painful skin sensations and nausea</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:30:21 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The death of dinosaurs dramatically re-engineered Earth's landscapes</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496215-the-death-of-dinosaurs-dramatically-re-engineered-earths-landscapes/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Changes in rock formations from before and after the mass extinction event 66 million years ago may reflect how dinosaurs acted as ecosystem engineers, shaping vegetation and even the meandering of rivers</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 11:43:45 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Stealth radio hides signal in background noise to protect drone pilots</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495997-stealth-radio-hides-signal-in-background-noise-to-protect-drone-pilots/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>As drones have risen to prominence on the battlefield, so too has electronic warfare, in which adversaries attempt to mask, jam or trace radio signals. Now, a new stealthy radio device could help give people the edge, letting them fly drones without detection</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 13:00:57 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Covid-19 vaccine benefits worth up to $38 trillion in first year alone</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496200-covid-19-vaccine-benefits-worth-up-to-38-trillion-in-first-year-alone/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The global health and economic benefits of covid-19 vaccines came to between $5 trillion and $38 trillion in their first year, showing an incredible return on investment</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 16:00:24 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What it’s like to run the world’s best dark matter detector</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2493944-what-its-like-to-run-the-worlds-best-dark-matter-detector/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Chamkaur Ghag is on a mission to find the 85 per cent of the universe’s matter that we haven’t yet identified. He details his hopes for the major scientific experiment – and what the future could hold</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:00:42 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Racism isn’t innate – here are five psychological stages that may lead to it</title><link>https://theconversation.com/racism-isnt-innate-here-are-five-psychological-stages-that-may-lead-to-it-264391</link><description>There is no genetic or biological basis for dividing the human race into distinct “races.”</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mars once had an atmosphere that was thicker than Earth's today</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496379-mars-once-had-an-atmosphere-that-was-thicker-than-earths-today/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>While Mars today only has a wispy remnant of an atmosphere, it may once have had one hundreds of times thicker with a pressure three times that on Earth</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 19:00:37 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Modular nuclear reactors sound great, but won't be ready any time soon</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496252-modular-nuclear-reactors-sound-great-but-wont-be-ready-any-time-soon/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The UK government has announced a raft of tiny nuclear power projects, while Russia, China and a host of tech giants are also betting big on small nuclear reactor designs. Does the idea make sense and can they really be built any time soon?</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 19:46:47 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The oldest human mummies were slowly smoked 14,000 years ago</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496267-the-oldest-human-mummies-were-slowly-smoked-14000-years-ago/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>For at least 10,000 years, humans across South-East Asia were being carefully preserved after death by being smoke-dried – a tradition that continues to this day in some cultures</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:00:28 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>AI companies want copyright exemptions – for NZ creatives, the market is their best protection</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-companies-want-copyright-exemptions-for-nz-creatives-the-market-is-their-best-protection-264468</link><description>AI ‘learns’ by digesting copyright-protected material, with billions at stake. Proper licensing deals offer the best solution for authors, artists and publishers.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 23:35:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lunar missions may contaminate the moon with hardy Earth microbes</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496319-lunar-missions-may-contaminate-the-moon-with-hardy-earth-microbes/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Experiments on Earth indicate some common species of bacteria and fungi could survive for several days on the moon's surface, suggesting missions must take stronger precautions to avoid contamination</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 09:00:09 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Good immune health may come at the expense of chronic inflammation</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496443-good-immune-health-may-come-at-the-expense-of-chronic-inflammation/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Inflammation is a vital part of the immune response, but it seems that the system can sometimes go awry, resulting in chronic inflammation that has been linked to conditions such as cancer</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 12:03:30 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Making atoms self-magnify reveals their quantum wave functions</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496211-making-atoms-self-magnify-reveals-their-quantum-wave-functions/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Trapping ultracold atoms with laser light let researchers magnify and then image the wave functions of atoms that were previously too close together to look like anything but a blob</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 13:00:42 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Around one-third of AI search tool answers make unsupported claims</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496133-around-one-third-of-ai-search-tool-answers-make-unsupported-claims/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>AI tools including Perplexity and Open AI’s GPT-4 often provide one-sided answers to contentious questions, and don’t back up their arguments with reliable sources</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:00:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Ozone Layer Recovery Continues under Montreal Protocol</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/ozone-layer-recovery-continues-under-montreal-protocol/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After nearly 40 years of global efforts, the ozone hole over Antarctica is continuing to heal&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The real scientific insights from Bryan Johnson’s immortality quest</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495156-the-real-scientific-insights-from-bryan-johnsons-immortality-quest/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Tech millionaire turned longevity pioneer Bryan Johnson devotes more than 6 hours a day to trialling different methods to turn back the clock. Can the rest of us learn anything from his radical approach?</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:01 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What’s the secret to living well beyond the average life expectancy?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495136-whats-the-secret-to-living-well-beyond-the-average-life-expectancy/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Many of us know people who live into their 90s, but hardly anyone makes it to 100. Studies are now revealing that factors that really make a difference</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:11 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How to nurture the right mindset for living to 100</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495108-how-to-nurture-the-right-mindset-for-living-to-100/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>It’s not just diet and exercise that governs how well you age. Your mindset, social connections and sense of purpose make a big difference, and it’s never too late to start working on them</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:13 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Why caring for your microbiome is crucial if you want to live to 100</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494981-why-caring-for-your-microbiome-is-crucial-if-you-want-to-live-to-100/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Our friendly – and not so friendly – gut bacteria lie at the core of healthy ageing. Research is now revealing what it takes to maintain a youthful microbiome</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:48 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The exercises you need to do to reach 100 in great shape</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494852-the-exercises-you-need-to-do-to-reach-100-in-great-shape/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>To be truly fit in older age, you need to work on specific aspects of your fitness – and research shows that it’s never too late to reap the benefits</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The science revealing how the right diet can add a decade to your life</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494953-the-science-revealing-how-the-right-diet-can-add-a-decade-to-your-life/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Evidence shows that eating a longevity diet can dramatically lengthen your lifespan – and the sooner you start, the more of a difference it makes</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:57 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Long covid may be making your periods longer and heavier</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496524-long-covid-may-be-making-your-periods-longer-and-heavier/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Half a decade since the arrival of the SARS-CoV-2 virus, we're still learning about its complications, with the latest research suggesting that long covid may disrupt menstrual periods</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 18:04:50 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>30,000-year-old toolkit shows what ancient hunter carried in a pouch</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496225-30000-year-old-toolkit-shows-what-ancient-hunter-carried-in-a-pouch/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A set of 29 stone tools, including blades and points for hunting, butchering and cutting wood, were found neatly arranged as if carried in a leather pouch that decayed</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 19:01:13 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Our new study found AI is wreaking havoc on uni assessments. Here’s how we should respond</title><link>https://theconversation.com/our-new-study-found-ai-is-wreaking-havoc-on-uni-assessments-heres-how-we-should-respond-264787</link><description>New research argues the problem of AI and assessment is way more difficult than media debates have been making out.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 20:10:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate Change Fuels Record Summer Heat, Killing Thousands</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/climate-change-fuels-record-summer-heat-killing-thousands/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Climate-fueled heat has caused thousands of excess deaths over the past three summers, which were the three hottest on record&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Politics with Michelle Grattan: Tony Wood on ‘politics trumping climate policy’ and the hard road ahead</title><link>https://theconversation.com/politics-with-michelle-grattan-tony-wood-on-politics-trumping-climate-policy-and-the-hard-road-ahead-265474</link><description>The energy expert says Australia’s only on track to cut its emissions by around 50% by 2035 – ‘so we’re going to have to step up the pace’ in the next decade.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 07:13:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Serious mental illness often brings rapid weight gain – but support is missing</title><link>https://theconversation.com/serious-mental-illness-often-brings-rapid-weight-gain-but-support-is-missing-264842</link><description>People with schizophrenia and bipolar disorder gain 5kg in five years. The average person gains 1.5kg.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 09:24:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New Research Shows Gut Cells Communicate Directly with the Brain</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/new-research-shows-gut-cells-communicate-directly-with-the-brain/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists are uncovering how your gut might be shaping your thoughts, feelings and cravings.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asteroid exploded 'similar to a bomb' over France in a rare event</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496598-asteroid-exploded-similar-to-a-bomb-over-france-in-a-rare-event/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>An asteroid called 2023 CX1 underwent a single explosion, hinting that it had an unusual structure that might be more damaging on the ground</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 11:00:35 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Impostor syndrome: the cost of being ‘superwoman’ at work and beyond</title><link>https://theconversation.com/impostor-syndrome-the-cost-of-being-superwoman-at-work-and-beyond-265218</link><description>Female leaders are under pressure to excel, professionally and personally, without showing weakness or strain. The emergence of neoliberal feminism helps explain why, and a milestone in psychology describes what can result.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 10:22:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global suicide rates fell 30 per cent since 1990 – but not in the US</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496424-global-suicide-rates-fell-30-per-cent-since-1990-but-not-in-the-us/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>While most countries have seen a steady decline in suicide rates, the United States has witnessed the opposite, with suicides jumping almost 30 per cent since 2000</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 14:00:12 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Is sleeping outside good for you? Science has a clear answer.</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/is-sleeping-outside-good-for-you/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A night under the stars can reset your body's clock, reduce stress, and more—but it might not benefit everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/is-sleeping-outside-good-for-you/"&gt;Is sleeping outside good for you? Science has a clear answer.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 09:01:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>This is the biggest sofa you can fit around a corner, according to a mathematician</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/gervers-sofa-problem-solved/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s hope your couch is shaped like an old-fashioned telephone receiver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/gervers-sofa-problem-solved/"&gt;This is the biggest sofa you can fit around a corner, according to a mathematician&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>A zookeeper’s burnt lunch revealed a lizard’s secret survival skill</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/sleepy-lizard-smoke-sense/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Australia’s sleepy lizards know to go when they smell smoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/sleepy-lizard-smoke-sense/"&gt;A zookeeper&amp;#8217;s burnt lunch revealed a lizard&amp;#8217;s secret survival skill&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 10:56:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Oldest Known Pachycephalosaur Fossil Discovered in Mongolia</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/oldest-known-pachycephalosaur-fossil-discovered-in-mongolia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A newly discovered dinosaur species has been identified from a fossil unearthed in Mongolia that represents the most complete pachycephalosaur specimen yet found&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>18 majestic images from the 2025 Audubon Photography Awards</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/audubon-photography-awards-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Bird photos that really take flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/audubon-photography-awards-2025/"&gt;18 majestic images from the 2025 Audubon Photography Awards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Stretching the skin could enable vaccines to be given without a needle</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496664-stretching-the-skin-could-enable-vaccines-to-be-given-without-a-needle/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Using a suction device to stretch the skin seems to increase its permeability and stimulate immune cells, which could allow vaccines to be administered topically</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:00:29 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Dome-headed dinosaur from Mongolia is the oldest ever found</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496656-dome-headed-dinosaur-from-mongolia-is-the-oldest-ever-found/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A fossil from about 108 million years ago reveals an early member of the pachycephalosaurs, a group of dinosaurs with bizarre protrusions on their skulls that may have been used in combat</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:00:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Caribbean coral reefs are running out of time to keep up with rising seas – new study</title><link>https://theconversation.com/caribbean-coral-reefs-are-running-out-of-time-to-keep-up-with-rising-seas-new-study-265203</link><description>Coral reefs will stop growing and many will start to erode if global warming hits 2°C, according to a new study of 400 sites.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 16:17:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>262 million birds forecast to take to the skies tonight</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/birds-migrating-tonight/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BirdCast can help you follow their fall migration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/birds-migrating-tonight/"&gt;262 million birds forecast to take to the skies tonight&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 12:42:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Vaccines Are at Risk, Fired CDC Director Warns Senators</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/vaccines-are-at-risk-fired-cdc-director-warns-senators/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Former CDC chief Susan Monarez testified that Secretary of Health and Human Services Robert F. Kennedy, Jr., had demanded she rubber-stamp recommendations from his remade vaccine panel&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bronze Age farmers often prioritized wine over olives</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/wine-bronze-age/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Both fruits have been a staple of agriculture for 10,000 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/wine-bronze-age/"&gt;Bronze Age farmers often prioritized wine over olives&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The real reason our weather is going to the dogs</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735614-600-the-real-reason-our-weather-is-going-to-the-dogs/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Feedback was amazed to hear that dog ownership could cause a hurricane across the other side of the world. Or are we barking up the wrong tree?</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>In the race to reach 100, the wealthy have a head start</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735612-800-in-the-race-to-reach-100-the-wealthy-have-a-head-start/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>There are more centenarians now than ever before. But more must be done to address inequalities that prevent people from having a realistic chance of hitting this milestone.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Steven Pinker’s new book shows how he’s become a contradictory figure</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735610-200-steven-pinkers-new-book-shows-how-hes-become-a-contradictory-figure/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Steven Pinker’s new book When Everyone Knows That Everyone Knows makes a compelling case for common knowledge. Shame the politics muddies the waters</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A radical idea to fix plastics recycling</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735611-900-a-radical-idea-to-fix-plastics-recycling/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Making all shampoo or detergent bottles look the same isn't anti-capitalist, and it's the only way to make a truly circular economy for plastics, says Saabira Chaudhuri</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Where’s my jetpack got to? And other sci-fi tech queries</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735610-100-wheres-my-jetpack-got-to-and-other-sci-fi-tech-queries/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>We are still waiting for the retro-futuristic tech and social revolutions envisioned in science fiction’s old gold, writes Annalee Newitz – not to mention advances in reproduction</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Ian McEwan’s new novel weaves climate change into literary mystery</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735610-500-ian-mcewans-new-novel-weaves-climate-change-into-literary-mystery/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Ian McEwan’s excellent What We Can Know is set in a UK largely swallowed up by rising seas. Emily H. Wilson explores the story of a scholar hunting a great lost poem – which may have something to with climate change</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Three simple rules for a great post-workout meal</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735610-800-three-simple-rules-for-a-great-post-workout-meal/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Taking care of your body’s nutritional needs after training doesn't have to be a headache. Grace Wade sums up three key pillars she uses to refuel with confidence</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Dramatic photos show bid to save the Javan slow loris</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735612-000-dramatic-photos-show-bid-to-save-the-javan-slow-loris/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The photos tell an unusual rescue story – the release of the critically endangered Javan slow lorises into Ujung Kulon National Park on Java Island, Indonesia, last month.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Chimpanzee Consumption of Boozy Fruit May Illuminate Roots of Humanity’s Love of Alcohol</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/chimpanzee-consumption-of-boozy-fruit-may-illuminate-roots-of-humanitys-love/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wild chimps ingest the equivalent of multiple alcoholic beverages a day&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wild chimpanzees may get mildly intoxicated from alcoholic fruit</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496701-wild-chimpanzees-may-get-mildly-intoxicated-from-alcoholic-fruit/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Chimpanzees are consuming significant levels of alcohol from their diet of ripe fruit and the finding may help explain the origins of humans’ taste for alcohol</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 20:00:18 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Lost mural reveals ancient Silk Road fire ritual</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/fire-mural-sogdian-tajikistan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The ruins of a palace in Tajikistan offer a glimpse into the Sogdians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/fire-mural-sogdian-tajikistan/"&gt;Lost mural reveals ancient Silk Road fire ritual&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 15:12:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>COVID Vaccine Access Now Varies from State to State. Here's What to Know</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/covid-vaccine-access-now-varies-from-state-to-state-heres-what-to-know/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With federal vaccine guidance under fire, states are forging their own immunization paths&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New species of coral named after Chewbacca</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/chewbacca-coral/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hrrraaaaawwwwwwwwrrrrrr!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/chewbacca-coral/"&gt;New species of coral named after Chewbacca&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 15:31:20 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Heat, air quality, insurance costs: how climate change is affecting our homes – and our health</title><link>https://theconversation.com/heat-air-quality-insurance-costs-how-climate-change-is-affecting-our-homes-and-our-health-263278</link><description>Our homes can and must protect us against some of the risks of climate change.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 20:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Last Americans Really Paying Taxes</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/taxes-managers-class-trump/684193/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The tax code is becoming more chaotic and less fair.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 16:23:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Secrets of Chinese AI Model DeepSeek Revealed in Landmark Paper</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/secrets-of-chinese-ai-model-deepseek-revealed-in-landmark-paper/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The first peer-reviewed study of the DeepSeek AI model shows how a Chinese start-up firm made the market-shaking LLM for $300,000&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 21:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vitamin D supplements may lower your level of one type of vitamin D</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496879-vitamin-d-supplements-may-lower-your-level-of-one-type-of-vitamin-d/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Taking vitamin D2 supplements seems to reduce levels of vitamin D3 in our body</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:01:51 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Government announces 2035 target of 62–70% emissions reduction</title><link>https://theconversation.com/government-announces-2035-target-of-62-70-emissions-reduction-265381</link><description>The Albanese government has announced Australia will commit to cutting emissions by between 62% and 70% on 2005 levels by 2035.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 04:09:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Albanese government has finally set a 2035 climate course – and it’s a mission Australia must accept</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-albanese-government-has-finally-set-a-2035-climate-course-and-its-a-mission-australia-must-accept-264885</link><description>The target seeks to balance positive action with pragmatism. Achieving it will requires a major policy step-up.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 04:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cut emissions 70% by 2035? There’s only one policy that can get us there</title><link>https://theconversation.com/cut-emissions-70-by-2035-theres-only-one-policy-that-can-get-us-there-264884</link><description>To cut emissions fast, the Australian government will have to dial back its command-and-control approach –&amp;nbsp;and put a price on carbon.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 06:50:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Simple menu tweak can nudge people into choosing climate-friendly food</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496570-simple-menu-tweak-can-nudge-people-into-choosing-climate-friendly-food/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Rejigging the meal choices on offer in a canteen can prompt people to make healthier, climate-friendlier decisions</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 09:00:10 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Quantum computers are finally on the verge of being useful</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496013-quantum-computers-are-finally-on-the-verge-of-being-useful/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Two experiments with different quantum computers showcase their growing ability to simulate materials and quantum matter that have so far proven elusive in the lab</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:00:29 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How Geocaching Became a Global GPS Treasure Hunt over 25 Years</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-geocaching-became-a-global-gps-treasure-hunt-over-25-years/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;These hobbyists use GPS coordinates to hunt for secret prizes around the world&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why People Fell for an Outlandish Charlie Kirk Theory</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/charlie-kirk-shooter-groyper/684244/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Political violence is a curse for which both the left and right have, at different times, been responsible.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How a Contentious CDC Vaccine Meeting Will Affect Public Health</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-a-contentious-cdc-vaccine-meeting-will-affect-public-health/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Three vaccines were on the agenda for this week&amp;rsquo;s meeting of ACIP, the CDC&amp;rsquo;s key advisory panel on immunization: the combined measles, mumps, rubella and varicella vaccine, the hepatitis B vaccine and COVID vaccines&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Curious kids: why do we dream?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/curious-kids-why-do-we-dream-264817</link><description>Why scientists still can’t agree what dreams are for.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 12:09:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scams and frauds: Here are the tactics criminals use on you in the age of AI and cryptocurrencies</title><link>https://theconversation.com/scams-and-frauds-here-are-the-tactics-criminals-use-on-you-in-the-age-of-ai-and-cryptocurrencies-264867</link><description>Technology has supercharged fraud. The ruses are ancient, but the tools scammers use are cutting edge.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 12:46:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The 21 grams experiment that tried to weigh a human soul</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/21-grams-experiment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 1907, Duncan MacDougall put dying patients on a scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/21-grams-experiment/"&gt;The 21 grams experiment that tried to weigh a human soul&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The War Hawk Who Wasn’t</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/mcnamara-vietnam-war/684241/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Newly discovered documents reveal Robert McNamara’s private doubts about Vietnam.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>A walk across Alaska’s Arctic sea ice brings to life the losses that appear in climate data</title><link>https://theconversation.com/a-walk-across-alaskas-arctic-sea-ice-brings-to-life-the-losses-that-appear-in-climate-data-254910</link><description>A polar scientist explains the changes hunters who rely on the ice are seeing off Utqiagvik, and how those shifts are echoed in satellite data and climate models.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:40:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Constitution Protects Jimmy Kimmel’s Mistake</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/this-wont-stop-with-jimmy-kimmel/684251/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Free speech is under assault.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 09:42:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Dogs can learn and remember how toys work</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/dogs-know-how-toys-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The process is similar to how human babies learn that bowls and spoons are used to eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/dogs-know-how-toys-work/"&gt;Dogs can learn and remember how toys work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Dogs with Large Vocabularies Can Understand Category Words, Not Just Names</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/dogs-with-large-vocabularies-can-understand-category-words-not-just-names/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;These dogs can extend words to new objects based on function the way children do in early language learning&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Some viruses like to cheat – and that may be good for our health</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496881-some-viruses-like-to-cheat-and-that-may-be-good-for-our-health/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Mutations can result in viruses that infect cells, but can't copy themselves without help from other viruses - now it seems these cheats may outnumber normal viruses in a third of influenza cases, reducing the severity of infections</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:00:41 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Japanese spacecraft eyes tricky asteroid landing</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/hayabusa-spacecraft-asteroid-size/</link><description>&lt;p&gt; Hyabusa2 is already 105.5 million miles on its journey, but new data indicates trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/hayabusa-spacecraft-asteroid-size/"&gt;Japanese spacecraft eyes tricky asteroid landing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 11:34:28 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How Spinoza Overcame 17th-Century Cancel Culture</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/spinozas-criticism-emotions-cancel/684236/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The great thinker never let his emotions get the better of him. Instead, he used reason to get the better of his detractors.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Stunning amber deposits hold insects from the time of the dinosaurs</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496954-stunning-amber-deposits-hold-insects-from-the-time-of-the-dinosaurs/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A sand quarry in Ecuador has yielded South America’s first amber with bio-inclusions, including a spider's web and a collection of mosquitoes, beetles, flies, wasps and biting midges that lived 112 million years ago</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:00:23 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How to use Google Drive’s new free video editor</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/how-to-use-google-drive-free-video-editor/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You can create a movie masterpiece right in your browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/how-to-use-google-drive-free-video-editor/"&gt;How to use Google Drive’s new free video editor&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>A volcano or a meteorite? New evidence sheds light on puzzling discovery in Greenland’s ice sheet</title><link>https://theconversation.com/a-volcano-or-a-meteorite-new-evidence-sheds-light-on-puzzling-discovery-in-greenlands-ice-sheet-265257</link><description>New research suggests that a mystery platinum signature found in Greenland’s ice may have come from a volcanic eruption in Iceland.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:18:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Government of All the Podcasters</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/maga-podcasters-charlie-kirk/684255/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The right-wing podcast-industrial complex is establishing new norms and taboos—and expanding the White House’s power.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:09:06 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Eavesdropping on grunting groupers reveals how the fish communicate</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/fish-grunting-grouper/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists listened to these Caribbean fish for over 2,000 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/fish-grunting-grouper/"&gt;Eavesdropping on grunting groupers reveals how the fish communicate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:44:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Genetics Can Track How Languages Mixed in the Past</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/genetics-can-track-how-languages-mixed-in-the-past/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New research shows that wherever human populations mix, their languages blend as well&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The DJI Osmo smartphone camera stabilizer is just $58 during this early Amazon Prime Day deal</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/dji-osmo-mobile-phone-camera-stabilizer-early-prime-day-deal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Make your smartphone videos look like professional film work for less than the price of a night out at the movies (with popcorn).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/dji-osmo-mobile-phone-camera-stabilizer-early-prime-day-deal/"&gt;The DJI Osmo smartphone camera stabilizer is just $58 during this early Amazon Prime Day deal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:13:25 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>New AI Tool Predicts Which of 1,000 Diseases Someone May Develop in 20 Years</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/new-ai-tool-predicts-which-of-1-000-diseases-someone-may-develop-in-20-years/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A large language model called Delphi-2M analyzes a person&amp;rsquo;s medical records and lifestyle to provide risk estimates for more than 1,000 diseases&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Starting HRT in early menopause may reduce women's risk of Alzheimer's</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496596-starting-hrt-in-early-menopause-may-reduce-womens-risk-of-alzheimers/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Hormone replacement therapy used within five years of the onset of menopause is associated with a lower risk of Alzheimer’s disease, while starting it later in life is associated with an increased risk</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:36:30 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Aftershock of July’s 8.8 Earthquake Strikes Kamchatka. Tsunami Risk Waning</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/aftershock-of-julys-8-8-earthquake-strikes-kamchatka-tsunami-risk-waning/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A powerful magnitude 7.8 aftershock off Russia&amp;rsquo;s Kamchatka Peninsula that arose from July&amp;rsquo;s magnitude 8.8 earthquake is raising concerns about possible tsunami impacts, although risk appears to be waning&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Early humans reached Europe via an Ice Age land bridge from Turkey</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/land-bridge-turkey/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The never-before-studied region 'holds vital traces of early human activity.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/land-bridge-turkey/"&gt;Early humans reached Europe via an Ice Age land bridge from Turkey&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:01:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Does ASMR really help with anxiety? A psychology expert explains the evidence</title><link>https://theconversation.com/does-asmr-really-help-with-anxiety-a-psychology-expert-explains-the-evidence-252181</link><description>The autonomous sensory meridian response may be linked to certain personality types and traits such as introversion.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:26:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>7 things we can do today to meet Australia’s new climate goal</title><link>https://theconversation.com/7-things-we-can-do-today-to-meet-australias-new-climate-goal-265023</link><description>Australia has the technologies to meet and exceed its new emissions target. The work now is to ensure they’re deployed at scale.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 03:39:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hollywood is suing yet another AI company. But there may be a better way to solve copyright conflicts</title><link>https://theconversation.com/hollywood-is-suing-yet-another-ai-company-but-there-may-be-a-better-way-to-solve-copyright-conflicts-265663</link><description>Different licensing models could help ensure the rights of creators are reconciled with AI companies’ hunger for data.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 03:53:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Etymology Nerd' Adam Aleksic on How Internet Culture Is Transforming the Way We Talk</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/etymology-nerd-adam-aleksic-on-how-internet-culture-is-transforming-the-way/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Linguist Adam Aleksic explains how viral slang and algorithm-driven speech aren&amp;rsquo;t destroying language&amp;ndash;&amp;ndash;they&amp;rsquo;re accelerating its natural evolution.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Quantum computers have finally achieved unconditional supremacy</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496944-quantum-computers-have-finally-achieved-unconditional-supremacy/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>For the first time, researchers have mathematically proven that a quantum computer can solve a particular task faster than an ordinary computer, in a way that can never be beaten</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:00:46 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Weigh a Black Hole</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-to-weigh-a-black-hole/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gauging the mass of a black hole is tricky, but astronomers have devised multiple methods to measure the heft of these galactic gluttons&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Think, Not What to Think</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/teach-students-how-think-not-what-think/684271/?utm_source=feed</link><description>College is not just about transmitting knowledge—it’s also about learning and practicing the skills that connect us to one another.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NASA Records More Than 6,000 Exoplanets and Counting</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/nasa-records-more-than-6-000-exoplanets-and-counting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a crowded galaxy, the latest exoplanet tally shows&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The tech prosperity deal is huge. But will the UK reap the benefits?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-tech-prosperity-deal-is-huge-but-will-the-uk-reap-the-benefits-265621</link><description>US tech firms have promised billions of pounds of investment into the UK.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 12:19:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Naming and categorizing objects is part of how young kids develop executive function skills – new research</title><link>https://theconversation.com/naming-and-categorizing-objects-is-part-of-how-young-kids-develop-executive-function-skills-new-research-255943</link><description>Kids with good executive function tend to grow up to be financially stable, healthy, productive adults. Past attempts to teach these skills have flopped. New brain research on language may change that.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 12:39:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suicide-by-chatbot puts Big Tech in the product liability hot seat</title><link>https://theconversation.com/suicide-by-chatbot-puts-big-tech-in-the-product-liability-hot-seat-265550</link><description>Internet companies have long enjoyed immunity for hosting other people’s content. AI chatbots are changing the legal equation.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 12:39:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>During WWII, the U.S. government censored the weather</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/censor-weather-world-war-2-us/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Even baseball rain delays went unexplained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/censor-weather-world-war-2-us/"&gt;During WWII, the U.S. government censored the weather&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Where you store fat may influence the effect it has on your brain</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496947-where-you-store-fat-may-influence-the-effect-it-has-on-your-brain/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Data from more than 18,000 people suggests that where excess fat is stored in the body influences its effects on brain structure, activity and health</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:55:22 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The 2025 Ig Nobel Prizes honor garlicky babies, drunk bats, and more</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/ig-nobel-prizes-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The annual awards celebrate achievements that make us ‘laugh then think.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/ig-nobel-prizes-2025/"&gt;The 2025 Ig Nobel Prizes honor garlicky babies, drunk bats, and more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:02:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>A Rogue Nation on the High Seas</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/rogue-nation-high-seas/684272/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Trump is treating the military like his personal mercenaries.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:02:24 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Go Ahead, Write in the Margins—It’s Good for Your Brain</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/go-ahead-write-in-the-margins-its-good-for-your-brain/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Annotating the margins of books is an important part&amp;nbsp;of deep reading and has a long legacy of merit in both science and literature&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beware! Your Halloween decorations could be a nightmare for wildlife</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/halloween-decorations-harm-wildlife/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Keep fake spider webs close to your house, and ditch the real pumpkins if you live near wildlife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/halloween-decorations-harm-wildlife/"&gt;Beware! Your Halloween decorations could be a nightmare for wildlife&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Atmospheric hydrogen is rising, which may be a problem for the climate</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497053-atmospheric-hydrogen-is-rising-which-may-be-a-problem-for-the-climate/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Ice core records of atmospheric hydrogen reveal a huge rise in concentration since the Industrial Revolution which has contributed to global warming – and could sway the debate over hydrogen as a fuel</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:31:33 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>First known wild ‘grue jay’ hybrid spotted in Texas</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/blue-jay-green-jay-hybrid/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Green and blue jays are crossing paths as temperatures rise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/blue-jay-green-jay-hybrid/"&gt;First known wild ‘grue jay’ hybrid spotted in Texas&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:50:57 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Have You Considered Not Polluting the Water?</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/ai-friend-startup/684256/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The tech industry will do anything to solve our loneliness epidemic except stop causing it in the first place.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:54:39 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>One blood sample could reveal the age of 11 of your organs and systems</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497154-one-blood-sample-could-reveal-the-age-of-11-of-your-organs-and-systems/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The rate that our heart or liver ages may differ from that of our immune or hormonal systems, and now it seems that a single blood test could break that down</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 17:00:24 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>2025 Ig Nobel Prizes Awarded for Research on Tipsy Bats and Pasta Physics</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/2025-ig-nobel-prizes-awarded-for-research-on-tipsy-bats-and-pasta-physics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Winners of the annual Ig Nobel awards include the science of tipsy bats and the physics of &lt;i&gt;cacio e pepe&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ground beef infused with apple scraps clears taste test</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/meatballs-made-with-apples/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Over 100 volunteers sampled meatballs made with the nutritious fruit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/meatballs-made-with-apples/"&gt;Ground beef infused with apple scraps clears taste test&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:26:13 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Unforgeable quantum money can be stored in an ultracold ‘debit card’</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497081-unforgeable-quantum-money-can-be-stored-in-an-ultracold-debit-card/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Using the quantum states of particles of light as currency could make for unforgeable transactions, and a new experiment has added a way to save some of that quantum money for future use, too</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Einstein’s handwritten encyclopedia entry could fetch $200,000</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/einstein-encyclopedia-draft-auction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The six-page draft attempted to lay out the Theory of Relativity for a general audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/einstein-encyclopedia-draft-auction/"&gt;Einstein&amp;#8217;s handwritten encyclopedia entry could fetch $200,000&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 15:48:32 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The best reusable food containers are on clearance at Amazon during this early Prime Day deal</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/amazon-rubbermaid-brilliance-deal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rubbermaid Brilliance containers are absolutely worth the investment for their sturdy build and they're extremely secure tops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/amazon-rubbermaid-brilliance-deal/"&gt;The best reusable food containers are on clearance at Amazon during this early Prime Day deal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 15:48:58 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Researchers created a soft squeezable computer mouse</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/squeezable-computer-mouse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;'The mouse is long overdue for reinvention.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/squeezable-computer-mouse/"&gt;Researchers created a soft squeezable computer mouse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 17:14:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The science behind what we eat for breakfast</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/the-science-behind-what-we-eat-for-breakfast/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Our ideas of what qualifies as breakfast food are cultural distinctions, not scientific ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/the-science-behind-what-we-eat-for-breakfast/"&gt;The science behind what we eat for breakfast&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 08:01:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>11 adorable photos of red pandas to celebrate International Red Panda Day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/11-adorable-photos-of-red-pandas-to-celebrate-international-red-panda-day/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are less than 10,000 of these furry tree-climbers left in the wild. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/11-adorable-photos-of-red-pandas-to-celebrate-international-red-panda-day/"&gt;11 adorable photos of red pandas to celebrate International Red Panda Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Tiny prairie dogs’ poop play a mighty role in grasslands</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/prairie-dogs-nutrients-grasslands/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;These environmental engineers and grasshoppers turn over more nutrients in the soil than bigger species do&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/prairie-dogs-nutrients-grasslands/"&gt;Tiny prairie dogs&amp;#8217; poop play a mighty role in grasslands&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 12:05:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Riding the Rockies on the Ducati XDiavel V4</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/ducati-xdiavel-v4/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The bike provides impressive ease of use to go with its high performance and visceral engine character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/ducati-xdiavel-v4/"&gt;Riding the Rockies on the Ducati XDiavel V4&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>বদরুদ্দীন উমর: অমরত্বের সন্তান</title><link>https://www.tbsnews.net/bangla/Easel/news-details-389556</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 10:03:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>This Isn’t Dubai; It’s Tuscaloosa</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/sorority-rush/684259/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Whose daddy is paying for all this?</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 07:31:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The pros and cons of not raking leaves</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/pros-and-cons-of-not-raking-leaves/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Your local beetles and chipmunks will thank you for backing away from the rake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/pros-and-cons-of-not-raking-leaves/"&gt;The pros and cons of not raking leaves&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shop these early Prime Day deals on powerful Ego battery-powered chainsaws and yard tools</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/ego-battery-powered-chainsaw-yard-tool-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;These battery-powered saws are even more powerful than their gas-powered competition. Plus, they're quieter and easier to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/ego-battery-powered-chainsaw-yard-tool-deals/"&gt;Shop these early Prime Day deals on powerful Ego battery-powered chainsaws and yard tools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 09:56:09 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>What every button on your iPhone can do (including hidden features)</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/what-iphone-buttons-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Five buttons, so many possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/what-iphone-buttons-do/"&gt;What every button on your iPhone can do (including hidden features)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump Might Be Losing His Race Against Time</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/trump-bondi-edva/684292/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The president is gambling that he can consolidate authority before the public turns too sharply against him.</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 11:49:02 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>14 winning images from the Ocean Photographer of the Year awards</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/ocean-photogapher-of-the-year-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Admire our mighty oceans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/ocean-photogapher-of-the-year-2025/"&gt;14 winning images from the Ocean Photographer of the Year awards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>New research shows Black Summer’s megafires left lasting scars far beyond property damage</title><link>https://theconversation.com/new-research-shows-black-summers-megafires-left-lasting-scars-far-beyond-property-damage-264195</link><description>The study found poorer communities, renters and women carried the heaviest burdens long after the Black Summer fires were put out.</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 19:35:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>With 2035 emissions targets set, what Australia does next will help shape global efforts to keep 1.5°C alive</title><link>https://theconversation.com/with-2035-emissions-targets-set-what-australia-does-next-will-help-shape-global-efforts-to-keep-1-5-c-alive-265665</link><description>Australia’s new emission target comes amid worrying signs of backsliding on climate action. As global leaders gather at the UN, Australia can play a role.</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 19:36:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>আইজ্যাক বাবেলের গল্প | বুড়ো শ্লয়মি</title><link>https://www.tbsnews.net/bangla/Easel/news-details-392316</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 04:59:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vaccine Panel Overhaul, Head Trauma in Sports, and Strange Reproduction in Ants</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/vaccine-panel-overhaul-head-trauma-in-sports-and-strange-reproduction-in/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A revamped CDC advisory committee faces vaccine debates, studies reveal brain changes in athletes, and climate change drives deadly heat waves across Europe.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cutting down the Amazon will bring extreme rain, wind and heat</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497158-cutting-down-the-amazon-will-bring-extreme-rain-wind-and-heat/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>We used to think that deforestation in the Amazon would dry out the local climate, but the effects may be even more extreme and varied</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:28:43 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside the Mysterious Smuggling of the El Ali Meteorite</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/inside-the-mysterious-smuggling-of-the-el-ali-meteorite/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How a space rock vanished from Africa and showed up for sale across an ocean&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why are there so many protests? The US public is highly polarized, and that drives people to act</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-are-there-so-many-protests-the-us-public-is-highly-polarized-and-that-drives-people-to-act-263021</link><description>Anger at the other side, as represented by the political party opposing yours, is a powerful motivator to engage in protests.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 12:15:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How users can make their AI companions feel real – from picking personality traits to creating fan art</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-users-can-make-their-ai-companions-feel-real-from-picking-personality-traits-to-creating-fan-art-265442</link><description>The strong bonds that users are forming with their AI chatbots rest on the human imagination at work.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 12:17:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Most Profound Transgression</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/trump-bondi-doj/684293/?utm_source=feed</link><description>In demanding that the attorney general go after his enemies, Donald Trump is upending fundamental norms of fairness and neutrality in the American legal system.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 08:32:31 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>What exactly is the UV Index? A dermatologist explains.</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/what-is-uv-index/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The measurement has nothing to do with how hot it is outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/what-is-uv-index/"&gt;What exactly is the UV Index? A dermatologist explains.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How US-UK tech deal could yield significant benefits for the British public – expert Q&amp;A</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-us-uk-tech-deal-could-yield-significant-benefits-for-the-british-public-expert-qanda-265707</link><description>The £150bn package could yield real benefits in public health, as well as other areas of technology.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 13:16:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ancient Egypt’s cemetery police blew bone whistles made from cow toes</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/ancient-egypt-police-whistle/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The 3,300-year-old artifact was found in the capital of the ‘Heretic King.’ &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/ancient-egypt-police-whistle/"&gt;Ancient Egypt’s cemetery police blew bone whistles made from cow toes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 09:33:34 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Almost Impossible’ Deep-Earth Diamonds Confirm How These Gems Form</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/almost-impossible-deep-earth-diamonds-confirm-how-these-gems-form/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Seemingly contradictory materials are trapped together in two glittering diamonds from South Africa, shedding light on how diamonds form&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>It’s dragonfly migration season!</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/dragonfly-migration-season/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Keep an eye out for dragonfly swarms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/dragonfly-migration-season/"&gt;It’s dragonfly migration season!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 10:10:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Magnitude 4.3 Earthquake Strikes San Francisco Bay Area</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/magnitude-4-3-earthquake-strikes-san-francisco-bay-area/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The San Francisco Bay Area was rattled early this morning by a magnitude 4.3 earthquake along the Hayward fault line&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Startup uses AI to fight art forgeries—with hyper-realistic copies</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/ai-trained-robot-art-forgeries/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Art knockoffs generate between $4 and $6 billion annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/ai-trained-robot-art-forgeries/"&gt;Startup uses AI to fight art forgeries—with hyper-realistic copies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>First-ever footage of leopard shark sex shows an unexpected trio</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/leopard-shark-mating-video/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“The males lost all their energy and lay immobile on the bottom while the female swam away actively.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/leopard-shark-mating-video/"&gt;First-ever footage of leopard shark sex shows an unexpected trio&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 12:16:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Venus has lava tubes, and they're weird</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497220-venus-has-lava-tubes-and-theyre-weird/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>It has been suggested that lava tubes - underground tunnels carved out by molten rock - might be on Venus, and now we have direct evidence that this is the case</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:36:36 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>AI use by UK justice system risks papering over the cracks caused by years of underfunding</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-use-by-uk-justice-system-risks-papering-over-the-cracks-caused-by-years-of-underfunding-264749</link><description>The justice system is suffering from underfunding and AI won’t solve all the problems.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:16:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Does Tylenol Use during Pregnancy Cause Autism? What the Research Shows</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/does-tylenol-use-during-pregnancy-cause-autism-what-the-research-shows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President Trump and Robert F. Kennedy, Jr., have tied Tylenol use during pregnancy and folate deficiencies to rising autism rates&amp;mdash;but the evidence is thin&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI and credit: How can we keep machines from reproducing social biases?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-and-credit-how-can-we-keep-machines-from-reproducing-social-biases-257756</link><description>Can we move from algorithmic discrimination to inclusive finance?</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out some of the most popular Keurig coffee machines during this early Prime Day deal</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/keurig-coffee-machine-amazon-early-prime-day-deal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you're going to buy a Keurig, this pre-Prime Day sale is a great time to do it. You can even get an ice coffee maker for the lowest price of the year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/keurig-coffee-machine-amazon-early-prime-day-deal/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out some of the most popular Keurig coffee machines during this early Prime Day deal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 16:02:52 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Dangerous climate change threatens Northern Australia’s big ‘food bowl’ dreams</title><link>https://theconversation.com/dangerous-climate-change-threatens-northern-australias-big-food-bowl-dreams-265727</link><description>Big plans are afoot to turn Northern Australia into Asia’s “food bowl”. But the reality of climate change can’t be ignored.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 20:19:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Announcing the #SciAmInTheWild Photography Contest Short List</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/announcing-the-sciaminthewild-photography-contest-short-list/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To celebrate &lt;i&gt;Scientific American&lt;/i&gt;&amp;rsquo;s 180th anniversary, we invited readers to place our magazine covers in the wild. See our staff&amp;rsquo;s favorite submissions&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tylenol Is Popular and Safe, Yet Nobody Knows How It Works</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/tylenol-is-popular-and-safe-yet-nobody-knows-how-it-works/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The common pain reliever is safe when used as directed, research shows. But scientists remain puzzled by one aspect: how it reduces pain and fever&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 22:40:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Close relatives of emperor penguins lived in NZ some 3 million years ago. What caused their extinction?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/close-relatives-of-emperor-penguins-lived-in-nz-some-3-million-years-ago-what-caused-their-extinction-265585</link><description>Great penguins once lived in much warmer waters, but then retreated to the Southern Ocean. In a warming world, they might be able to shift their range again.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 23:27:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fish ‘fingerprints’ in the ocean reveal which species are moving homes due to climate change</title><link>https://theconversation.com/fish-fingerprints-in-the-ocean-reveal-which-species-are-moving-homes-due-to-climate-change-264683</link><description>Tracking these shifts is crucial for understanding how climate change is transforming our oceans.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 23:47:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New Eyes on Space Weather</title><link>https://nautil.us/new-eyes-on-space-weather-1238886/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From threats of solar storms to cosmic radiation, new efforts to warn Earthlings are launching&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/new-eyes-on-space-weather-1238886/"&gt;New Eyes on Space Weather&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>সোভিয়েতরা কীভাবে হেমিংওয়েকে গুপ্তচর বানাল</title><link>https://www.tbsnews.net/bangla/Easel/news-details-392346</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:31:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>James Webb Space Telescope Finds Atmosphere on Lava Planet TOI-561 b</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/james-webb-space-telescope-finds-atmosphere-on-lava-planet-toi-561-b/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hot, small and old&amp;mdash;exoplanet TOI-561 b is just about the worst place to look for alien air. Scientists using JWST found it there anyway&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 11:25:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What happens when AI comes to the cotton fields</title><link>https://theconversation.com/what-happens-when-ai-comes-to-the-cotton-fields-261526</link><description>AI can help farmers be more effective and sustainable, but its use varies from state to state. A project in Georgia aims to bring the technology to the state’s cotton farmers.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 12:49:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air quality analysis reveals minimal changes after xAI data center opens in pollution-burdened Memphis neighborhood</title><link>https://theconversation.com/air-quality-analysis-reveals-minimal-changes-after-xai-data-center-opens-in-pollution-burdened-memphis-neighborhood-265152</link><description>Analysis of the air quality data available for southwest Memphis finds that pollution has long been quite bad, but the turbines powering an xAI data center have not made it much worse.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 12:50:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why your dog gets so excited to see you</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/why-dogs-get-so-excited-to-see-you/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Memory, scent, and strong bonds fuel the joyous reunions between dogs and their pet parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/why-dogs-get-so-excited-to-see-you/"&gt;Why your dog gets so excited to see you&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Final RSV Frontier Is within Reach</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-final-rsv-frontier-is-within-reach/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The journey toward an RSV vaccine for children has been wrought with tragedy and setbacks. But six decades after scientists embarked on that path, they are nearing the finish line&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Promise of RSV Prevention</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-promise-of-rsv-prevention/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;RSV is the leading cause of infant hospitalizations in the U.S. But that could soon change as research advances lead to new preventive drugs for everyone&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New RSV Preventives Dramatically Reduce Infant Illness and Death</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/new-rsv-preventatives-dramatically-reduce-infant-illness-and-death/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The year 2023 marked the debut of groundbreaking innovations to prevent severe RSV infections in infants. Now protected babies are way less likely to develop severe infections or to end up in the ICU&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Global Burden of RSV</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-global-burden-of-rsv/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) continues to affect infants and older and immunocompromised people around the world. These graphics reveal where the burden lies and what the effects of immunizations are&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Indigenous Storytelling Is Transforming RSV Care in Native Communities</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-indigenous-storytelling-is-transforming-rsv-care-in-native-communities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Abigail Echo-Hawk, a preeminent Native American public health expert, discusses RSV, &amp;ldquo;data genocide&amp;rdquo; and positive change driven by Indigenous storytelling&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Fight to End Childhood RSV in Indian Country</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-fight-to-end-childhood-rsv-in-indian-country/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;American Indian and Alaska Native infants experience the highest rates of RSV-related hospitalization in the U.S., but a breakthrough immunization is helping to close the gap&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Long Road to an RSV Antibody to Protect the Most Vulnerable</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/a-long-road-to-an-rsv-antibody-to-protect-the-most-vulnerable/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tragic RSV vaccine trials in the 1960s set the field back for decades. Here&amp;rsquo;s how scientists finally made breakthroughs in RSV immunization&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Home Depot has dozens of portable power stations and solar generators at clearance prices during this fall sale</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/home-depot-portable-power-station-solar-generator-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Save hundreds of dollars on powerful battery backups from Anker, Jackery, Bluetti, and more. Don't let power outages interrupt your streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/home-depot-portable-power-station-solar-generator-deals/"&gt;The Home Depot has dozens of portable power stations and solar generators at clearance prices during this fall sale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:26:32 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>2,000-pound megaraptor died while snacking on a crocodile</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/new-megaraptor-dinosaur-cretaceous/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;'Joaquinraptor casali' was one of the Cretaceous Era's last apex predators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/new-megaraptor-dinosaur-cretaceous/"&gt;2,000-pound megaraptor died while snacking on a crocodile&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hints of exotic dark matter particles could be hiding in LHC data</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497100-hints-of-exotic-dark-matter-particles-could-be-hiding-in-lhc-data/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Particles similar to axions, the leading candidate for dark matter that has long eluded detection, may have already been created in particle colliders – and remained hidden in the data</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:00:17 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Dinosaur found with a crocodile in its jaws named as new species</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497299-dinosaur-found-with-a-crocodile-in-its-jaws-named-as-new-species/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A fossil from about 66 million years ago reveals a species of dinosaur that is new to science, with claws that would have ripped through its prey's flesh</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:00:45 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Leopards may have feasted on our earliest ancestors</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/leopards-ate-early-humans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It took a while for humans to climb the food chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/leopards-ate-early-humans/"&gt;Leopards may have feasted on our earliest ancestors&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 12:11:51 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The US-UK tech prosperity deal carries promise but also peril for the general public</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-us-uk-tech-prosperity-deal-carries-promise-but-also-peril-for-the-general-public-265728</link><description>The deliberate alignment of AI systems with the values of corporations and individuals could sour the investment.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 16:17:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Moon Is Rusting—Thanks to ‘Wind’ Blown from Earth</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-moon-is-rusting-thanks-to-wind-blown-from-earth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lunar minerals can rust when bombarded with high-energy oxygen particles, experiments show&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UV light can fight indoor allergens</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/allergies-uv-light/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A 30-minute treatment can help reduce allergies from pet dander, dust, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/allergies-uv-light/"&gt;UV light can fight indoor allergens&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:38:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>A Censored Rap Legend Has Advice for Jimmy Kimmel</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/jimmy-kimmel-luther-campbell-fcc/684326/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Three decades ago, 2 Live Crew fought a First Amendment battle against the government—and won.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:58:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Mapping the structure of the brain doesn't fully explain its function</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497291-mapping-the-structure-of-the-brain-doesnt-fully-explain-its-function/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Comparing a map of the neurons in a nematode worm - the connectome - with a map of how signals travel across those neurons has revealed a surprising number of differences, suggesting that the structure of the brain alone doesn't explain how it works</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 19:00:37 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What we know, and don't, about the link between painkillers and autism</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497384-what-we-know-and-dont-about-the-link-between-painkillers-and-autism/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Scientific evidence is lacking to support the US government’s decisions to caution against using a common painkiller in pregnancy and fast-track the approval of an experimental medication for autism</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 21:30:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Trump Changed His Mind on Ukraine</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/trump-russia-ukraine-position-change/684344/?utm_source=feed</link><description>And why he still might change it again</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 18:05:53 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Spectacle, weirdness and novelty: what early cinema tells us about the appeal of ‘AI slop’</title><link>https://theconversation.com/spectacle-weirdness-and-novelty-what-early-cinema-tells-us-about-the-appeal-of-ai-slop-265071</link><description>Just as the gimmicky first films evolved into a sophisticated medium, will we look back on today’s AI-generated video as the beginnings of a new art form?</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 01:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>We Can Stop Teen Suicide</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/we-can-stop-teen-suicide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By understanding warning signs and talking to your child, parents can help reduce the risk of teen suicide&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bowers &amp; Wilkins Px8 S2 wireless headphones upgrade an already desirable update</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/bowers-wilkins-px8-s2-flagship-wireless-bluetooth-headphones-announcement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The British brand's new Bluetooth flagship further refines the platform introduced with the award-winning Px7 S3, making the Px8 S2 the choice for maximizing microdetails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/bowers-wilkins-px8-s2-flagship-wireless-bluetooth-headphones-announcement/"&gt;Bowers &amp;amp; Wilkins Px8 S2 wireless headphones upgrade an already desirable update&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 03:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Life a Form of Computation?</title><link>https://nautil.us/is-life-a-form-of-computation-1238864/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Alan Turing and John von Neumann saw it early: the logic of life and the logic of code may be one and the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/is-life-a-form-of-computation-1238864/"&gt;Is Life a Form of Computation?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Extraterrestrials are People, Too</title><link>https://nautil.us/extraterrestrials-are-people-too-1238997/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Should we grant legal rights to extraterrestrial lifeforms before we find them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/extraterrestrials-are-people-too-1238997/"&gt;Extraterrestrials are People, Too&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Gaza Left and the Gender Left</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/uk-your-party-corbyn-sultana/684343/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Can groups with different values work together against Britain’s far right?</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Mary Roach’s New Book Replaceable You Explores Challenges in Replacing Body Parts</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/mary-roachs-new-book-replaceable-you-explores-challenges-in-replacing-body/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mary Roach unpacks the millennia-long effort to replace failing body parts&amp;mdash;and the reasons that modern medicine still struggles to match the original designs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquakes Release Energy Mostly Through Heat, Not Ground Shaking</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/earthquakes-release-energy-mostly-through-heat-not-ground-shaking/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Up to 98 percent of the energy of an earthquake goes into flash heating rocks, not shaking the ground, new research shows. The finding could help yield better earthquake forecasts&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Ganges River is drying faster than ever – here’s what it means for the region and the world</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-ganges-river-is-drying-faster-than-ever-heres-what-it-means-for-the-region-and-the-world-265891</link><description>Climate change and overuse are creating a crisis for south Asia’s most important river.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:10:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>So Much for Class-Based Affirmative Action</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/affirmative-action-race-class-trump/684347/?utm_source=feed</link><description>&lt;span&gt;The Trump administration considers even race-blind admissions policies illegal if they’re intended to achieve diversity. &lt;/span&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 08:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Why archaeologists are studying a skate park</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/archaeologists-skate-park-weirdest-thing-podcast/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Plus dire wolves' bad knees and other weird things we learned this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/archaeologists-skate-park-weirdest-thing-podcast/"&gt;Why archaeologists are studying a skate park &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Researchers develop a pimple patch that actually seems to work</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/researchers-develop-a-pimple-patch-that-actually-seems-to-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After seven days, the treated pimples completely disappeared &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/researchers-develop-a-pimple-patch-that-actually-seems-to-work/"&gt;Researchers develop a pimple patch that actually seems to work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 10:04:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Unconstitutional Tactics Trump Wants to Revive in Memphis</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/memphis-police-tactic/684325/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The president’s plans resemble the aggressive, showy, and ultimately failed crime-fighting strategy once used by the city’s police.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 11:03:17 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How researchers are making precision agriculture more affordable</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-researchers-are-making-precision-agriculture-more-affordable-265366</link><description>Researchers have developed a tool that allows farmers to quickly and affordably test soil samples, get results in real-time, and obtain fertilizer recommendations.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 15:55:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside the factory where MasterCraft builds watersports boats from the outside in</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/mastercraft-boat-construction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Based in Tennessee, the boatbuilder is making waves with its artisan process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/mastercraft-boat-construction/"&gt;Inside the factory where MasterCraft builds watersports boats from the outside in&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>World’s oldest person had a young microbiome and 'exceptional genome'</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497328-worlds-oldest-person-had-a-young-microbiome-and-exceptional-genome/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Scientists have studied the genetics and lifestyle factors that enabled María Branyas Morera, officially the oldest person in the world until she died last year, to reach 117 years old</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:00:05 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How faster-than-light explosions could reveal the universe’s secrets</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495828-how-faster-than-light-explosions-could-reveal-the-universes-secrets/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Some things we see in space appear to outpace light. Now we are learning to harness these bizarre optical illusions to understand the mysteries of neutron stars, gamma ray bursts and more</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:00:24 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Device with 6100 qubits is a step towards largest quantum computer yet</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497439-device-with-6100-qubits-is-a-step-towards-largest-quantum-computer-yet/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>An array of 6100 ultracold caesium atoms controlled by lasers is the largest collection of qubits ever assembled, and researchers hope they can soon turn it into the world's most advanced quantum computer</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:00:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>America’s Zombie Democracy</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/america-authoritarian-regime-ai-suicide/684350/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Its trappings remain, but authoritarianism and AI are hollowing out our humanity.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:33:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Why some memories stick while others fade</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/why-memories-stick/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;'Memory isn’t just a passive recording device.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/why-memories-stick/"&gt;Why some memories stick while others fade&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>We can avoid the agonising wait for advances in women's healthcare</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735623-000-we-can-avoid-the-agonising-wait-for-advances-in-womens-healthcare/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Simply listening to the experiences of women with conditions such as endometriosis will help to end the long-standing inequalities they face when it comes to medical progress</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Two climate scientists on how to use emotion in the climate crisis</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735620-400-two-climate-scientists-on-how-to-use-emotion-in-the-climate-crisis/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>From anger to hope, Kate Marvel and Tim Lenton explain how to tackle the tricky feelings aroused by climate change and harness them to take action</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Are you an introvert or extrovert? Surprisingly, the answer is neither</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735622-700-are-you-an-introvert-or-extrovert-surprisingly-the-answer-is-neither/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>We are quick to place ourselves on the extremes of the social spectrum, but the truth is that personality is more malleable than you think, says Claudia Canavan</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How Taylor Swift is helping botany gain celebrity status</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735622-900-how-taylor-swift-is-helping-botany-gain-celebrity-status/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Feedback is delighted to learn that researchers have discovered what Taylor Swift is accidentally doing to rescue the science of plants from mid-ness. Just take a look at her videos – sorry, botany teaching aids</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What made solar power the most desirable energy source on the planet?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735622-800-what-made-solar-power-the-most-desirable-energy-source-on-the-planet/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>In this latest instalment of Future Chronicles, an imagined history of future inventions, Rowan Hooper explains how the creation of living solar panels transformed their impact on the world</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A compelling book about the end of the Neanderthals is a rare treat</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735620-500-a-compelling-book-about-the-end-of-the-neanderthals-is-a-rare-treat/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Forget the tropes about how violence or maybe volcanic eruptions killed off our ancient cousins, The Last Neanderthal by Ludovic Slimak offers a very different take on how they died out</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazing images expose inner world of mind-blowing plants and fungi</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735620-300-amazing-images-expose-inner-world-of-mind-blowing-plants-and-fungi/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Surreal images from a new book, Microcosms, show how confocal microscopy that uses laser scanning creates a super-sharp new journey around mind-altering plants and fungi</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>We finally found the hot wind coming out of our black hole</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497671-we-finally-found-the-hot-wind-coming-out-of-our-black-hole/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Since the 1970s, astronomers have predicted that Sagittarius A*, the supermassive black hole at the centre of the Milky Way, should be sending out hot wind – they have just caught the first glimpse of it</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 20:01:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Shark bite-resistant wetsuits could save lives</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/shark-bite-resistant-wetsuit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;While not all injuries can be prevented, these new materials offer a new tool for surfers and divers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/shark-bite-resistant-wetsuit/"&gt;Shark bite-resistant wetsuits could save lives&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 15:06:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>What Is Leucovorin, the Unproven Autism Drug Backed by Trump Officials?</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/what-is-leucovorin-the-unproven-autism-drug-backed-by-trump-officials/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration is backing leucovorin as a treatment for autism, despite limited evidence. Some doctors and researchers are concerned&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine’s Plan to Starve the Russian War Machine</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/ukraines-strategy-to-win-the-war/684356/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Negotiations have stalled. Trump keeps changing his policies. Ukrainians, backed by Europeans, are taking matters into their own hands. ​​​</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 15:25:32 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Goodbye petrostates, hello ‘electrostates’: how the clean energy shift is reshaping the world order</title><link>https://theconversation.com/goodbye-petrostates-hello-electrostates-how-the-clean-energy-shift-is-reshaping-the-world-order-264267</link><description>The global shift toward renewable energy is challenging old geopolitical power structures. So where does Australia stand?</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:31:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Huntington’s disease breakthrough: what to know about the gene therapy</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497677-huntingtons-disease-breakthrough-what-to-know-about-the-gene-therapy/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Huntington’s disease has been successfully treated for the first time using a gene therapy, which may be available in the US as soon as next year</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 22:07:17 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Save on last year’s Patagonia jackets, apparel, and accessories during REI’s seasonal clearance sale</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/rei-patagonia-deals-fall-sale-mens-womens/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Grab some classic Patagonia pieces including the iconic Synchilla fleece and its fantastic puffer jackets for up to 45 percent off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/rei-patagonia-deals-fall-sale-mens-womens/"&gt;Save on last year&amp;#8217;s Patagonia jackets, apparel, and accessories during REI&amp;#8217;s seasonal clearance sale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:07:47 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Nightmare Bacteria’ Infections Spiking, Leaving Key Carbapenem Antibiotics Useless, CDC Warns</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/nightmare-bacteria-infections-spiking-leaving-key-carbapenem-antibiotics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The infection rate of one type of carbapenem-resistant Enterobacterales bacteria has risen by more than 460 percent in recent years. Scientists say people receiving treatment in hospitals are at highest risk&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Could we have cracked one of the world's toughest climate problems?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497594-could-we-have-cracked-one-of-the-worlds-toughest-climate-problems/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>It is almost impossible to make cement without emissions, but carbon-capture-and-storage technology is finally being deployed to decarbonise the sector</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 01:01:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Digital brains’ that ‘think’ and ‘feel’: why do we personify AI models, and are these metaphors actually helpful?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/digital-brains-that-think-and-feel-why-do-we-personify-ai-models-and-are-these-metaphors-actually-helpful-265883</link><description>Metaphors help us understand complexity, but they can also be dangerous, or even misleading.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 08:49:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Silent Language of Birds</title><link>https://nautil.us/the-silent-language-of-birds-1239100/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;These songbirds swap chirps for blinks when nature drowns them out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/the-silent-language-of-birds-1239100/"&gt;The Silent Language of Birds&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Nano-sized Art Gallery</title><link>https://nautil.us/a-nano-sized-art-gallery-1239123/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Vote on your favorite miniature art pieces and discover their link to futuristic research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/a-nano-sized-art-gallery-1239123/"&gt; A Nano-sized Art Gallery&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modeling the Deep</title><link>https://nautil.us/modeling-the-deep-1238087/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An ambitious mission seeks to map the flow of crucial chemicals through marine food webs in far-flung oceanic gyres&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/modeling-the-deep-1238087/"&gt;Modeling the Deep&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate change is making trees grow larger in the Amazon rainforest</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497707-climate-change-is-making-trees-grow-larger-in-the-amazon-rainforest/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Rising carbon dioxide levels have boosted the growth of trees in the Amazon rainforest over the past few decades, but it is unclear if this trend will continue</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 11:00:04 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Grattan on Friday: As the government rejects Trump’s stands, Liberal leadership aspirant Andrew Hastie sounds decidedly Trumpian</title><link>https://theconversation.com/grattan-on-friday-as-the-government-rejects-trumps-stands-liberal-leadership-aspirant-andrew-hastie-sounds-decidedly-trumpian-265860</link><description>The prime minister avoided any major pitfalls during his week in the US. Back at home, the Liberal party’s infighting has shown no signs of stopping.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:06:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bird Flu and Human Flu Viruses Could Mix in Cow Udders and Spark a Pandemic</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/bird-flu-and-human-flu-viruses-could-mix-in-cow-udders-and-spark-a-pandemic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Cells in cow udders could act as a site for human flu and bird flu viruses to swap genes and generate dangerous novel strains&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lower Than Cowards</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/freedom-trump-threats-kimmel/684358/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The surrender of America’s elites</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 07:31:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Good Conversations Don’t Require Everybody to Agree, Neuroscience Shows</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/good-conversations-dont-require-everybody-to-agree-neuroscience-shows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Brain imaging is illuminating the patterns linked to productive, positive dialogue&lt;b&gt;,&lt;/b&gt; and those insights could help people connect with others&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cheetahs naturally turned into mummies in caves in Saudi Arabia</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497320-cheetahs-naturally-turned-into-mummies-in-caves-in-saudi-arabia/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The constant temperature and low humidity of a cave network in Saudi Arabia turned cheetahs, some of which died thousands of years ago, into mummies</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:00:12 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Rivers are heating up faster than the air − that’s a problem for aquatic life and people</title><link>https://theconversation.com/rivers-are-heating-up-faster-than-the-air-thats-a-problem-for-aquatic-life-and-people-263718</link><description>River heat waves are rising faster than the pace of air heat waves. That’s a problem for fish, drinking water quality, and food and energy production.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:19:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks retreat from climate change commitments – but it’s business more than politics</title><link>https://theconversation.com/banks-retreat-from-climate-change-commitments-but-its-business-more-than-politics-265176</link><description>The Net-Zero Banking Alliance, intended to curb lending to carbon-intensive sectors, wasn’t effective and more importantly never made much business sense.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:20:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The science of defiance: A psychology researcher explains why people comply – and how to resist</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-science-of-defiance-a-psychology-researcher-explains-why-people-comply-and-how-to-resist-264567</link><description>You don’t need to be a rebel to defy. Defiance isn’t about personality, it’s a practice – one that’s becoming essential in workplaces, politics and everyday life.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:22:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4 films that show how humans can fortify – or botch – their relationship with AI</title><link>https://theconversation.com/4-films-that-show-how-humans-can-fortify-or-botch-their-relationship-with-ai-263603</link><description>From 1980s sci-fi films to today’s blockbusters, filmmakers have wrestled with questions about what happens when humans rely on intelligent machines.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:23:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Does vagus nerve stimulation work? A scientific cure-all explained.</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/what-is-vagus-nerve-stimulation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From treating seizures to depression, stimulating the body's longest nerve has real benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/what-is-vagus-nerve-stimulation/"&gt;Does vagus nerve stimulation work? A scientific cure-all explained.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>AI in Africa: 5 issues that must be tackled for digital equality</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-in-africa-5-issues-that-must-be-tackled-for-digital-equality-265611</link><description>Policy-makers must grapple with an uncomfortable truth: without deliberate action, AI will magnify global divides.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:36:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why September 27, 2025 is the ‘coolest mathematical date of our lifetime’</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/september-27-math-date/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Get ready for a whacky series of numerical coincidences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/september-27-math-date/"&gt;Why September 27, 2025 is the &amp;#8216;coolest mathematical date of our lifetime&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:06:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Nanoparticles may be the secret ingredient in making ultimate plastics</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497683-nanoparticles-may-be-the-secret-ingredient-in-making-ultimate-plastics/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Mixing nanoparticles into some common plastics made them harder to break and possibly easier to process, pointing towards a way to make better materials or packaging</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:41:37 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>3D-printed skin stretches, bleeds like the real thing</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/3d-printed-skin-bleeds/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capsules embedded between layers of this fake tissue simulate human blood and pus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/3d-printed-skin-bleeds/"&gt;3D-printed skin stretches, bleeds like the real thing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:47:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelensky says a destructive drone arms race looms – but dystopia isn’t inevitable</title><link>https://theconversation.com/zelensky-says-a-destructive-drone-arms-race-looms-but-dystopia-isnt-inevitable-263644</link><description>The new age of drones and AI may be terrifying, but there are reasons for thinking the dystopian possibilities of future war will be contained.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:24:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>If I Work Harder, Will You Love Me?</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/workaholic-love-practical-solutions/684353/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The tragedy of workaholism is the false belief that you can trade toil for affection. Knowing that is the first step to recovery.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Cat owners donate more money than dog owners</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/cat-owners-donate-more-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An analysis of nearly $70 billion in donations showed feline lovers contributed slightly more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/cat-owners-donate-more-money/"&gt;Cat owners donate more money than dog owners&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:27:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Punch Cards, Pipeline Problems, and the Future of Women in Computing</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/punch-cards-pipeline-problems-and-the-future-of-women-in-computing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Carla Brodley, founding executive director of the Center for Inclusive Computing at Northeastern University, explains how to make computer science education more accessible to everyone&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alaska’s Fat Bear Week is more than a bit of fun – for the animals, size is a matter of survival</title><link>https://theconversation.com/alaskas-fat-bear-week-is-more-than-a-bit-of-fun-for-the-animals-size-is-a-matter-of-survival-266099</link><description>Bears need to put on fat in order to survive the harsh Alaskan winters.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:31:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vanishing waters in a warming world</title><link>https://theconversation.com/vanishing-waters-in-a-warming-world-266001</link><description>Bad news for the rivers and the lakes that we’re used to.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:31:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Walmart’s gaming PC clearance sale drops prices on laptops, desktops, graphics cards, and more</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/walmart-desktop-laptop-pc-gaming-deals-sale/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Whatever you need to upgrade your PC gaming experience, Walmart has it on sale right now. That includes laptops, desktops, graphics cards, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/walmart-desktop-laptop-pc-gaming-deals-sale/"&gt;Walmart&amp;#8217;s gaming PC clearance sale drops prices on laptops, desktops, graphics cards, and more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:50:42 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Taylor Swift’s Speech Pattern Changed over Time, Linguistics Study Shows</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/taylor-swift-speech-pattern-changed-over-time-linguistics-study-shows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An analysis of Taylor Swift&amp;rsquo;s interviews suggests her speech pattern has changed over her career&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Republicans Can Do If They Really Want to Protect Free Speech</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/republicans-free-speech-fcc/684359/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The best way to defend Americans’ expressive rights is to pass laws.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 14:05:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>12 astonishing images from the 2025 Astrophotography Prize Photographer of the Year</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/2025-astrophotography-prize-photographer-of-the-year-images/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A ‘tornado in space’ and the ISS shine in these inspiring examples of the best in astrophotography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/2025-astrophotography-prize-photographer-of-the-year-images/"&gt;12 astonishing images from the 2025 Astrophotography Prize Photographer of the Year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>WWI-Era Shipwrecks in Mallows Bay Form Ecological Sanctuary</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/wwi-era-shipwrecks-in-mallows-bay-form-ecological-sanctuary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly 100 years ago dozens of ships were abandoned in a shallow bay in the Potomac River. Today plants and animals are thriving on the skeletons of these vessels&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reconstructed skull gives surprising clues to our enigmatic Ancestor X</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497765-reconstructed-skull-gives-surprising-clues-to-our-enigmatic-ancestor-x/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The shared ancestor of our species, the Neanderthals and the Denisovans may be far older than we thought – which could completely change our understanding of humanity's evolution</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 20:00:46 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Apple AirPods Pro 3 earbuds first impressions: The rightful Air to the throne</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/apple-airpods-pro-3-true-wireless-anc-earbuds-first-impressions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Upgraded housings, drivers, eartips, and algorithms mean the Apple AirPods Pro 3 earbuds dig deeper and hold the stage better, improving noise isolation and sonic sensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/apple-airpods-pro-3-true-wireless-anc-earbuds-first-impressions/"&gt;Apple AirPods Pro 3 earbuds first impressions: The rightful Air to the throne&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:15:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>AI systems can easily lie and deceive us – a fact researchers are painfully aware of</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-systems-can-easily-lie-and-deceive-us-a-fact-researchers-are-painfully-aware-of-263531</link><description>In stress-testing AI models, it’s not hard to push them to the brink and make them threaten to harm humans.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:40:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Warn, hide or stand out? How colour in the animal world is a battle for survival</title><link>https://theconversation.com/warn-hide-or-stand-out-how-colour-in-the-animal-world-is-a-battle-for-survival-265670</link><description>A global experiment has helped explain why some animals use stealthy patterns to hide from predators, while others use warning colours to avoid being eaten.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>11 dolphins stranded in Cape Cod rescued by nonprofit</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/stranded-dolphins-rescued/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;‘These strandings happen fast, and every minute counts.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/stranded-dolphins-rescued/"&gt;11 dolphins stranded in Cape Cod rescued by nonprofit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:02:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Comey Indictment Is Not Just Payback</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/comey-indictment/684377/?utm_source=feed</link><description>It’s a glimpse of Trump’s next attempt to seize power.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 21:35:45 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Workers Are Talking About Neurodiversity. Employers Must Keep Up</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/a-hidden-force/202509/workjers-are-talking-about-neurodiversity-employers-must-keep-up</link><description>Rising awareness of neurodiversity is reshaping workplaces and those that don't keep up face real risks.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 23:05:46 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Are Astrology Followers Gullible? Not Necessarily</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/counseling-keys/202509/are-astrology-followers-gullible-not-necessarily</link><description>Why do millions still read their horoscopes? New research suggest astrology fans are less intelligent, but the truth is more complex, and more human.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 23:24:34 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How AI Is Helping Archaeologists Make Discoveries</title><link>https://nautil.us/how-ai-is-helping-archaeologists-make-discoveries-1238095/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New clues about ancient civilizations are being unearthed from the data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/how-ai-is-helping-archaeologists-make-discoveries-1238095/"&gt;How AI Is Helping Archaeologists Make Discoveries&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Neuroscience and Art Collide in a Posthumous ‘Composition’ by Alvin Lucier in Revivification</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/neuroscience-and-art-collide-in-a-posthumous-composition-by-alvin-lucier-in/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A museum exhibit in Australia lets visitors hear music generated by brain cells derived from the blood of a dead composer.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asteroid ‘Families’ Reveal Solar System’s Secret History</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/asteroid-families-reveal-solar-systems-secret-history/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Many asteroids are related, but their family trees can be hard to trace&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Smallmouth Bass Evolve to Evade Electric Culling in Adirondack Lake</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/smallmouth-bass-evolve-to-evade-electric-culling-in-adirondack-lake/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists electrically culled invasive fish in a 20-year battle&amp;mdash;but the fish fought back with rapid evolution&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How fast you age may be controlled by a DNA repair boss in your cells</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497492-how-fast-you-age-may-be-controlled-by-a-dna-repair-boss-in-your-cells/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>When a key protein regulator dials down DNA repair mechanisms, our cells accumulate more mutations, which may cause us to age faster</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 12:00:17 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Atmospheric chaos has sent temperatures soaring in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497898-atmospheric-chaos-has-sent-temperatures-soaring-in-antarctica/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Stratospheric temperatures in Antarctica are spiking, which could see strange weather unfold across the southern hemisphere in the coming months</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 13:00:56 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Making It Alone: 5 Ways Solitude Can Spark Creativity</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-joy-of-solitude/202509/making-it-alone-5-ways-solitude-can-spark-creativity</link><description>How does solitude bolster imagination, unlock ingenuity, and foster inspiration?</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 08:22:27 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk and the making of an AI-generated martyr</title><link>https://theconversation.com/charlie-kirk-and-the-making-of-an-ai-generated-martyr-265834</link><description>In a polarized environment, the elevation of a figure into a saint does more than honor the individual. It turns a political struggle into a sacred one.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 12:31:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Synchronicities Can Teach Us</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/lgbtq-affirmative-psychology/202509/what-synchronicities-can-teach-us</link><description>Discover how noticing meaningful coincidences, or synchronicities, can guide your path and reveal insight in everyday life.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 08:49:13 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Want knives? How to buy what people leave at airport security.</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/what-happens-to-tsa-confiscated-items/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to very weird corner of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/what-happens-to-tsa-confiscated-items/"&gt;Want knives? How to buy what people leave at airport security.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Babies' brains 'tick' more slowly than ours, which may help them learn</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497755-babies-brains-tick-more-slowly-than-ours-which-may-help-them-learn/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The rhythm of an infant's brain activity seems to put them in constant learning mode, whereas that of an adult may allow them to retrieve conceptual knowledge</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What the Gorilla Saw</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-secret-mind/202509/what-the-gorilla-saw</link><description>How much do we miss in a day? Apparently, a lot. Selective attention refers to how we filter information. Nighttime dreams can help us to look for what we might be missing.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 09:03:21 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>3 Ways to Become More Emotionally Aware</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/social-instincts/202509/3-ways-to-become-more-emotionally-aware</link><description>How to start catching your emotions early, before you’re overwhelmed.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 09:21:17 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Stop Outsourcing Your Brain</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/code-conscience/202509/stop-outsourcing-your-brain</link><description>AI doesn’t create expertise; it amplifies it. Mastery is earned through practice, persistence, and embracing the struggle.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 09:31:56 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Dyspraxia Is Often Misunderstood</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/surrey-minds/202509/why-dyspraxia-is-often-misunderstood</link><description>Dyspraxia affects one in 20 children but it is often overlooked and misunderstood. It affects movement and so much more.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 09:56:27 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Amateur paleontologist opens fossil museum in rural Minnesota</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/amateur-paleontologist-opens-fossil-museum-in-rural-minnesota/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jim Pollard is bringing bison bones, fossilized mammoth poop, and more to Blue Earth's 3,000 residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/amateur-paleontologist-opens-fossil-museum-in-rural-minnesota/"&gt;Amateur paleontologist opens fossil museum in rural Minnesota&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Did a star blow up and hit Earth 10 million years ago?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497946-did-a-star-blow-up-and-hit-earth-10-million-years-ago/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>There are signs deep beneath the Pacific Ocean that an exploding star once sent cosmic rays blasting out towards Earth, and now we have an idea of which stars may be to blame</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:09:42 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The Secret Superpower of Vulnerability</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/last-stop-on-the-struggle-bus/202509/the-secret-superpower-of-vulnerability</link><description>While being vulnerable and opening ourselves up to others can be a scary prospect, it also can bring profound meaning to our lives and deepen our relationships.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:39:46 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>A Powerful, Non-Toxic Masculinity</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/nurturing-resilience/202509/a-powerful-non-toxic-masculinity</link><description>Men’s relationships can offer opportunities to be attentive and protective, without the toxic overtones of power and control.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:55:18 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Quiz: Can You Match These Official Symbols to Their States? It Might Be Harder Than You Think</title><link>https://www.mentalfloss.com/quizzes/match-state-symbols-quiz?utm_source=RSS</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class="ff-og-image-inserted" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_26,y_88,w_622,h_349/c_fill,w_1440,ar_1440:810,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/voltaxMediaLibrary/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k5h6gf7zxs18zxvs04.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9n q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Some state symbols are pretty obvious. There’s California’s state &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/section/animals"&gt;animal&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/531450/facts-about-grizzly-bears"&gt;grizzly bear&lt;/a&gt;, right on its &lt;a href="https://www.parks.ca.gov/?page_id=24644" target="_blank"&gt;flag&lt;/a&gt;. It should come as no surprise that the official domestic animal of Wisconsin, the &lt;a href="https://wi101.wisc.edu/becoming-the-dairy-state-2/" target="_blank"&gt;Dairy State&lt;/a&gt;, is the dairy &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/550594/facts-about-cows"&gt;cow&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9o q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="mt-[18px] md:mt-0 mb-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-0"&gt;Some state symbols are pretty obvious. There’s California’s state &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/section/animals"&gt;animal&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/531450/facts-about-grizzly-bears"&gt;grizzly bear&lt;/a&gt;, right on its &lt;a href="https://www.parks.ca.gov/?page_id=24644" target="_blank"&gt;flag&lt;/a&gt;. It should come as no surprise that the official domestic animal of Wisconsin, the &lt;a href="https://wi101.wisc.edu/becoming-the-dairy-state-2/" target="_blank"&gt;Dairy State&lt;/a&gt;, is the dairy &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/550594/facts-about-cows"&gt;cow&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9q q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Other symbols are just very common: Seven states chose the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/72702/10-crimson-facts-about-cardinals"&gt;northern cardinal&lt;/a&gt;, six picked the &lt;a href="https://www.allaboutbirds.org/guide/Western_Meadowlark/overview" target="_blank"&gt;western meadowlark&lt;/a&gt;, and five chose the &lt;a href="https://abcbirds.org/bird/northern-mockingbird/" target="_blank"&gt;northern mockingbird&lt;/a&gt; as their state birds:&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9r q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-1"&gt;Other symbols are just very common: Seven states chose the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/72702/10-crimson-facts-about-cardinals"&gt;northern cardinal&lt;/a&gt;, six picked the &lt;a href="https://www.allaboutbirds.org/guide/Western_Meadowlark/overview" target="_blank"&gt;western meadowlark&lt;/a&gt;, and five chose the &lt;a href="https://abcbirds.org/bird/northern-mockingbird/" target="_blank"&gt;northern mockingbird&lt;/a&gt; as their state birds:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9t q:key=vcaa:2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9u q:key=ndZW:mL_1--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-auto max-w-[90vw]"&gt;&lt;table class="border-collapse text-left w-full"&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="bg-lightGrey py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State Bird ...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th class="bg-lightGrey py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;... of These States&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Northern Cardinal&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Illinois, Indiana, Kentucky, North Carolina, Ohio, Virginia, and West Virginia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Western Meadowlark&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kansas, Montana, Nebraska, North Dakota, Oregon, and Wyoming&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Northern Mockingbird&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arkansas, Florida, Mississippi, Tennessee, and Texas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9v q:key=vcaa:--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9w q:key=StMp:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=Lf_2--&gt;&lt;ol class="toc text-primary mt-4 flex flex-col gap-y-2.5 ps-10 list-decimal [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/quizzes/match-state-symbols-quiz?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-4"&gt;The Origin of State Symbols&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/quizzes/match-state-symbols-quiz?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-13"&gt;Quiz: Can You Correctly Match These States and Symbols?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9y q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;The Origin of State Symbols&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9z q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-4"&gt;The Origin of State Symbols&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a1 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;The habit of designating state symbols can be traced back to the 1893 Chicago World’s Fair (which also introduced Americans to the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/78188/7-things-introduced-worlds-fairs"&gt;Ferris wheel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.pbs.org/wgbh/americanexperience/features/chicago-worlds-columbian-exposition-1893/" target="_blank"&gt;hamburgers&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.nps.gov/articles/000/inventions-from-the-world-s-columbian-exposition.htm" target="_blank"&gt;zippers&lt;/a&gt;). The Congress-appointed Board of Lady Managers was in charge of designing and building the Women’s Hall to showcase women’s industries from across the country. Among its many duties, the board &lt;a href="https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-weekend-essay/the-unstoppable-rise-of-the-state-symbol" target="_blank"&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt; that each state and territory select an official flower that could be displayed as a garland.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a2 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-5"&gt;The habit of designating state symbols can be traced back to the 1893 Chicago World’s Fair (which also introduced Americans to the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/78188/7-things-introduced-worlds-fairs"&gt;Ferris wheel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.pbs.org/wgbh/americanexperience/features/chicago-worlds-columbian-exposition-1893/" target="_blank"&gt;hamburgers&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.nps.gov/articles/000/inventions-from-the-world-s-columbian-exposition.htm" target="_blank"&gt;zippers&lt;/a&gt;). The Congress-appointed Board of Lady Managers was in charge of designing and building the Women’s Hall to showcase women’s industries from across the country. Among its many duties, the board &lt;a href="https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-weekend-essay/the-unstoppable-rise-of-the-state-symbol" target="_blank"&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt; that each state and territory select an official flower that could be displayed as a garland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a4 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Women’s groups in the states made the selections, and over the next few decades, state legislatures made many of these choices official emblems. And didn’t stop with flowers. All 50 states and the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/geography/cities/district-of-columbia-origin"&gt;District of Columbia&lt;/a&gt; have now designated a state bird and tree in addition to flowers; a majority has named state mammals, fish, insects, and reptiles, and many recognize their official state fossils, minerals, beverages, fruits, vegetables, songs, dances, sports, and more.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a5 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-6"&gt;Women’s groups in the states made the selections, and over the next few decades, state legislatures made many of these choices official emblems. And didn’t stop with flowers. All 50 states and the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/geography/cities/district-of-columbia-origin"&gt;District of Columbia&lt;/a&gt; have now designated a state bird and tree in addition to flowers; a majority has named state mammals, fish, insects, and reptiles, and many recognize their official state fossils, minerals, beverages, fruits, vegetables, songs, dances, sports, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a7 q:key=vcaa:7--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a8 q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a9 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You May Also Like:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aa q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You May Also Like:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ac q:key=vcaa:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/72542/how-all-50-state-capitals-got-their-names"&gt;How All 50 State Capitals Got Their Names&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/22848/quick-9-nine-capitals-united-states"&gt;9 Places That Have Served as the Capital of the United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/647376/juneteenth-flag"&gt;What Does the Juneteenth Flag Symbolize?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ad q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=af q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ag q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-10"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ai q:key=vcaa:11--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aj q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ak q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;See how familiar you are with the symbols of various U.S. states and the District of Columbia below. (Yes, we know D.C. isn’t a state, but we’ve called its symbol a “state symbol” to maintain quiz integrity.) Remember, it’s possible that a particular symbol may apply to more than one state—for example, at least 20 states have designated milk as their official drink—but in our quiz, only one of the three multiple choice answers will be correct.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=al q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-12"&gt;See how familiar you are with the symbols of various U.S. states and the District of Columbia below. (Yes, we know D.C. isn’t a state, but we’ve called its symbol a “state symbol” to maintain quiz integrity.) Remember, it’s possible that a particular symbol may apply to more than one state—for example, at least 20 states have designated milk as their official drink—but in our quiz, only one of the three multiple choice answers will be correct.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=an q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;Quiz: Can You Correctly Match These States and Symbols?&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ao q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-13"&gt;Quiz: Can You Correctly Match These States and Symbols?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aq q:key=vcaa:https://www.riddle.com/embed/a/AcolovUi?--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ar q:key=SRoa:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=as q:key=EEns:oZ_1--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=au q:key=vcaa:&lt;h3&gt;Take Our Latest &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/quizzes"&gt;Quizzes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/h3&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=av q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h3 class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-15"&gt;Take Our Latest &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/quizzes"&gt;Quizzes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ax q:key=vcaa:https://content-enrichment-service.mmsport.minutesvc.com/oembed?url=https://content-enrichment-service.mmsport.minutesvc.com/properties/mentalfloss/embeds/01j6yxa15b2gmq4--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ay q:key=jBas:mL_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org"&gt;Adblock test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org/acceptable.html"&gt;(Why?)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:04:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out Coway air purifiers for every room during this early Prime Day deal</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/coway-air-purifier-early-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon has Coway air purifiers for every home and budget on sale for their lowest prices of the year before the Prime Big Deal Days even get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/coway-air-purifier-early-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out Coway air purifiers for every room during this early Prime Day deal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:06:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Butterfly Wings Inspire Barrier-Breaking Nanotech</title><link>https://nautil.us/butterfly-wings-inspire-barrier-breaking-nanotech-1239257/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mimicking the charismatic insect’s trick for flashing iridescent blue allows devices to grow ever smaller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/butterfly-wings-inspire-barrier-breaking-nanotech-1239257/"&gt;Butterfly Wings Inspire Barrier-Breaking Nanotech&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:17:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Comey Indictment Is an Embarrassment</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/comey-indictment-trump-doj/684381/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The Justice Department should never have brought such a shoddy case.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:26:17 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Attack squirrel’ sends two people to the ER</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/attack-squirrel-california/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A friendly reminder to not feed wildlife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/attack-squirrel-california/"&gt;&amp;#8216;Attack squirrel&amp;#8217; sends two people to the ER&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:32:57 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Earth’s Largest Mirror Shattered by Science</title><link>https://nautil.us/earths-largest-mirror-shattered-by-science-1239349/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Bolivian salt flat long touted as a massive looking glass loses some of its shine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/earths-largest-mirror-shattered-by-science-1239349/"&gt;Earth’s Largest Mirror Shattered by Science&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:39:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Can We Learn From Suicide Hotlines?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/philosophy-and-therapy/202509/what-can-we-learn-from-suicide-hotlines</link><description>Are suicide hotlines effective in preventing suicide? It is complicated. Hotlines address some causes of suicide, but not others, and are but one part of suicide prevention.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:41:40 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Surprising Lessons From Late-in-Life Divorce</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/counseling-keys/202509/surprising-lessons-from-late-in-life-divorce</link><description>Gray divorce is shaking up what we think we know about love and aging. Here’s what it really means for families, freedom, and new beginnings.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:47:20 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Top 50 Pet Names of 2025, From Bella to Ziggy</title><link>https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/pets/most-popular-pet-names-2025?utm_source=RSS</link><description>&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9n q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Choosing the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/dogs/most-popular-dog-names-2025"&gt;perfect name for a pet&lt;/a&gt; may be a cinch for some owners, but it can feel daunting to others. If you’re expecting a new furry friend soon and can’t find a fitting name, you may get some inspiration from the ones listed below. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9o q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="mt-[18px] md:mt-0 mb-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-0"&gt;Choosing the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/dogs/most-popular-dog-names-2025"&gt;perfect name for a pet&lt;/a&gt; may be a cinch for some owners, but it can feel daunting to others. If you’re expecting a new furry friend soon and can’t find a fitting name, you may get some inspiration from the ones listed below.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9q q:key=vcaa:--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9r q:key=StMp:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=Lf_2--&gt;&lt;ol class="toc text-primary mt-4 flex flex-col gap-y-2.5 ps-10 list-decimal [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/pets/most-popular-pet-names-2025?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-3"&gt;These Pet Names Are Popular Across the Country&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9t q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;To compile the list, &lt;a href="https://www.trustedhousesitters.com/blog/pets/popular-pet-names-study-2025/" target="_blank"&gt;TrustedHousesitters&lt;/a&gt;, a pet sitter website, examined the names of nearly 100,000 dogs and cats registered on the website in July of 2025. Here’s what the researchers found.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9u q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-2"&gt;To compile the list, &lt;a href="https://www.trustedhousesitters.com/blog/pets/popular-pet-names-study-2025/" target="_blank"&gt;TrustedHousesitters&lt;/a&gt;, a pet sitter website, examined the names of nearly 100,000 dogs and cats registered on the website in July of 2025. Here’s what the researchers found.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9w q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;These Pet Names Are Popular Across the Country&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9x q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-3"&gt;These Pet Names Are Popular Across the Country&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9z q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_2121,h_1193,x_0,y_45/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k5hhjjdqxxp4pywnxm--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a0 q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a1 q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=a1 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a2 q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=a2 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a3 q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a4 q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a5 q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=a5 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=a4 q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="The woman puts on a collar with a tag that says “I want to go home.”" class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="1193" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_45,w_2121,h_1193/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k5hhjjdqxxp4pywnxm.jpg" title="The woman puts on a collar with a tag that says “I want to go home.”" width="2121" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A pretty collar for a pretty girl. | Maria Korneeva/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a9 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;This year’s picks show that classic names, like &lt;em&gt;Max&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Milo&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Daisy&lt;/em&gt;, continue to be dominant. Yet again, &lt;em&gt;Luna &lt;/em&gt;is quite a popular choice for both cats and dogs. The moniker topped &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/most-popular-pet-names-2024"&gt;last year’s&lt;/a&gt; list from the pet insurance company &lt;a href="https://spotpet.com/blog/lifestyle/most-popular-pet-names-us" target="_blank"&gt;Spot&lt;/a&gt; and has kept its place since. In &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/posts/americas-most-popular-dog-names"&gt;2023&lt;/a&gt;, the celestial name came in second place to &lt;em&gt;Bella &lt;/em&gt;on &lt;em&gt;U.S. News &amp;amp; World Report&lt;/em&gt;’s list of the most popular dog names&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;Now, canine owners generally prefer the name above all others.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aa q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-5"&gt;This year’s picks show that classic names, like &lt;em&gt;Max&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Milo&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Daisy&lt;/em&gt;, continue to be dominant. Yet again, &lt;em&gt;Luna &lt;/em&gt;is quite a popular choice for both cats and dogs. The moniker topped &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/most-popular-pet-names-2024"&gt;last year’s&lt;/a&gt; list from the pet insurance company &lt;a href="https://spotpet.com/blog/lifestyle/most-popular-pet-names-us" target="_blank"&gt;Spot&lt;/a&gt; and has kept its place since. In &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/posts/americas-most-popular-dog-names"&gt;2023&lt;/a&gt;, the celestial name came in second place to &lt;em&gt;Bella &lt;/em&gt;on &lt;em&gt;U.S. News &amp;amp; World Report&lt;/em&gt;’s list of the most popular dog names&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;Now, canine owners generally prefer the name above all others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ac q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lucy&lt;/em&gt;’s ranking&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;made the most significant jump from the previous year—the name moved from eighth place to second. Meanwhile, &lt;em&gt;Bella &lt;/em&gt;dropped down one rank this year, rounding out the top three names for pets in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ad q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lucy&lt;/em&gt;’s ranking&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;made the most significant jump from the previous year—the name moved from eighth place to second. Meanwhile, &lt;em&gt;Bella &lt;/em&gt;dropped down one rank this year, rounding out the top three names for pets in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=af q:key=vcaa:7--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ag q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ah q:key=vcaa:&lt;h3&gt;You May Also Like:&lt;/h3&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ai q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h3 class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-8"&gt;You May Also Like:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ak q:key=vcaa:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/dogs/tips-for-hiking-with-dogs"&gt;Want to Safely Hike With Your Dog? Consider These 6 Tips From an Expert Dog Trainer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/564264/dogs-puppies-facts?utm_source=gol"&gt;42 Amazing Facts About Dogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/524452/what-makes-cats-tail-puff-when-its-scared"&gt;Why Is My Cat’s Tail All Puffed Up?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=al q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=an q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ao q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-10"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aq q:key=vcaa:11--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ar q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=as q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;TrustedHousesitters’ complete list of the most common female and male pet names for dogs and cats is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=at q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-12"&gt;TrustedHousesitters’ complete list of the most common female and male pet names for dogs and cats is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=av q:key=vcaa:&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Luna&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lucy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bella&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Charlie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Daisy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Max&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rosie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lola&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lily&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Leo&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Stella&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cooper&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bailey&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Oliver&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Milo&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Buddy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sadie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Penny&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Coco&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sophie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Olive&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ruby&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ollie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Molly&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pepper&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Willow&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gracie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Scout&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Maggie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Jack&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Finn&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chloe&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Frankie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Poppy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gus&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nala&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Teddy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ziggy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Loki&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Piper&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lulu&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bear&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ellie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rocky&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Louie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Jasper&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Winston&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tucker&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cleo&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aw q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;ol class="!list-decimal ml-5 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-13"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Luna&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lucy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bella&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Charlie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Daisy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Max&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rosie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lola&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lily&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Leo&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Stella&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cooper&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bailey&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Oliver&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Milo&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Buddy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sadie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Penny&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Coco&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sophie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Olive&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ruby&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ollie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Molly&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pepper&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Willow&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gracie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Scout&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Maggie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Jack&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Finn&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chloe&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Frankie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Poppy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gus&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nala&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Teddy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ziggy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Loki&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Piper&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lulu&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bear&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ellie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rocky&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Louie&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Jasper&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Winston&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tucker&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cleo&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ay q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Now that you know the most popular pet names in the U.S., check out the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/posts/most-popular-dog-breeds-worldwide"&gt;50 most beloved breeds across the world&lt;/a&gt;, from feisty Chihuahuas to gigantic Great Danes.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=az q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-14"&gt;Now that you know the most popular pet names in the U.S., check out the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/posts/most-popular-dog-breeds-worldwide"&gt;50 most beloved breeds across the world&lt;/a&gt;, from feisty Chihuahuas to gigantic Great Danes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org"&gt;Adblock test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org/acceptable.html"&gt;(Why?)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How water fuels conflict in Pakistan</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-water-fuels-conflict-in-pakistan-262628</link><description>The potential of water to cause conflict is a live issue in Pakistan, with climate change only making matters worse.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:08:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Labeling Partners “Avoidant” or “Narcissistic” Backfires</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/connection-and-coping/202509/why-labeling-partners-avoidant-or-narcissistic-backfires</link><description>Think your partner is “avoidant” or “narcissistic”? Learn why these labels can backfire—and what actually builds intimacy instead.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 12:27:59 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Healing Through Music</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-elusive-brain/202509/healing-through-music</link><description>"Music has the potential to be a potent carrier for inner and outer revolution."</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 12:50:05 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Novels with a certain structure are more likely to be classics</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497589-novels-with-a-certain-structure-are-more-likely-to-be-classics/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Novels need a gripping story to stay popular as the decades pass, but it seems that other less-obvious factors may also contribute to their lasting success</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 18:00:52 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The Quiet Crisis: Untreated Mental Illness and Violence</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/esprit/202509/the-quiet-crisis-untreated-mental-illness-and-violence</link><description>When parents miss the warning signs of serious mental illness, the consequences can be tragic. Here's what must change—and how lives can be saved.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 13:31:35 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Redesigned umbrella is smaller than an iPhone</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/small-umbrella-simprella/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The 'Simprella' weighs less than a few Snickers’ bars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/small-umbrella-simprella/"&gt;Redesigned umbrella is smaller than an iPhone&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 13:41:48 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>What Does a Good ADHD Evaluation Look Like?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/from-trial-to-triumph/202509/what-does-a-good-adhd-evaluation-look-like</link><description>To avoid mis-diagnosis, make sure an evaluation includes these steps.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 13:42:06 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>This ‘funny-looking rock’ holds 3,000 years of Iron Age secrets</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/iron-age-copper-breakthrough/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Experimenting with copper may have led to our eventual breakthroughs with making iron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/iron-age-copper-breakthrough/"&gt;This ‘funny-looking rock’ holds 3,000 years of Iron Age secrets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Lung inflammation may make traumatic events harder to forget</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497888-lung-inflammation-may-make-traumatic-events-harder-to-forget/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Severe lung inflammation has been linked to symptoms resembling post-traumatic stress disorder in mice, which could help us better treat and prevent the mental health condition</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 19:00:07 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>You’re Probably Not Washing Your Car Often Enough—Here’s Why</title><link>https://www.mentalfloss.com/transportation/cars-trucks/how-often-should-you-wash-your-car?utm_source=RSS</link><description>&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9n q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;In terms of technology, &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/transportation/cars-trucks"&gt;cars&lt;/a&gt; are “smarter” than they’ve ever been, with driving assistance features that can make drivers feel more like co-pilots. But regardless of these advancements, cars are still highly dependent on regular maintenance. Oil and filter changes, tire replacement, and more help keep them running longer.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9o q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="mt-[18px] md:mt-0 mb-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-0"&gt;In terms of technology, &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/transportation/cars-trucks"&gt;cars&lt;/a&gt; are “smarter” than they’ve ever been, with driving assistance features that can make drivers feel more like co-pilots. But regardless of these advancements, cars are still highly dependent on regular maintenance. Oil and filter changes, tire replacement, and more help keep them running longer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9q q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;You might think washing your car falls more under the cosmetic category; some might even go months without a wash, or postpone it until it’s visibly dirty. For a variety of reasons, though, depriving your vehicle of regular cleaning is actually a bad idea—not only for its finish, but for its resale value. Here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9r q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-1"&gt;You might think washing your car falls more under the cosmetic category; some might even go months without a wash, or postpone it until it’s visibly dirty. For a variety of reasons, though, depriving your vehicle of regular cleaning is actually a bad idea—not only for its finish, but for its resale value. Here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9t q:key=vcaa:--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9u q:key=StMp:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=Lf_2--&gt;&lt;ol class="toc text-primary mt-4 flex flex-col gap-y-2.5 ps-10 list-decimal [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/transportation/cars-trucks/how-often-should-you-wash-your-car?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-3"&gt;Why You Should Wash Your Car Regularly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/transportation/cars-trucks/how-often-should-you-wash-your-car?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-13"&gt;The Role of Road Salt in Washing Your Car&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/transportation/cars-trucks/how-often-should-you-wash-your-car?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-18"&gt;Washing Your Car Less Often&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/transportation/cars-trucks/how-often-should-you-wash-your-car?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-22"&gt;Handwashing vs. Car Washes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9w q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;Why You Should Wash Your Car Regularly&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9x q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-3"&gt;Why You Should Wash Your Car Regularly&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9z q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.acg.aaa.com/connect/blogs/4c/auto/how-often-should-you-wash-your-car" target="_blank"&gt;According to&lt;/a&gt; roadside assistance company AAA, car owners should typically aim to wash their vehicle every two weeks. The reason? Cars are constantly exposed to environmental factors like bird droppings, tree sap, insects, and other contaminants. While these things aren’t going to affect your vehicle’s operation, they can do a number on the paint job. Bird deposits, for example, are extremely acidic, and leaving them on your car’s roof can deteriorate the finish.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a0 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-4"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.acg.aaa.com/connect/blogs/4c/auto/how-often-should-you-wash-your-car" target="_blank"&gt;According to&lt;/a&gt; roadside assistance company AAA, car owners should typically aim to wash their vehicle every two weeks. The reason? Cars are constantly exposed to environmental factors like bird droppings, tree sap, insects, and other contaminants. While these things aren’t going to affect your vehicle’s operation, they can do a number on the paint job. Bird deposits, for example, are extremely acidic, and leaving them on your car’s roof can deteriorate the finish.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a2 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;It’s not strictly nature that’s a problem. When you drive, your car can &lt;a href="https://lifelanes.progressive.com/how-often-to-wash-your-car/" target="_blank"&gt;pick up &lt;/a&gt;road debris from construction and tar from roads, which can damage paint and potentially the undercarriage.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a3 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-5"&gt;It’s not strictly nature that’s a problem. When you drive, your car can &lt;a href="https://lifelanes.progressive.com/how-often-to-wash-your-car/" target="_blank"&gt;pick up &lt;/a&gt;road debris from construction and tar from roads, which can damage paint and potentially the undercarriage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a5 q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_2232,h_1255,x_0,y_0/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k60jksa7e8t1cfyq3g--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a6 q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a7 q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=a7 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a8 q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=a8 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a9 q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aa q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ab q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=ab q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=aa q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="Cleaning supplies in a car" class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="1255" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_2232,h_1255/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k60jksa7e8t1cfyq3g.jpg" title="Cleaning supplies in a car" width="2232" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Don’t forget to clean the inside of your car. | Peter Dazeley/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=af q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Your car’s interior probably doesn’t need to be cleaned as frequently, but you should still keep a regular schedule of vacuuming up crumbs or dirt to keep the upholstery maintained. (Leather seats may also benefit from regular conditioning to keep the surface from cracking; check your auto manual for specific guidance.)&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ag q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-7"&gt;Your car’s interior probably doesn’t need to be cleaned as frequently, but you should still keep a regular schedule of vacuuming up crumbs or dirt to keep the upholstery maintained. (Leather seats may also benefit from regular conditioning to keep the surface from cracking; check your auto manual for specific guidance.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ai q:key=vcaa:8--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aj q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ak q:key=vcaa:&lt;h3&gt;You May Also Like:&lt;/h3&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=al q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h3 class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-9"&gt;You May Also Like:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=an q:key=vcaa:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/63747/meanings-behind-these-15-symbols-your-cars-dashboard"&gt;What Do These 18 Common Car Dashboard Symbols Actually Mean?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/geography/maps/most-searched-car-types-map"&gt;Mapped: What Americans Want in a Car, According to Search Trends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/how-cars-get-their-names"&gt;How Do Cars Get Their Names?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ao q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aq q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ar q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-11"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=at q:key=vcaa:12--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=au q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=av q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;The Role of Road Salt in Washing Your Car&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aw q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-13"&gt;The Role of Road Salt in Washing Your Car&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ay q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;People living in colder climates have an additional road hazard to worry about: road salt. While salt can keep roads from becoming too slippery in the winter, it’s &lt;a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/cars/how-often-should-you-wash-road-salt-off-your-car-a7227523841/" target="_blank"&gt;often corrosive&lt;/a&gt; to a car’s body and undercarriage. Rusty braking or steering mechanisms can then become a costly or dangerous problem. (The same concern holds true for living near the ocean, where saltwater and sand can also have damaging effects.)&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=az q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-14"&gt;People living in colder climates have an additional road hazard to worry about: road salt. While salt can keep roads from becoming too slippery in the winter, it’s &lt;a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/cars/how-often-should-you-wash-road-salt-off-your-car-a7227523841/" target="_blank"&gt;often corrosive&lt;/a&gt; to a car’s body and undercarriage. Rusty braking or steering mechanisms can then become a costly or dangerous problem. (The same concern holds true for living near the ocean, where saltwater and sand can also have damaging effects.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b1 q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_2123,h_1194,x_0,y_0/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k60jnvk78s4f15xm0n--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b2 q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b3 q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=b3 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b4 q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=b4 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b5 q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b6 q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b7 q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=b7 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=b6 q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="Crystal rock salt for road de-icing" class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="1194" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_2123,h_1194/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k60jnvk78s4f15xm0n.jpg" title="Crystal rock salt for road de-icing" width="2123" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Salt on the road can cause big problems for your car. | Douglas Sacha/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bb q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Salt can also coat headlights, which can reduce your car’s visibility. It can also interfere with sensors, which might impact driving assistance functions like emergency braking. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bc q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-16"&gt;Salt can also coat headlights, which can reduce your car’s visibility. It can also interfere with sensors, which might impact driving assistance functions like emergency braking. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=be q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;You don’t necessarily have to wash your car more often in the winter if you’re keeping up with the two-week rule. But one thing you should do is get to a car wash rather than wash by hand. That’s because you want to make sure the bottom of the car is getting a thorough rinse, something typically only possible with water nozzles positioned underneath the body of the vehicle. (Rust-proofing, which &lt;a href="https://www.readersdigest.ca/cars/maintenance/rust-proofing-methods/" target="_blank"&gt;involves &lt;/a&gt;a spray coating to reduce corrosion, gets mixed reviews and may actually trap moisture if not properly applied.)&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bf q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-17"&gt;You don’t necessarily have to wash your car more often in the winter if you’re keeping up with the two-week rule. But one thing you should do is get to a car wash rather than wash by hand. That’s because you want to make sure the bottom of the car is getting a thorough rinse, something typically only possible with water nozzles positioned underneath the body of the vehicle. (Rust-proofing, which &lt;a href="https://www.readersdigest.ca/cars/maintenance/rust-proofing-methods/" target="_blank"&gt;involves &lt;/a&gt;a spray coating to reduce corrosion, gets mixed reviews and may actually trap moisture if not properly applied.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bh q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;Washing Your Car Less Often&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bi q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-18"&gt;Washing Your Car Less Often&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bk q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;If you find a bi-weekly wash daunting, you might be able to get away with less frequent maintenance with two preventative steps. First, try waxing your car after washing—it adds a protective layer to your car’s paint finish that makes it more resistant to corrosive elements. It also makes washing a little easier: Grime should rinse off more quickly. (Be mindful that some experts advise waxing more often; check the product you’re using for recommendations.)&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bl q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-19"&gt;If you find a bi-weekly wash daunting, you might be able to get away with less frequent maintenance with two preventative steps. First, try waxing your car after washing—it adds a protective layer to your car’s paint finish that makes it more resistant to corrosive elements. It also makes washing a little easier: Grime should rinse off more quickly. (Be mindful that some experts advise waxing more often; check the product you’re using for recommendations.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bn q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_2121,h_1414,x_0,y_0/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k60js3dkyfdwv3gj2y--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bo q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bp q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=bp q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bq q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=bq q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=br q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bs q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bt q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=bt q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=bs q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="Man Leaning Against Washed Cars in Garage" class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="1414" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_2121,h_1414/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k60js3dkyfdwv3gj2y.jpg" title="Man Leaning Against Washed Cars in Garage" width="2121" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Keeping your car in the garage could help you avoid more frequent washes. | Don Mason/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bx q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;If you’re able, storing your vehicle in a garage can also &lt;a href="https://www.meineke.com/blog/how-often-should-you-wash-your-car/" target="_blank"&gt;reduce&lt;/a&gt; the amount of debris it collects: A roof is able to protect it from most environmental factors like sap and birds. The less grime it collects, the less often you'll have to clean it off.  &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=by q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-21"&gt;If you’re able, storing your vehicle in a garage can also &lt;a href="https://www.meineke.com/blog/how-often-should-you-wash-your-car/" target="_blank"&gt;reduce&lt;/a&gt; the amount of debris it collects: A roof is able to protect it from most environmental factors like sap and birds. The less grime it collects, the less often you'll have to clean it off.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c0 q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;Handwashing vs. Car Washes&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c1 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-22"&gt;Handwashing vs. Car Washes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c3 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Using car washes every couple of weeks can get expensive, which is why some opt for hand-washing at home with a sponge and hose. If you don’t mind getting a little dirty, there’s no material difference between the two: Some auto experts &lt;a href="https://www.autozone.com/diy/wash-and-wax/benefits-of-handwashing-your-car-vs-automatic-car-wash" target="_blank"&gt;believe&lt;/a&gt; handwashing is actually superior since you can target problem areas and get a more thorough clean than a one-size-fits-all drive-through wash. Experts recommend using a separate rag or sponge for your car’s wheels, since the tires are the dirtiest part and you don’t want to transfer grime from their surface to your car’s paint.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c4 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-23"&gt;Using car washes every couple of weeks can get expensive, which is why some opt for hand-washing at home with a sponge and hose. If you don’t mind getting a little dirty, there’s no material difference between the two: Some auto experts &lt;a href="https://www.autozone.com/diy/wash-and-wax/benefits-of-handwashing-your-car-vs-automatic-car-wash" target="_blank"&gt;believe&lt;/a&gt; handwashing is actually superior since you can target problem areas and get a more thorough clean than a one-size-fits-all drive-through wash. Experts recommend using a separate rag or sponge for your car’s wheels, since the tires are the dirtiest part and you don’t want to transfer grime from their surface to your car’s paint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c6 q:key=vcaa:24--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c7 q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c8 q:key=vcaa:25--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c9 q:key=ndZW:mL_1--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-auto max-w-[90vw]"&gt;&lt;table class="border-collapse text-left w-full"&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="bg-lightGrey py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does Rain Clean Your Car?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;At some point, you may have put off a car wash because of recent rainfall. That’s sort of like a wash, right? Not really. Rainwater isn’t the same as water from a treated public supply: It can harbor minerals and acids that can damage paint. It’s also not pressurized, meaning it won’t get dirt and debris off effectively. If anything, you might want to consider washing your car &lt;em&gt;after &lt;/em&gt;a rainstorm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ca q:key=vcaa:26--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cb q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cc q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;While some people use a garden hose to rinse their car, it’s not really effective for general cleaning: You’ll still &lt;a href="https://www.turtlewax.com/blogs/how-to/can-a-pressure-washer-be-used-safely-for-car-cleaning" target="_blank"&gt;need to use&lt;/a&gt; a sponge or car mitt and bucket to make contact with the dirt. And unless you know precisely what you’re doing, using a pressure washer on a car can be risky. Too much water pressure can strip or damage paint and even shatter windows.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cd q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-27"&gt;While some people use a garden hose to rinse their car, it’s not really effective for general cleaning: You’ll still &lt;a href="https://www.turtlewax.com/blogs/how-to/can-a-pressure-washer-be-used-safely-for-car-cleaning" target="_blank"&gt;need to use&lt;/a&gt; a sponge or car mitt and bucket to make contact with the dirt. And unless you know precisely what you’re doing, using a pressure washer on a car can be risky. Too much water pressure can strip or damage paint and even shatter windows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cf q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;In the end, washing your car isn’t just about keeping up appearances. It’s likely you’ll want to sell or trade it in at some point in the future, which is when a well-maintained paint job and lack of rust or salt damage can pay off in the form of getting a better price. Chipped paint or rusted brakes can also imply you haven’t kept up with other maintenance, which could scare off potential buyers.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cg q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-28"&gt;In the end, washing your car isn’t just about keeping up appearances. It’s likely you’ll want to sell or trade it in at some point in the future, which is when a well-maintained paint job and lack of rust or salt damage can pay off in the form of getting a better price. Chipped paint or rusted brakes can also imply you haven’t kept up with other maintenance, which could scare off potential buyers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ci q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Consider it good automotive hygiene: If you wouldn’t go without a shower for two days, then your car probably shouldn’t go two weeks without a wash.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cj q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-29"&gt;Consider it good automotive hygiene: If you wouldn’t go without a shower for two days, then your car probably shouldn’t go two weeks without a wash.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org"&gt;Adblock test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org/acceptable.html"&gt;(Why?)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When High Control Politics Meet High Capacity Firepower</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/freedom-of-mind/202509/when-high-control-politics-meet-high-capacity-firepower</link><description>When implicit permission to attack is paired with easy access to highly lethal firearms, the risk of politically motivated violence rises.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:03:03 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Emptiness of Attacking Critics for Their Hypocrisy</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/free-speech-cancel-culture-republicans/684382/?utm_source=feed</link><description>It’s hard to defend crackdowns on free speech. It’s easier to simply claim everyone’s doing it.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:17:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Identify What Is Making a Task Hard or Slow</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/in-practice/202509/how-to-identify-what-is-making-a-task-hard-or-slow</link><description>Eliminate self-created friction without lowering important standards.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:27:49 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NIH Funds New Autism Studies on Genes and Environment as Trump Focuses on Tylenol</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/nih-funds-new-autism-studies-on-genes-and-environment-as-trump-focuses-on/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The National Institutes of Health is investing $50 million into research on genetic and environmental factors underlying autism&amp;mdash;news that was eclipsed by President Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s recent controversial claims about acetaminophen&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Hybrid Moral Codex for Human-AI Cohabitation</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/harnessing-hybrid-intelligence/202509/a-hybrid-moral-codex-for-human-ai-cohabitation</link><description>For business leaders, embracing a hybrid moral codex must be central to future-proofing operations. Three steps can help navigate a hybrid landscape.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:41:35 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The tug-of-war between engineering and design to build the Hyundai Palisade XRT Pro</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/engineering-and-design-hyundai-palisade-xrt-pro/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The brand toughened up its popular family SUV, but first, the design and engineering team had to agree on the dimensions and recovery hook placement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/engineering-and-design-hyundai-palisade-xrt-pro/"&gt;The tug-of-war between engineering and design to build the Hyundai Palisade XRT Pro&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Anti-Empathy Curriculum</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/deeper-empathy-lasting-change/202509/the-anti-empathy-curriculum</link><description>Many boys find belonging in spaces that equate worth with dominance. Why does that feel compelling, and how does empathy erode? Adults can do a few things to interrupt the slide.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:07:06 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>10 Strategies to Combat Loneliness</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/head-games/202509/10-strategies-to-combat-loneliness</link><description>New research identifies effective ways to feel more connected to oneself and others in our post-pandemic world.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:14:59 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Retirement and Marriage: Rules of Engagement</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/speaking-about-trauma/202509/retirement-and-marriage-rules-of-engagement</link><description>As increasing numbers of seniors retire, it is important to recognize the role of marriage in navigating the unexpected negative and positive life changes of retirement.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:24:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Spiritual Strength Requires Wisdom</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/philosophies-in-psychology/202509/spiritual-strength-requires-wisdom</link><description>True spiritual strength is not about control or dogma but about wisdom that embraces both clarity and madness.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:41:27 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Tips for Coping and Grounding in a Topsy-Turvy World</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/less-stress-more-peace/202509/tips-for-coping-and-grounding-in-a-topsy-turvy-world</link><description>Feeling a bit overwhelmed right now? You’re not alone. Here are a few tips for navigating an uncertain world and taking care of ourselves.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:08:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>9 Steps for Living an October Life</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/stonewall-strong/202509/9-steps-for-living-an-october-life</link><description>You too can live with authenticity, beauty, deliberateness, resilience, and wisdom—an October life—at any age and in every season of life.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:26:57 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>When Your Boss Has a Hard Time Meeting Deadlines</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/working-with-difficult-people/202509/when-your-boss-has-a-hard-time-meeting-deadlines</link><description>Does your boss have a hard time meeting deadlines? Take these steps to remain calm and regain structure in your workplace.&lt;br /&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:43:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Observing Aggression and Learning From It</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/what-are-the-chances/202509/observing-aggression-and-learning-from-it</link><description>In a groundbreaking study from 1961, Albert Bandura demonstrated that we learn by watching what others do. New evidence links observational learning to familiarity with models.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:03:57 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How Your Brain Conducts the Symphony of Speech</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/wired-for-words/202509/how-your-brain-conducts-the-symphony-of-speech</link><description>A tiny brain blip during silent speech revealed the shocking truth: Your brain plans words by imagining sounds, not movements. This discovery revolutionized speech science.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:13:03 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hurricane Humberto and Potential Tropical Storm Imelda Complicate Forecasts</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/hurricane-humberto-and-potential-tropical-storm-imelda-complicate-forecasts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hurricane Humberto and a system that may become Tropical Storm Imelda in the coming days are swirling quite close to each other in the western Atlantic Ocean&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 21:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Best Drinks for Brain Health</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-modern-brain/202509/the-best-drinks-for-brain-health</link><description>Are you already drinking these?</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:43:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Highly Caffeinated Energy Drinks and Teenage Gaming Disorder</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/addiction-outlook/202509/highly-caffeinated-energy-drinks-and-teenage-gaming-disorder</link><description>Many teens play vido games but some develop a gaming disorder, leading them to neglect family, friends, and school. They may abuse caffeine and other stimulants to improve scores.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 18:16:55 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>A Pediatrician’s Lament</title><link>https://nautil.us/a-pediatricians-lament-1239480/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How the blustery rhetoric of Trump and Kennedy makes life harder for local physicians&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/a-pediatricians-lament-1239480/"&gt;A Pediatrician’s Lament&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 23:00:13 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>