<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/merged-feed/merged.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS from multiple sources</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/merged-feed/merged.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:18:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ultra-processed foods might not be the real villain in our diets – here’s what our research found</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ultra-processed-foods-might-not-be-the-real-villain-in-our-diets-heres-what-our-research-found-261867</link><description>Chocolate and porridge are both popular but only one gets binged. Why? Our psychology plays a bigger role in overeating than food labels alone.</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:42:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Do people dream in color or black and white?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/do-people-dream-in-color-or-black-and-white-256971</link><description>Researchers have found dreams are most likely to occur during the stage of sleep known as rapid eye movement, or REM.</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:46:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Drought can make farmers feel worried and hopeless: Ghana study finds social networks help</title><link>https://theconversation.com/drought-can-make-farmers-feel-worried-and-hopeless-ghana-study-finds-social-networks-help-262627</link><description>Drought adversely affects the mental health of Ghanaian farmers.</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 14:02:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why do smart people get hooked on wellness trends? Personality traits may play a role</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-do-smart-people-get-hooked-on-wellness-trends-personality-traits-may-play-a-role-263041</link><description>Certain personality traits may help explain why some educated, well-intentioned people sometimes reject conventional medicine in favour of fringe practices.</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:35:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Are you really an ISFJ? The truth about personality tests – and why we keep taking them</title><link>https://theconversation.com/are-you-really-an-isfj-the-truth-about-personality-tests-and-why-we-keep-taking-them-261183</link><description>Tests such as Myers-Briggs promise self-discovery – but here’s why you shouldn’t take them too seriously.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 05:11:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1 in 3 teens has thought about suicide this year. Here’s what to look for – and where to get help</title><link>https://theconversation.com/1-in-3-teens-has-thought-about-suicide-this-year-heres-what-to-look-for-and-where-to-get-help-263422</link><description>A suicide attempt doesn’t always involve prior planning or thinking. But there are warnings signs.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 05:18:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why people embrace conspiracy theories: it’s about community, not gullibility</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-people-embrace-conspiracy-theories-its-about-community-not-gullibility-262276</link><description>Far from being isolated outsiders, conspiracy theorists enjoy thriving communities that recruit and organise activism.</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 12:09:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eating disorder symptoms in teens can be traced back to family hardship, new study shows</title><link>https://theconversation.com/eating-disorder-symptoms-in-teens-can-be-traced-back-to-family-hardship-new-study-shows-263529</link><description>It’s a stereotype that eating disorders mainly affect people from wealthy backgrounds.</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 01:28:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Burnt out and radicalised: how workplace exhaustion breeds extremist thinking – new study</title><link>https://theconversation.com/burnt-out-and-radicalised-how-workplace-exhaustion-breeds-extremist-thinking-new-study-261123</link><description>Our research found a link between burnout and support for extremist violence.</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 08:28:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Defendants in sexual assault cases are just as likely to misremember the event as alleged victims – new study</title><link>https://theconversation.com/defendants-in-sexual-assault-cases-are-just-as-likely-to-misremember-the-event-as-alleged-victims-new-study-262841</link><description>In court, scrutiny is normally focused on the alleged victim’s ability to recall details from the event.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 10:05:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Phubbing’: why ignoring your partner for your phone infuriates certain people – and causes them to retaliate</title><link>https://theconversation.com/phubbing-why-ignoring-your-partner-for-your-phone-infuriates-certain-people-and-causes-them-to-retaliate-263963</link><description>Research shows that ‘phubbing’ – ignoring a partner to look at your phone – can lower relationship satisfaction and spark retaliation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 10:50:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why scammers fake illness for cash, according to a psychologist</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-scammers-fake-illness-for-cash-according-to-a-psychologist-263264</link><description>What type of person lies to friends and family about having cancer?</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 20:03:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What does it mean to become an adult? In Namibia, it’s caring for others</title><link>https://theconversation.com/what-does-it-mean-to-become-an-adult-in-namibia-its-caring-for-others-263223</link><description>There is no single way of becoming an adult in the world.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 13:53:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>65,000 Pennsylvania kids have a parent in prison or jail − here’s what research says about the value of in-person visits</title><link>https://theconversation.com/65-000-pennsylvania-kids-have-a-parent-in-prison-or-jail-heres-what-research-says-about-the-value-of-in-person-visits-262185</link><description>In-person visits in prisons and jails can strengthen family relationships and reduce recidivism.</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 12:28:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Powerful images show dark side of South-East Asia’s fishing industry</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495209-powerful-images-show-dark-side-of-south-east-asias-fishing-industry/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Photographer Nicole Tung captures the tough world facing South-East Asia’s fishers and their families in this series of images, which won her the Carmignac Photojournalism Award for fieldwork</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 21:00:18 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>We’ve glimpsed the secret quantum landscape inside all matter</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494508-weve-glimpsed-the-secret-quantum-landscape-inside-all-matter/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A strange kind of geometry governs how particles move inside matter. Now, for the first time, physicists have uncovered its full shape – and it could transform how we design materials</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:00:16 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What we’ve learned about narcissism over the past 30 years</title><link>https://theconversation.com/what-weve-learned-about-narcissism-over-the-past-30-years-258505</link><description>Narcissism is a picture that includes insecurity, emotional sensitivity and surprising fragility.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 14:27:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can a strange new treatment finally relieve chronic sinus infections?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494362-can-a-strange-new-treatment-finally-relieve-chronic-sinus-infections/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Constant loss of smell, facial pain and a blocked nose are a reality for the 10 per cent of people living with chronic rhinosinusitis, a disease long-neglected by research. Targeting the nasal microbiome, though, is offering hope</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:00:19 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Mass hysteria at Heathrow airport – how social contagion works</title><link>https://theconversation.com/mass-hysteria-at-heathrow-airport-how-social-contagion-works-264900</link><description>Heathrow’s Terminal 4 evacuation shows the power of social contagion.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:02:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How our minds trick us into thinking we are being greener than we really are</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-our-minds-trick-us-into-thinking-we-are-being-greener-than-we-really-are-263959</link><description>Adding “green” products to your food basket doesn’t reduce its carbon footprint – even though we think it does.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:37:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Earth’s climate in a state of 'termination shock'?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494279-is-earths-climate-in-a-state-of-termination-shock/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Cleaning up air pollution has saved millions of lives, but it has also given us an inadvertent taste of a nightmare climate scenario. The race is on to understand how bad it could be – and how to swerve the worst effects</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:00:31 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Which perimenopause treatments actually work?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2493005-which-perimenopause-treatments-actually-work/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>For women going through perimenopause, there is no shortage of advice on how to deal with the symptoms – but which strategies show real results, and which are social media hype?</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 17:00:34 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Matt Richtel grapples with how modern life is warping adolescence</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735600-400-matt-richtel-grapples-with-how-modern-life-is-warping-adolescence/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Not only are children starting puberty earlier, they face a digital world where, for good and bad, most of their interactions are internalised. How We Grow Up is scary, illuminating and hopeful, says Chris Simms</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Alien: Earth adds surprisingly good TV dimension to veteran sci-fi</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735600-600-alien-earth-adds-surprisingly-good-tv-dimension-to-veteran-sci-fi/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>After 50 years of books, games and movies, what more could the Alien franchise deliver? An inventive TV show, with fresh monsters and new heroes, finds our TV critic Bethan Ackerley</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How to pick the right fertiliser for all your different plants</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735602-600-how-to-pick-the-right-fertiliser-for-all-your-different-plants/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>There are three key nutrients that all plants need – nitrogen, phosphorous and potassium – but in different amounts. So finding fertiliser that suits all your plants might seem tricky, but there is a simple solution, says James Wong</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Telling incoming aliens from space rocks… on a scale of 1 to 10!</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735601-600-telling-incoming-aliens-from-space-rocks-on-a-scale-of-1-to-10/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Feedback is mystified by a new way to assess interstellar visitors and the risks they pose, be they lumps of ice or alien craft. Just pray they don’t top out on the Loeb Scale</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>DNA cassette tape can store every song ever recorded</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495758-dna-cassette-tape-can-store-every-song-ever-recorded/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>By combining the information storage capabilities of DNA with a design inspired by a cassette tape, researchers have created a storage medium that can hold 36 petabytes of data</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 20:00:34 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A weird cloud forms on Mars each year and now we know why</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495985-a-weird-cloud-forms-on-mars-each-year-and-now-we-know-why/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Astronomers have struggled to explain why a long and thin cloud forms above Mars’s Arsia Mons volcano each year, until now</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 18:00:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Jupiter is smaller and more squashed than we thought</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496032-jupiter-is-smaller-and-more-squashed-than-we-thought/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The gas giant has been measured for the first time in decades, trimming 8 kilometres from its diameter</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 11:00:39 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Hedonistic habits could turn you into a mosquito magnet</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496103-hedonistic-habits-could-turn-you-into-a-mosquito-magnet/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A study of festivalgoers suggests that drinking beer and sharing a bed makes you more attractive to mosquitoes</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 14:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Child obesity is now more common than undernutrition – what do we do?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496086-child-obesity-is-now-more-common-than-undernutrition-what-do-we-do/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Childhood obesity rates have surpassed those of undernutrition for the first time, suggesting efforts to combat malnutrition will have to shift gears.</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:57:48 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Jaguar breaks records by swimming at least 1.3 kilometres</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496123-jaguar-breaks-records-by-swimming-at-least-1-3-kilometres/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A 1.3-kilometre swim by a jaguar is the longest ever confirmed, but the cat's motives for making the journey are unclear</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 18:00:59 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Higher dose of Wegovy ups both weight loss and side effects</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496140-higher-dose-of-wegovy-ups-both-weight-loss-and-side-effects/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Trial participants who received an increased weekly dose of Wegovy lost 19 per cent of their body weight in a year on average, but also saw a higher risk of painful skin sensations and nausea</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:30:21 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The death of dinosaurs dramatically re-engineered Earth's landscapes</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496215-the-death-of-dinosaurs-dramatically-re-engineered-earths-landscapes/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Changes in rock formations from before and after the mass extinction event 66 million years ago may reflect how dinosaurs acted as ecosystem engineers, shaping vegetation and even the meandering of rivers</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 11:43:45 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Stealth radio hides signal in background noise to protect drone pilots</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495997-stealth-radio-hides-signal-in-background-noise-to-protect-drone-pilots/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>As drones have risen to prominence on the battlefield, so too has electronic warfare, in which adversaries attempt to mask, jam or trace radio signals. Now, a new stealthy radio device could help give people the edge, letting them fly drones without detection</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 13:00:57 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Covid-19 vaccine benefits worth up to $38 trillion in first year alone</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496200-covid-19-vaccine-benefits-worth-up-to-38-trillion-in-first-year-alone/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The global health and economic benefits of covid-19 vaccines came to between $5 trillion and $38 trillion in their first year, showing an incredible return on investment</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 16:00:24 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What it’s like to run the world’s best dark matter detector</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2493944-what-its-like-to-run-the-worlds-best-dark-matter-detector/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Chamkaur Ghag is on a mission to find the 85 per cent of the universe’s matter that we haven’t yet identified. He details his hopes for the major scientific experiment – and what the future could hold</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:00:42 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Racism isn’t innate – here are five psychological stages that may lead to it</title><link>https://theconversation.com/racism-isnt-innate-here-are-five-psychological-stages-that-may-lead-to-it-264391</link><description>There is no genetic or biological basis for dividing the human race into distinct “races.”</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mars once had an atmosphere that was thicker than Earth's today</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496379-mars-once-had-an-atmosphere-that-was-thicker-than-earths-today/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>While Mars today only has a wispy remnant of an atmosphere, it may once have had one hundreds of times thicker with a pressure three times that on Earth</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 19:00:37 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Modular nuclear reactors sound great, but won't be ready any time soon</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496252-modular-nuclear-reactors-sound-great-but-wont-be-ready-any-time-soon/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The UK government has announced a raft of tiny nuclear power projects, while Russia, China and a host of tech giants are also betting big on small nuclear reactor designs. Does the idea make sense and can they really be built any time soon?</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 19:46:47 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The oldest human mummies were slowly smoked 14,000 years ago</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496267-the-oldest-human-mummies-were-slowly-smoked-14000-years-ago/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>For at least 10,000 years, humans across South-East Asia were being carefully preserved after death by being smoke-dried – a tradition that continues to this day in some cultures</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:00:28 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>AI companies want copyright exemptions – for NZ creatives, the market is their best protection</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-companies-want-copyright-exemptions-for-nz-creatives-the-market-is-their-best-protection-264468</link><description>AI ‘learns’ by digesting copyright-protected material, with billions at stake. Proper licensing deals offer the best solution for authors, artists and publishers.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 23:35:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lunar missions may contaminate the moon with hardy Earth microbes</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496319-lunar-missions-may-contaminate-the-moon-with-hardy-earth-microbes/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Experiments on Earth indicate some common species of bacteria and fungi could survive for several days on the moon's surface, suggesting missions must take stronger precautions to avoid contamination</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 09:00:09 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Good immune health may come at the expense of chronic inflammation</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496443-good-immune-health-may-come-at-the-expense-of-chronic-inflammation/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Inflammation is a vital part of the immune response, but it seems that the system can sometimes go awry, resulting in chronic inflammation that has been linked to conditions such as cancer</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 12:03:30 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Making atoms self-magnify reveals their quantum wave functions</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496211-making-atoms-self-magnify-reveals-their-quantum-wave-functions/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Trapping ultracold atoms with laser light let researchers magnify and then image the wave functions of atoms that were previously too close together to look like anything but a blob</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 13:00:42 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Around one-third of AI search tool answers make unsupported claims</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496133-around-one-third-of-ai-search-tool-answers-make-unsupported-claims/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>AI tools including Perplexity and Open AI’s GPT-4 often provide one-sided answers to contentious questions, and don’t back up their arguments with reliable sources</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:00:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The real scientific insights from Bryan Johnson’s immortality quest</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495156-the-real-scientific-insights-from-bryan-johnsons-immortality-quest/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Tech millionaire turned longevity pioneer Bryan Johnson devotes more than 6 hours a day to trialling different methods to turn back the clock. Can the rest of us learn anything from his radical approach?</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:01 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What’s the secret to living well beyond the average life expectancy?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495136-whats-the-secret-to-living-well-beyond-the-average-life-expectancy/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Many of us know people who live into their 90s, but hardly anyone makes it to 100. Studies are now revealing that factors that really make a difference</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:11 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How to nurture the right mindset for living to 100</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495108-how-to-nurture-the-right-mindset-for-living-to-100/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>It’s not just diet and exercise that governs how well you age. Your mindset, social connections and sense of purpose make a big difference, and it’s never too late to start working on them</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:13 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Why caring for your microbiome is crucial if you want to live to 100</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494981-why-caring-for-your-microbiome-is-crucial-if-you-want-to-live-to-100/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Our friendly – and not so friendly – gut bacteria lie at the core of healthy ageing. Research is now revealing what it takes to maintain a youthful microbiome</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:48 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The exercises you need to do to reach 100 in great shape</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494852-the-exercises-you-need-to-do-to-reach-100-in-great-shape/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>To be truly fit in older age, you need to work on specific aspects of your fitness – and research shows that it’s never too late to reap the benefits</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The science revealing how the right diet can add a decade to your life</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494953-the-science-revealing-how-the-right-diet-can-add-a-decade-to-your-life/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Evidence shows that eating a longevity diet can dramatically lengthen your lifespan – and the sooner you start, the more of a difference it makes</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:57 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Long covid may be making your periods longer and heavier</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496524-long-covid-may-be-making-your-periods-longer-and-heavier/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Half a decade since the arrival of the SARS-CoV-2 virus, we're still learning about its complications, with the latest research suggesting that long covid may disrupt menstrual periods</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 18:04:50 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>30,000-year-old toolkit shows what ancient hunter carried in a pouch</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496225-30000-year-old-toolkit-shows-what-ancient-hunter-carried-in-a-pouch/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A set of 29 stone tools, including blades and points for hunting, butchering and cutting wood, were found neatly arranged as if carried in a leather pouch that decayed</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 19:01:13 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Our new study found AI is wreaking havoc on uni assessments. Here’s how we should respond</title><link>https://theconversation.com/our-new-study-found-ai-is-wreaking-havoc-on-uni-assessments-heres-how-we-should-respond-264787</link><description>New research argues the problem of AI and assessment is way more difficult than media debates have been making out.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 20:10:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Serious mental illness often brings rapid weight gain – but support is missing</title><link>https://theconversation.com/serious-mental-illness-often-brings-rapid-weight-gain-but-support-is-missing-264842</link><description>People with schizophrenia and bipolar disorder gain 5kg in five years. The average person gains 1.5kg.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 09:24:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asteroid exploded 'similar to a bomb' over France in a rare event</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496598-asteroid-exploded-similar-to-a-bomb-over-france-in-a-rare-event/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>An asteroid called 2023 CX1 underwent a single explosion, hinting that it had an unusual structure that might be more damaging on the ground</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 11:00:35 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Impostor syndrome: the cost of being ‘superwoman’ at work and beyond</title><link>https://theconversation.com/impostor-syndrome-the-cost-of-being-superwoman-at-work-and-beyond-265218</link><description>Female leaders are under pressure to excel, professionally and personally, without showing weakness or strain. The emergence of neoliberal feminism helps explain why, and a milestone in psychology describes what can result.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 10:22:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global suicide rates fell 30 per cent since 1990 – but not in the US</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496424-global-suicide-rates-fell-30-per-cent-since-1990-but-not-in-the-us/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>While most countries have seen a steady decline in suicide rates, the United States has witnessed the opposite, with suicides jumping almost 30 per cent since 2000</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 14:00:12 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Stretching the skin could enable vaccines to be given without a needle</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496664-stretching-the-skin-could-enable-vaccines-to-be-given-without-a-needle/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Using a suction device to stretch the skin seems to increase its permeability and stimulate immune cells, which could allow vaccines to be administered topically</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:00:29 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Dome-headed dinosaur from Mongolia is the oldest ever found</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496656-dome-headed-dinosaur-from-mongolia-is-the-oldest-ever-found/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A fossil from about 108 million years ago reveals an early member of the pachycephalosaurs, a group of dinosaurs with bizarre protrusions on their skulls that may have been used in combat</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:00:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>In the race to reach 100, the wealthy have a head start</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735612-800-in-the-race-to-reach-100-the-wealthy-have-a-head-start/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>There are more centenarians now than ever before. But more must be done to address inequalities that prevent people from having a realistic chance of hitting this milestone.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Steven Pinker’s new book shows how he’s become a contradictory figure</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735610-200-steven-pinkers-new-book-shows-how-hes-become-a-contradictory-figure/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Steven Pinker’s new book When Everyone Knows That Everyone Knows makes a compelling case for common knowledge. Shame the politics muddies the waters</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A radical idea to fix plastics recycling</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735611-900-a-radical-idea-to-fix-plastics-recycling/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Making all shampoo or detergent bottles look the same isn't anti-capitalist, and it's the only way to make a truly circular economy for plastics, says Saabira Chaudhuri</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Where’s my jetpack got to? And other sci-fi tech queries</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735610-100-wheres-my-jetpack-got-to-and-other-sci-fi-tech-queries/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>We are still waiting for the retro-futuristic tech and social revolutions envisioned in science fiction’s old gold, writes Annalee Newitz – not to mention advances in reproduction</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Ian McEwan’s new novel weaves climate change into literary mystery</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735610-500-ian-mcewans-new-novel-weaves-climate-change-into-literary-mystery/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Ian McEwan’s excellent What We Can Know is set in a UK largely swallowed up by rising seas. Emily H. Wilson explores the story of a scholar hunting a great lost poem – which may have something to with climate change</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Three simple rules for a great post-workout meal</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735610-800-three-simple-rules-for-a-great-post-workout-meal/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Taking care of your body’s nutritional needs after training doesn't have to be a headache. Grace Wade sums up three key pillars she uses to refuel with confidence</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Dramatic photos show bid to save the Javan slow loris</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735612-000-dramatic-photos-show-bid-to-save-the-javan-slow-loris/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The photos tell an unusual rescue story – the release of the critically endangered Javan slow lorises into Ujung Kulon National Park on Java Island, Indonesia, last month.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Wild chimpanzees may get mildly intoxicated from alcoholic fruit</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496701-wild-chimpanzees-may-get-mildly-intoxicated-from-alcoholic-fruit/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Chimpanzees are consuming significant levels of alcohol from their diet of ripe fruit and the finding may help explain the origins of humans’ taste for alcohol</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 20:00:18 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Heat, air quality, insurance costs: how climate change is affecting our homes – and our health</title><link>https://theconversation.com/heat-air-quality-insurance-costs-how-climate-change-is-affecting-our-homes-and-our-health-263278</link><description>Our homes can and must protect us against some of the risks of climate change.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 20:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vitamin D supplements may lower your level of one type of vitamin D</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496879-vitamin-d-supplements-may-lower-your-level-of-one-type-of-vitamin-d/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Taking vitamin D2 supplements seems to reduce levels of vitamin D3 in our body</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:01:51 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Government announces 2035 target of 62–70% emissions reduction</title><link>https://theconversation.com/government-announces-2035-target-of-62-70-emissions-reduction-265381</link><description>The Albanese government has announced Australia will commit to cutting emissions by between 62% and 70% on 2005 levels by 2035.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 04:09:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Albanese government has finally set a 2035 climate course – and it’s a mission Australia must accept</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-albanese-government-has-finally-set-a-2035-climate-course-and-its-a-mission-australia-must-accept-264885</link><description>The target seeks to balance positive action with pragmatism. Achieving it will requires a major policy step-up.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 04:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cut emissions 70% by 2035? There’s only one policy that can get us there</title><link>https://theconversation.com/cut-emissions-70-by-2035-theres-only-one-policy-that-can-get-us-there-264884</link><description>To cut emissions fast, the Australian government will have to dial back its command-and-control approach –&amp;nbsp;and put a price on carbon.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 06:50:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Simple menu tweak can nudge people into choosing climate-friendly food</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496570-simple-menu-tweak-can-nudge-people-into-choosing-climate-friendly-food/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Rejigging the meal choices on offer in a canteen can prompt people to make healthier, climate-friendlier decisions</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 09:00:10 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Quantum computers are finally on the verge of being useful</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496013-quantum-computers-are-finally-on-the-verge-of-being-useful/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Two experiments with different quantum computers showcase their growing ability to simulate materials and quantum matter that have so far proven elusive in the lab</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:00:29 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Curious kids: why do we dream?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/curious-kids-why-do-we-dream-264817</link><description>Why scientists still can’t agree what dreams are for.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 12:09:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scams and frauds: Here are the tactics criminals use on you in the age of AI and cryptocurrencies</title><link>https://theconversation.com/scams-and-frauds-here-are-the-tactics-criminals-use-on-you-in-the-age-of-ai-and-cryptocurrencies-264867</link><description>Technology has supercharged fraud. The ruses are ancient, but the tools scammers use are cutting edge.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 12:46:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A walk across Alaska’s Arctic sea ice brings to life the losses that appear in climate data</title><link>https://theconversation.com/a-walk-across-alaskas-arctic-sea-ice-brings-to-life-the-losses-that-appear-in-climate-data-254910</link><description>A polar scientist explains the changes hunters who rely on the ice are seeing off Utqiagvik, and how those shifts are echoed in satellite data and climate models.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:40:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Some viruses like to cheat – and that may be good for our health</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496881-some-viruses-like-to-cheat-and-that-may-be-good-for-our-health/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Mutations can result in viruses that infect cells, but can't copy themselves without help from other viruses - now it seems these cheats may outnumber normal viruses in a third of influenza cases, reducing the severity of infections</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:00:41 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Stunning amber deposits hold insects from the time of the dinosaurs</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496954-stunning-amber-deposits-hold-insects-from-the-time-of-the-dinosaurs/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A sand quarry in Ecuador has yielded South America’s first amber with bio-inclusions, including a spider's web and a collection of mosquitoes, beetles, flies, wasps and biting midges that lived 112 million years ago</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:00:23 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A volcano or a meteorite? New evidence sheds light on puzzling discovery in Greenland’s ice sheet</title><link>https://theconversation.com/a-volcano-or-a-meteorite-new-evidence-sheds-light-on-puzzling-discovery-in-greenlands-ice-sheet-265257</link><description>New research suggests that a mystery platinum signature found in Greenland’s ice may have come from a volcanic eruption in Iceland.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:18:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Genetics Can Track How Languages Mixed in the Past</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/genetics-can-track-how-languages-mixed-in-the-past/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New research shows that wherever human populations mix, their languages blend as well&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New AI Tool Predicts Which of 1,000 Diseases Someone May Develop in 20 Years</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/new-ai-tool-predicts-which-of-1-000-diseases-someone-may-develop-in-20-years/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A large language model called Delphi-2M analyzes a person&amp;rsquo;s medical records and lifestyle to provide risk estimates for more than 1,000 diseases&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Starting HRT in early menopause may reduce women's risk of Alzheimer's</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496596-starting-hrt-in-early-menopause-may-reduce-womens-risk-of-alzheimers/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Hormone replacement therapy used within five years of the onset of menopause is associated with a lower risk of Alzheimer’s disease, while starting it later in life is associated with an increased risk</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:36:30 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Aftershock of July’s 8.8 Earthquake Strikes Kamchatka. Tsunami Risk Waning</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/aftershock-of-julys-8-8-earthquake-strikes-kamchatka-tsunami-risk-waning/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A powerful magnitude 7.8 aftershock off Russia&amp;rsquo;s Kamchatka Peninsula that arose from July&amp;rsquo;s magnitude 8.8 earthquake is raising concerns about possible tsunami impacts, although risk appears to be waning&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Does ASMR really help with anxiety? A psychology expert explains the evidence</title><link>https://theconversation.com/does-asmr-really-help-with-anxiety-a-psychology-expert-explains-the-evidence-252181</link><description>The autonomous sensory meridian response may be linked to certain personality types and traits such as introversion.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:26:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>7 things we can do today to meet Australia’s new climate goal</title><link>https://theconversation.com/7-things-we-can-do-today-to-meet-australias-new-climate-goal-265023</link><description>Australia has the technologies to meet and exceed its new emissions target. The work now is to ensure they’re deployed at scale.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 03:39:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hollywood is suing yet another AI company. But there may be a better way to solve copyright conflicts</title><link>https://theconversation.com/hollywood-is-suing-yet-another-ai-company-but-there-may-be-a-better-way-to-solve-copyright-conflicts-265663</link><description>Different licensing models could help ensure the rights of creators are reconciled with AI companies’ hunger for data.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 03:53:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Etymology Nerd' Adam Aleksic on How Internet Culture Is Transforming the Way We Talk</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/etymology-nerd-adam-aleksic-on-how-internet-culture-is-transforming-the-way/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Linguist Adam Aleksic explains how viral slang and algorithm-driven speech aren&amp;rsquo;t destroying language&amp;ndash;&amp;ndash;they&amp;rsquo;re accelerating its natural evolution.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Quantum computers have finally achieved unconditional supremacy</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496944-quantum-computers-have-finally-achieved-unconditional-supremacy/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>For the first time, researchers have mathematically proven that a quantum computer can solve a particular task faster than an ordinary computer, in a way that can never be beaten</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:00:46 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Weigh a Black Hole</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-to-weigh-a-black-hole/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gauging the mass of a black hole is tricky, but astronomers have devised multiple methods to measure the heft of these galactic gluttons&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Think, Not What to Think</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/teach-students-how-think-not-what-think/684271/?utm_source=feed</link><description>College is not just about transmitting knowledge—it’s also about learning and practicing the skills that connect us to one another.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NASA Records More Than 6,000 Exoplanets and Counting</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/nasa-records-more-than-6-000-exoplanets-and-counting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a crowded galaxy, the latest exoplanet tally shows&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The tech prosperity deal is huge. But will the UK reap the benefits?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-tech-prosperity-deal-is-huge-but-will-the-uk-reap-the-benefits-265621</link><description>US tech firms have promised billions of pounds of investment into the UK.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 12:19:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Naming and categorizing objects is part of how young kids develop executive function skills – new research</title><link>https://theconversation.com/naming-and-categorizing-objects-is-part-of-how-young-kids-develop-executive-function-skills-new-research-255943</link><description>Kids with good executive function tend to grow up to be financially stable, healthy, productive adults. Past attempts to teach these skills have flopped. New brain research on language may change that.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 12:39:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suicide-by-chatbot puts Big Tech in the product liability hot seat</title><link>https://theconversation.com/suicide-by-chatbot-puts-big-tech-in-the-product-liability-hot-seat-265550</link><description>Internet companies have long enjoyed immunity for hosting other people’s content. AI chatbots are changing the legal equation.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 12:39:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Where you store fat may influence the effect it has on your brain</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496947-where-you-store-fat-may-influence-the-effect-it-has-on-your-brain/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Data from more than 18,000 people suggests that where excess fat is stored in the body influences its effects on brain structure, activity and health</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:55:22 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A Rogue Nation on the High Seas</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/rogue-nation-high-seas/684272/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Trump is treating the military like his personal mercenaries.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:02:24 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Go Ahead, Write in the Margins—It’s Good for Your Brain</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/go-ahead-write-in-the-margins-its-good-for-your-brain/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Annotating the margins of books is an important part&amp;nbsp;of deep reading and has a long legacy of merit in both science and literature&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Atmospheric hydrogen is rising, which may be a problem for the climate</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497053-atmospheric-hydrogen-is-rising-which-may-be-a-problem-for-the-climate/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Ice core records of atmospheric hydrogen reveal a huge rise in concentration since the Industrial Revolution which has contributed to global warming – and could sway the debate over hydrogen as a fuel</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:31:33 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Have You Considered Not Polluting the Water?</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/ai-friend-startup/684256/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The tech industry will do anything to solve our loneliness epidemic except stop causing it in the first place.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:54:39 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>One blood sample could reveal the age of 11 of your organs and systems</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497154-one-blood-sample-could-reveal-the-age-of-11-of-your-organs-and-systems/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The rate that our heart or liver ages may differ from that of our immune or hormonal systems, and now it seems that a single blood test could break that down</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 17:00:24 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>2025 Ig Nobel Prizes Awarded for Research on Tipsy Bats and Pasta Physics</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/2025-ig-nobel-prizes-awarded-for-research-on-tipsy-bats-and-pasta-physics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Winners of the annual Ig Nobel awards include the science of tipsy bats and the physics of &lt;i&gt;cacio e pepe&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unforgeable quantum money can be stored in an ultracold ‘debit card’</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497081-unforgeable-quantum-money-can-be-stored-in-an-ultracold-debit-card/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Using the quantum states of particles of light as currency could make for unforgeable transactions, and a new experiment has added a way to save some of that quantum money for future use, too</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Riding the Rockies on the Ducati XDiavel V4</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/ducati-xdiavel-v4/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The bike provides impressive ease of use to go with its high performance and visceral engine character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/ducati-xdiavel-v4/"&gt;Riding the Rockies on the Ducati XDiavel V4&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>This Isn’t Dubai; It’s Tuscaloosa</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/sorority-rush/684259/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Whose daddy is paying for all this?</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 07:31:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The pros and cons of not raking leaves</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/pros-and-cons-of-not-raking-leaves/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Your local beetles and chipmunks will thank you for backing away from the rake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/pros-and-cons-of-not-raking-leaves/"&gt;The pros and cons of not raking leaves&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shop these early Prime Day deals on powerful Ego battery-powered chainsaws and yard tools</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/ego-battery-powered-chainsaw-yard-tool-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;These battery-powered saws are even more powerful than their gas-powered competition. Plus, they're quieter and easier to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/ego-battery-powered-chainsaw-yard-tool-deals/"&gt;Shop these early Prime Day deals on powerful Ego battery-powered chainsaws and yard tools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 09:56:09 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>What every button on your iPhone can do (including hidden features)</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/what-iphone-buttons-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Five buttons, so many possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/what-iphone-buttons-do/"&gt;What every button on your iPhone can do (including hidden features)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump Might Be Losing His Race Against Time</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/trump-bondi-edva/684292/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The president is gambling that he can consolidate authority before the public turns too sharply against him.</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 11:49:02 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>14 winning images from the Ocean Photographer of the Year awards</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/ocean-photogapher-of-the-year-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Admire our mighty oceans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/ocean-photogapher-of-the-year-2025/"&gt;14 winning images from the Ocean Photographer of the Year awards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>New research shows Black Summer’s megafires left lasting scars far beyond property damage</title><link>https://theconversation.com/new-research-shows-black-summers-megafires-left-lasting-scars-far-beyond-property-damage-264195</link><description>The study found poorer communities, renters and women carried the heaviest burdens long after the Black Summer fires were put out.</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 19:35:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>With 2035 emissions targets set, what Australia does next will help shape global efforts to keep 1.5°C alive</title><link>https://theconversation.com/with-2035-emissions-targets-set-what-australia-does-next-will-help-shape-global-efforts-to-keep-1-5-c-alive-265665</link><description>Australia’s new emission target comes amid worrying signs of backsliding on climate action. As global leaders gather at the UN, Australia can play a role.</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 19:36:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vaccine Panel Overhaul, Head Trauma in Sports, and Strange Reproduction in Ants</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/vaccine-panel-overhaul-head-trauma-in-sports-and-strange-reproduction-in/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A revamped CDC advisory committee faces vaccine debates, studies reveal brain changes in athletes, and climate change drives deadly heat waves across Europe.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is reading always better for your brain than listening to audiobooks?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497112-is-reading-always-better-for-your-brain-than-listening-to-audiobooks/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Reading books and listening to audiobooks tap into different elements of cognition, each with their own benefits. So which one should you choose, and when?</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:00:40 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Cutting down the Amazon will bring extreme rain, wind and heat</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497158-cutting-down-the-amazon-will-bring-extreme-rain-wind-and-heat/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>We used to think that deforestation in the Amazon would dry out the local climate, but the effects may be even more extreme and varied</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:28:43 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside the Mysterious Smuggling of the El Ali Meteorite</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/inside-the-mysterious-smuggling-of-the-el-ali-meteorite/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How a space rock vanished from Africa and showed up for sale across an ocean&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why are there so many protests? The US public is highly polarized, and that drives people to act</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-are-there-so-many-protests-the-us-public-is-highly-polarized-and-that-drives-people-to-act-263021</link><description>Anger at the other side, as represented by the political party opposing yours, is a powerful motivator to engage in protests.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 12:15:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How users can make their AI companions feel real – from picking personality traits to creating fan art</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-users-can-make-their-ai-companions-feel-real-from-picking-personality-traits-to-creating-fan-art-265442</link><description>The strong bonds that users are forming with their AI chatbots rest on the human imagination at work.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 12:17:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Most Profound Transgression</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/trump-bondi-doj/684293/?utm_source=feed</link><description>In demanding that the attorney general go after his enemies, Donald Trump is upending fundamental norms of fairness and neutrality in the American legal system.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 08:32:31 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>What exactly is the UV Index? A dermatologist explains.</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/what-is-uv-index/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The measurement has nothing to do with how hot it is outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/what-is-uv-index/"&gt;What exactly is the UV Index? A dermatologist explains.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How US-UK tech deal could yield significant benefits for the British public – expert Q&amp;A</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-us-uk-tech-deal-could-yield-significant-benefits-for-the-british-public-expert-qanda-265707</link><description>The £150bn package could yield real benefits in public health, as well as other areas of technology.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 13:16:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ancient Egypt’s cemetery police blew bone whistles made from cow toes</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/ancient-egypt-police-whistle/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The 3,300-year-old artifact was found in the capital of the ‘Heretic King.’ &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/ancient-egypt-police-whistle/"&gt;Ancient Egypt’s cemetery police blew bone whistles made from cow toes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 09:33:34 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Almost Impossible’ Deep-Earth Diamonds Confirm How These Gems Form</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/almost-impossible-deep-earth-diamonds-confirm-how-these-gems-form/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Seemingly contradictory materials are trapped together in two glittering diamonds from South Africa, shedding light on how diamonds form&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>It’s dragonfly migration season!</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/dragonfly-migration-season/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Keep an eye out for dragonfly swarms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/dragonfly-migration-season/"&gt;It’s dragonfly migration season!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 10:10:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Magnitude 4.3 Earthquake Strikes San Francisco Bay Area</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/magnitude-4-3-earthquake-strikes-san-francisco-bay-area/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The San Francisco Bay Area was rattled early this morning by a magnitude 4.3 earthquake along the Hayward fault line&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Startup uses AI to fight art forgeries—with hyper-realistic copies</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/ai-trained-robot-art-forgeries/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Art knockoffs generate between $4 and $6 billion annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/ai-trained-robot-art-forgeries/"&gt;Startup uses AI to fight art forgeries—with hyper-realistic copies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>A deeper understanding of endometriosis is suggesting new treatments</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496240-a-deeper-understanding-of-endometriosis-is-suggesting-new-treatments/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The revelation that&amp;nbsp;endometriosis is linked to autoimmune disorders is opening up a whole new way to treat this painful and poorly understood condition</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:00:29 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>First-ever footage of leopard shark sex shows an unexpected trio</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/leopard-shark-mating-video/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“The males lost all their energy and lay immobile on the bottom while the female swam away actively.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/leopard-shark-mating-video/"&gt;First-ever footage of leopard shark sex shows an unexpected trio&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 12:16:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Venus has lava tubes, and they're weird</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497220-venus-has-lava-tubes-and-theyre-weird/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>It has been suggested that lava tubes - underground tunnels carved out by molten rock - might be on Venus, and now we have direct evidence that this is the case</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:36:36 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>AI use by UK justice system risks papering over the cracks caused by years of underfunding</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-use-by-uk-justice-system-risks-papering-over-the-cracks-caused-by-years-of-underfunding-264749</link><description>The justice system is suffering from underfunding and AI won’t solve all the problems.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:16:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Does Tylenol Use during Pregnancy Cause Autism? What the Research Shows</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/does-tylenol-use-during-pregnancy-cause-autism-what-the-research-shows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President Trump and Robert F. Kennedy, Jr., have tied Tylenol use during pregnancy and folate deficiencies to rising autism rates&amp;mdash;but the evidence is thin&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI and credit: How can we keep machines from reproducing social biases?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-and-credit-how-can-we-keep-machines-from-reproducing-social-biases-257756</link><description>Can we move from algorithmic discrimination to inclusive finance?</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out some of the most popular Keurig coffee machines during this early Prime Day deal</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/keurig-coffee-machine-amazon-early-prime-day-deal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you're going to buy a Keurig, this pre-Prime Day sale is a great time to do it. You can even get an ice coffee maker for the lowest price of the year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/keurig-coffee-machine-amazon-early-prime-day-deal/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out some of the most popular Keurig coffee machines during this early Prime Day deal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 16:02:52 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Dangerous climate change threatens Northern Australia’s big ‘food bowl’ dreams</title><link>https://theconversation.com/dangerous-climate-change-threatens-northern-australias-big-food-bowl-dreams-265727</link><description>Big plans are afoot to turn Northern Australia into Asia’s “food bowl”. But the reality of climate change can’t be ignored.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 20:19:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Announcing the #SciAmInTheWild Photography Contest Short List</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/announcing-the-sciaminthewild-photography-contest-short-list/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To celebrate &lt;i&gt;Scientific American&lt;/i&gt;&amp;rsquo;s 180th anniversary, we invited readers to place our magazine covers in the wild. See our staff&amp;rsquo;s favorite submissions&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tylenol Is Popular and Safe, Yet Nobody Knows How It Works</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/tylenol-is-popular-and-safe-yet-nobody-knows-how-it-works/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The common pain reliever is safe when used as directed, research shows. But scientists remain puzzled by one aspect: how it reduces pain and fever&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 22:40:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Close relatives of emperor penguins lived in NZ some 3 million years ago. What caused their extinction?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/close-relatives-of-emperor-penguins-lived-in-nz-some-3-million-years-ago-what-caused-their-extinction-265585</link><description>Great penguins once lived in much warmer waters, but then retreated to the Southern Ocean. In a warming world, they might be able to shift their range again.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 23:27:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fish ‘fingerprints’ in the ocean reveal which species are moving homes due to climate change</title><link>https://theconversation.com/fish-fingerprints-in-the-ocean-reveal-which-species-are-moving-homes-due-to-climate-change-264683</link><description>Tracking these shifts is crucial for understanding how climate change is transforming our oceans.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 23:47:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>সোভিয়েতরা কীভাবে হেমিংওয়েকে গুপ্তচর বানাল</title><link>https://www.tbsnews.net/bangla/Easel/news-details-392346</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:31:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>James Webb Space Telescope Finds Atmosphere on Lava Planet TOI-561 b</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/james-webb-space-telescope-finds-atmosphere-on-lava-planet-toi-561-b/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hot, small and old&amp;mdash;exoplanet TOI-561 b is just about the worst place to look for alien air. Scientists using JWST found it there anyway&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 11:25:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What happens when AI comes to the cotton fields</title><link>https://theconversation.com/what-happens-when-ai-comes-to-the-cotton-fields-261526</link><description>AI can help farmers be more effective and sustainable, but its use varies from state to state. A project in Georgia aims to bring the technology to the state’s cotton farmers.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 12:49:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air quality analysis reveals minimal changes after xAI data center opens in pollution-burdened Memphis neighborhood</title><link>https://theconversation.com/air-quality-analysis-reveals-minimal-changes-after-xai-data-center-opens-in-pollution-burdened-memphis-neighborhood-265152</link><description>Analysis of the air quality data available for southwest Memphis finds that pollution has long been quite bad, but the turbines powering an xAI data center have not made it much worse.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 12:50:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why your dog gets so excited to see you</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/why-dogs-get-so-excited-to-see-you/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Memory, scent, and strong bonds fuel the joyous reunions between dogs and their pet parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/why-dogs-get-so-excited-to-see-you/"&gt;Why your dog gets so excited to see you&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Final RSV Frontier Is within Reach</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-final-rsv-frontier-is-within-reach/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The journey toward an RSV vaccine for children has been wrought with tragedy and setbacks. But six decades after scientists embarked on that path, they are nearing the finish line&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Promise of RSV Prevention</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-promise-of-rsv-prevention/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;RSV is the leading cause of infant hospitalizations in the U.S. But that could soon change as research advances lead to new preventive drugs for everyone&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New RSV Preventives Dramatically Reduce Infant Illness and Death</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/new-rsv-preventatives-dramatically-reduce-infant-illness-and-death/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The year 2023 marked the debut of groundbreaking innovations to prevent severe RSV infections in infants. Now protected babies are way less likely to develop severe infections or to end up in the ICU&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Global Burden of RSV</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-global-burden-of-rsv/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) continues to affect infants and older and immunocompromised people around the world. These graphics reveal where the burden lies and what the effects of immunizations are&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Indigenous Storytelling Is Transforming RSV Care in Native Communities</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-indigenous-storytelling-is-transforming-rsv-care-in-native-communities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Abigail Echo-Hawk, a preeminent Native American public health expert, discusses RSV, &amp;ldquo;data genocide&amp;rdquo; and positive change driven by Indigenous storytelling&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Fight to End Childhood RSV in Indian Country</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-fight-to-end-childhood-rsv-in-indian-country/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;American Indian and Alaska Native infants experience the highest rates of RSV-related hospitalization in the U.S., but a breakthrough immunization is helping to close the gap&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Long Road to an RSV Antibody to Protect the Most Vulnerable</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/a-long-road-to-an-rsv-antibody-to-protect-the-most-vulnerable/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tragic RSV vaccine trials in the 1960s set the field back for decades. Here&amp;rsquo;s how scientists finally made breakthroughs in RSV immunization&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Home Depot has dozens of portable power stations and solar generators at clearance prices during this fall sale</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/home-depot-portable-power-station-solar-generator-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Save hundreds of dollars on powerful battery backups from Anker, Jackery, Bluetti, and more. Don't let power outages interrupt your streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/home-depot-portable-power-station-solar-generator-deals/"&gt;The Home Depot has dozens of portable power stations and solar generators at clearance prices during this fall sale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:26:32 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>2,000-pound megaraptor died while snacking on a crocodile</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/new-megaraptor-dinosaur-cretaceous/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;'Joaquinraptor casali' was one of the Cretaceous Era's last apex predators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/new-megaraptor-dinosaur-cretaceous/"&gt;2,000-pound megaraptor died while snacking on a crocodile&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hints of exotic dark matter particles could be hiding in LHC data</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497100-hints-of-exotic-dark-matter-particles-could-be-hiding-in-lhc-data/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Particles similar to axions, the leading candidate for dark matter that has long eluded detection, may have already been created in particle colliders – and remained hidden in the data</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:00:17 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The truth about narcissists: How to handle them, and can they change?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496324-the-truth-about-narcissists-how-to-handle-them-and-can-they-change/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Although narcissistic personality disorder is rarer than you might think, psychological research suggests it can come in two different types, one of which may be underdiagnosed</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:00:23 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Dinosaur found with a crocodile in its jaws named as new species</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497299-dinosaur-found-with-a-crocodile-in-its-jaws-named-as-new-species/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A fossil from about 66 million years ago reveals a species of dinosaur that is new to science, with claws that would have ripped through its prey's flesh</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:00:45 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Leopards may have feasted on our earliest ancestors</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/leopards-ate-early-humans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It took a while for humans to climb the food chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/leopards-ate-early-humans/"&gt;Leopards may have feasted on our earliest ancestors&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 12:11:51 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The US-UK tech prosperity deal carries promise but also peril for the general public</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-us-uk-tech-prosperity-deal-carries-promise-but-also-peril-for-the-general-public-265728</link><description>The deliberate alignment of AI systems with the values of corporations and individuals could sour the investment.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 16:17:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Moon Is Rusting—Thanks to ‘Wind’ Blown from Earth</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-moon-is-rusting-thanks-to-wind-blown-from-earth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lunar minerals can rust when bombarded with high-energy oxygen particles, experiments show&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UV light can fight indoor allergens</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/allergies-uv-light/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A 30-minute treatment can help reduce allergies from pet dander, dust, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/allergies-uv-light/"&gt;UV light can fight indoor allergens&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:38:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>A Censored Rap Legend Has Advice for Jimmy Kimmel</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/jimmy-kimmel-luther-campbell-fcc/684326/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Three decades ago, 2 Live Crew fought a First Amendment battle against the government—and won.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:58:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Mapping the structure of the brain doesn't fully explain its function</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497291-mapping-the-structure-of-the-brain-doesnt-fully-explain-its-function/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Comparing a map of the neurons in a nematode worm - the connectome - with a map of how signals travel across those neurons has revealed a surprising number of differences, suggesting that the structure of the brain alone doesn't explain how it works</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 19:00:37 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What we know, and don't, about the link between painkillers and autism</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497384-what-we-know-and-dont-about-the-link-between-painkillers-and-autism/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Scientific evidence is lacking to support the US government’s decisions to caution against using a common painkiller in pregnancy and fast-track the approval of an experimental medication for autism</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 21:30:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Trump Changed His Mind on Ukraine</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/trump-russia-ukraine-position-change/684344/?utm_source=feed</link><description>And why he still might change it again</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 18:05:53 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Spectacle, weirdness and novelty: what early cinema tells us about the appeal of ‘AI slop’</title><link>https://theconversation.com/spectacle-weirdness-and-novelty-what-early-cinema-tells-us-about-the-appeal-of-ai-slop-265071</link><description>Just as the gimmicky first films evolved into a sophisticated medium, will we look back on today’s AI-generated video as the beginnings of a new art form?</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 01:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>We Can Stop Teen Suicide</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/we-can-stop-teen-suicide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By understanding warning signs and talking to your child, parents can help reduce the risk of teen suicide&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bowers &amp; Wilkins Px8 S2 wireless headphones upgrade an already desirable update</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/bowers-wilkins-px8-s2-flagship-wireless-bluetooth-headphones-announcement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The British brand's new Bluetooth flagship further refines the platform introduced with the award-winning Px7 S3, making the Px8 S2 the choice for maximizing microdetails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/bowers-wilkins-px8-s2-flagship-wireless-bluetooth-headphones-announcement/"&gt;Bowers &amp;amp; Wilkins Px8 S2 wireless headphones upgrade an already desirable update&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 03:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Gaza Left and the Gender Left</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/uk-your-party-corbyn-sultana/684343/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Can groups with different values work together against Britain’s far right?</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Mary Roach’s New Book Replaceable You Explores Challenges in Replacing Body Parts</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/mary-roachs-new-book-replaceable-you-explores-challenges-in-replacing-body/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mary Roach unpacks the millennia-long effort to replace failing body parts&amp;mdash;and the reasons that modern medicine still struggles to match the original designs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquakes Release Energy Mostly Through Heat, Not Ground Shaking</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/earthquakes-release-energy-mostly-through-heat-not-ground-shaking/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Up to 98 percent of the energy of an earthquake goes into flash heating rocks, not shaking the ground, new research shows. The finding could help yield better earthquake forecasts&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Ganges River is drying faster than ever – here’s what it means for the region and the world</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-ganges-river-is-drying-faster-than-ever-heres-what-it-means-for-the-region-and-the-world-265891</link><description>Climate change and overuse are creating a crisis for south Asia’s most important river.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:10:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>So Much for Class-Based Affirmative Action</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/affirmative-action-race-class-trump/684347/?utm_source=feed</link><description>&lt;span&gt;The Trump administration considers even race-blind admissions policies illegal if they’re intended to achieve diversity. &lt;/span&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 08:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Why archaeologists are studying a skate park</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/archaeologists-skate-park-weirdest-thing-podcast/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Plus dire wolves' bad knees and other weird things we learned this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/archaeologists-skate-park-weirdest-thing-podcast/"&gt;Why archaeologists are studying a skate park &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Researchers develop a pimple patch that actually seems to work</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/researchers-develop-a-pimple-patch-that-actually-seems-to-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After seven days, the treated pimples completely disappeared &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/researchers-develop-a-pimple-patch-that-actually-seems-to-work/"&gt;Researchers develop a pimple patch that actually seems to work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 10:04:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Unconstitutional Tactics Trump Wants to Revive in Memphis</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/memphis-police-tactic/684325/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The president’s plans resemble the aggressive, showy, and ultimately failed crime-fighting strategy once used by the city’s police.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 11:03:17 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How researchers are making precision agriculture more affordable</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-researchers-are-making-precision-agriculture-more-affordable-265366</link><description>Researchers have developed a tool that allows farmers to quickly and affordably test soil samples, get results in real-time, and obtain fertilizer recommendations.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 15:55:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside the factory where MasterCraft builds watersports boats from the outside in</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/mastercraft-boat-construction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Based in Tennessee, the boatbuilder is making waves with its artisan process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/mastercraft-boat-construction/"&gt;Inside the factory where MasterCraft builds watersports boats from the outside in&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>World’s oldest person had a young microbiome and 'exceptional genome'</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497328-worlds-oldest-person-had-a-young-microbiome-and-exceptional-genome/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Scientists have studied the genetics and lifestyle factors that enabled María Branyas Morera, officially the oldest person in the world until she died last year, to reach 117 years old</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:00:05 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How faster-than-light explosions could reveal the universe’s secrets</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495828-how-faster-than-light-explosions-could-reveal-the-universes-secrets/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Some things we see in space appear to outpace light. Now we are learning to harness these bizarre optical illusions to understand the mysteries of neutron stars, gamma ray bursts and more</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:00:24 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Device with 6100 qubits is a step towards largest quantum computer yet</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497439-device-with-6100-qubits-is-a-step-towards-largest-quantum-computer-yet/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>An array of 6100 ultracold caesium atoms controlled by lasers is the largest collection of qubits ever assembled, and researchers hope they can soon turn it into the world's most advanced quantum computer</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:00:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>America’s Zombie Democracy</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/america-authoritarian-regime-ai-suicide/684350/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Its trappings remain, but authoritarianism and AI are hollowing out our humanity.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:33:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Why some memories stick while others fade</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/why-memories-stick/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;'Memory isn’t just a passive recording device.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/why-memories-stick/"&gt;Why some memories stick while others fade&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>We can avoid the agonising wait for advances in women's healthcare</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735623-000-we-can-avoid-the-agonising-wait-for-advances-in-womens-healthcare/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Simply listening to the experiences of women with conditions such as endometriosis will help to end the long-standing inequalities they face when it comes to medical progress</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Two climate scientists on how to use emotion in the climate crisis</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735620-400-two-climate-scientists-on-how-to-use-emotion-in-the-climate-crisis/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>From anger to hope, Kate Marvel and Tim Lenton explain how to tackle the tricky feelings aroused by climate change and harness them to take action</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Are you an introvert or extrovert? Surprisingly, the answer is neither</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735622-700-are-you-an-introvert-or-extrovert-surprisingly-the-answer-is-neither/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>We are quick to place ourselves on the extremes of the social spectrum, but the truth is that personality is more malleable than you think, says Claudia Canavan</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How Taylor Swift is helping botany gain celebrity status</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735622-900-how-taylor-swift-is-helping-botany-gain-celebrity-status/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Feedback is delighted to learn that researchers have discovered what Taylor Swift is accidentally doing to rescue the science of plants from mid-ness. Just take a look at her videos – sorry, botany teaching aids</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What made solar power the most desirable energy source on the planet?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735622-800-what-made-solar-power-the-most-desirable-energy-source-on-the-planet/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>In this latest instalment of Future Chronicles, an imagined history of future inventions, Rowan Hooper explains how the creation of living solar panels transformed their impact on the world</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A compelling book about the end of the Neanderthals is a rare treat</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735620-500-a-compelling-book-about-the-end-of-the-neanderthals-is-a-rare-treat/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Forget the tropes about how violence or maybe volcanic eruptions killed off our ancient cousins, The Last Neanderthal by Ludovic Slimak offers a very different take on how they died out</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazing images expose inner world of mind-blowing plants and fungi</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735620-300-amazing-images-expose-inner-world-of-mind-blowing-plants-and-fungi/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Surreal images from a new book, Microcosms, show how confocal microscopy that uses laser scanning creates a super-sharp new journey around mind-altering plants and fungi</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>If you feel you don't really belong, here is some science-based advice</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735621-000-if-you-feel-you-dont-really-belong-here-is-some-science-based-advice/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Thinking you don’t fit in is agonising, whether you are starting at university or changing jobs. Our advice columnist, David Robson, shares some tips to change how you feel</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>We finally found the hot wind coming out of our black hole</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497671-we-finally-found-the-hot-wind-coming-out-of-our-black-hole/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Since the 1970s, astronomers have predicted that Sagittarius A*, the supermassive black hole at the centre of the Milky Way, should be sending out hot wind – they have just caught the first glimpse of it</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 20:01:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Shark bite-resistant wetsuits could save lives</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/shark-bite-resistant-wetsuit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;While not all injuries can be prevented, these new materials offer a new tool for surfers and divers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/shark-bite-resistant-wetsuit/"&gt;Shark bite-resistant wetsuits could save lives&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 15:06:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>What Is Leucovorin, the Unproven Autism Drug Backed by Trump Officials?</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/what-is-leucovorin-the-unproven-autism-drug-backed-by-trump-officials/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration is backing leucovorin as a treatment for autism, despite limited evidence. Some doctors and researchers are concerned&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine’s Plan to Starve the Russian War Machine</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/ukraines-strategy-to-win-the-war/684356/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Negotiations have stalled. Trump keeps changing his policies. Ukrainians, backed by Europeans, are taking matters into their own hands. ​​​</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 15:25:32 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Goodbye petrostates, hello ‘electrostates’: how the clean energy shift is reshaping the world order</title><link>https://theconversation.com/goodbye-petrostates-hello-electrostates-how-the-clean-energy-shift-is-reshaping-the-world-order-264267</link><description>The global shift toward renewable energy is challenging old geopolitical power structures. So where does Australia stand?</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:31:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Huntington’s disease breakthrough: what to know about the gene therapy</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497677-huntingtons-disease-breakthrough-what-to-know-about-the-gene-therapy/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Huntington’s disease has been successfully treated for the first time using a gene therapy, which may be available in the US as soon as next year</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 22:07:17 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Save on last year’s Patagonia jackets, apparel, and accessories during REI’s seasonal clearance sale</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/rei-patagonia-deals-fall-sale-mens-womens/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Grab some classic Patagonia pieces including the iconic Synchilla fleece and its fantastic puffer jackets for up to 45 percent off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/rei-patagonia-deals-fall-sale-mens-womens/"&gt;Save on last year&amp;#8217;s Patagonia jackets, apparel, and accessories during REI&amp;#8217;s seasonal clearance sale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:07:47 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Nightmare Bacteria’ Infections Spiking, Leaving Key Carbapenem Antibiotics Useless, CDC Warns</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/nightmare-bacteria-infections-spiking-leaving-key-carbapenem-antibiotics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The infection rate of one type of carbapenem-resistant Enterobacterales bacteria has risen by more than 460 percent in recent years. Scientists say people receiving treatment in hospitals are at highest risk&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Could we have cracked one of the world's toughest climate problems?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497594-could-we-have-cracked-one-of-the-worlds-toughest-climate-problems/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>It is almost impossible to make cement without emissions, but carbon-capture-and-storage technology is finally being deployed to decarbonise the sector</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 01:01:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Digital brains’ that ‘think’ and ‘feel’: why do we personify AI models, and are these metaphors actually helpful?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/digital-brains-that-think-and-feel-why-do-we-personify-ai-models-and-are-these-metaphors-actually-helpful-265883</link><description>Metaphors help us understand complexity, but they can also be dangerous, or even misleading.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 08:49:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modeling the Deep</title><link>https://nautil.us/modeling-the-deep-1238087/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An ambitious mission seeks to map the flow of crucial chemicals through marine food webs in far-flung oceanic gyres&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/modeling-the-deep-1238087/"&gt;Modeling the Deep&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate change is making trees grow larger in the Amazon rainforest</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497707-climate-change-is-making-trees-grow-larger-in-the-amazon-rainforest/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Rising carbon dioxide levels have boosted the growth of trees in the Amazon rainforest over the past few decades, but it is unclear if this trend will continue</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 11:00:04 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Grattan on Friday: As the government rejects Trump’s stands, Liberal leadership aspirant Andrew Hastie sounds decidedly Trumpian</title><link>https://theconversation.com/grattan-on-friday-as-the-government-rejects-trumps-stands-liberal-leadership-aspirant-andrew-hastie-sounds-decidedly-trumpian-265860</link><description>The prime minister avoided any major pitfalls during his week in the US. Back at home, the Liberal party’s infighting has shown no signs of stopping.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:06:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bird Flu and Human Flu Viruses Could Mix in Cow Udders and Spark a Pandemic</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/bird-flu-and-human-flu-viruses-could-mix-in-cow-udders-and-spark-a-pandemic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Cells in cow udders could act as a site for human flu and bird flu viruses to swap genes and generate dangerous novel strains&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lower Than Cowards</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/freedom-trump-threats-kimmel/684358/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The surrender of America’s elites</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 07:31:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Good Conversations Don’t Require Everybody to Agree, Neuroscience Shows</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/good-conversations-dont-require-everybody-to-agree-neuroscience-shows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Brain imaging is illuminating the patterns linked to productive, positive dialogue&lt;b&gt;,&lt;/b&gt; and those insights could help people connect with others&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cheetahs naturally turned into mummies in caves in Saudi Arabia</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497320-cheetahs-naturally-turned-into-mummies-in-caves-in-saudi-arabia/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The constant temperature and low humidity of a cave network in Saudi Arabia turned cheetahs, some of which died thousands of years ago, into mummies</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:00:12 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Rivers are heating up faster than the air − that’s a problem for aquatic life and people</title><link>https://theconversation.com/rivers-are-heating-up-faster-than-the-air-thats-a-problem-for-aquatic-life-and-people-263718</link><description>River heat waves are rising faster than the pace of air heat waves. That’s a problem for fish, drinking water quality, and food and energy production.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:19:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks retreat from climate change commitments – but it’s business more than politics</title><link>https://theconversation.com/banks-retreat-from-climate-change-commitments-but-its-business-more-than-politics-265176</link><description>The Net-Zero Banking Alliance, intended to curb lending to carbon-intensive sectors, wasn’t effective and more importantly never made much business sense.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:20:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The science of defiance: A psychology researcher explains why people comply – and how to resist</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-science-of-defiance-a-psychology-researcher-explains-why-people-comply-and-how-to-resist-264567</link><description>You don’t need to be a rebel to defy. Defiance isn’t about personality, it’s a practice – one that’s becoming essential in workplaces, politics and everyday life.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:22:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4 films that show how humans can fortify – or botch – their relationship with AI</title><link>https://theconversation.com/4-films-that-show-how-humans-can-fortify-or-botch-their-relationship-with-ai-263603</link><description>From 1980s sci-fi films to today’s blockbusters, filmmakers have wrestled with questions about what happens when humans rely on intelligent machines.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:23:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Does vagus nerve stimulation work? A scientific cure-all explained.</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/what-is-vagus-nerve-stimulation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From treating seizures to depression, stimulating the body's longest nerve has real benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/what-is-vagus-nerve-stimulation/"&gt;Does vagus nerve stimulation work? A scientific cure-all explained.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>AI in Africa: 5 issues that must be tackled for digital equality</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-in-africa-5-issues-that-must-be-tackled-for-digital-equality-265611</link><description>Policy-makers must grapple with an uncomfortable truth: without deliberate action, AI will magnify global divides.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:36:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why September 27, 2025 is the ‘coolest mathematical date of our lifetime’</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/september-27-math-date/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Get ready for a whacky series of numerical coincidences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/september-27-math-date/"&gt;Why September 27, 2025 is the &amp;#8216;coolest mathematical date of our lifetime&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:06:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Nanoparticles may be the secret ingredient in making ultimate plastics</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497683-nanoparticles-may-be-the-secret-ingredient-in-making-ultimate-plastics/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Mixing nanoparticles into some common plastics made them harder to break and possibly easier to process, pointing towards a way to make better materials or packaging</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:41:37 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>3D-printed skin stretches, bleeds like the real thing</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/3d-printed-skin-bleeds/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capsules embedded between layers of this fake tissue simulate human blood and pus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/3d-printed-skin-bleeds/"&gt;3D-printed skin stretches, bleeds like the real thing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:47:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelensky says a destructive drone arms race looms – but dystopia isn’t inevitable</title><link>https://theconversation.com/zelensky-says-a-destructive-drone-arms-race-looms-but-dystopia-isnt-inevitable-263644</link><description>The new age of drones and AI may be terrifying, but there are reasons for thinking the dystopian possibilities of future war will be contained.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:24:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>If I Work Harder, Will You Love Me?</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/workaholic-love-practical-solutions/684353/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The tragedy of workaholism is the false belief that you can trade toil for affection. Knowing that is the first step to recovery.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Cat owners donate more money than dog owners</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/cat-owners-donate-more-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An analysis of nearly $70 billion in donations showed feline lovers contributed slightly more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/cat-owners-donate-more-money/"&gt;Cat owners donate more money than dog owners&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:27:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Punch Cards, Pipeline Problems, and the Future of Women in Computing</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/punch-cards-pipeline-problems-and-the-future-of-women-in-computing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Carla Brodley, founding executive director of the Center for Inclusive Computing at Northeastern University, explains how to make computer science education more accessible to everyone&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alaska’s Fat Bear Week is more than a bit of fun – for the animals, size is a matter of survival</title><link>https://theconversation.com/alaskas-fat-bear-week-is-more-than-a-bit-of-fun-for-the-animals-size-is-a-matter-of-survival-266099</link><description>Bears need to put on fat in order to survive the harsh Alaskan winters.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:31:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vanishing waters in a warming world</title><link>https://theconversation.com/vanishing-waters-in-a-warming-world-266001</link><description>Bad news for the rivers and the lakes that we’re used to.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:31:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Walmart’s gaming PC clearance sale drops prices on laptops, desktops, graphics cards, and more</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/walmart-desktop-laptop-pc-gaming-deals-sale/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Whatever you need to upgrade your PC gaming experience, Walmart has it on sale right now. That includes laptops, desktops, graphics cards, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/walmart-desktop-laptop-pc-gaming-deals-sale/"&gt;Walmart&amp;#8217;s gaming PC clearance sale drops prices on laptops, desktops, graphics cards, and more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:50:42 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Taylor Swift’s Speech Pattern Changed over Time, Linguistics Study Shows</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/taylor-swift-speech-pattern-changed-over-time-linguistics-study-shows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An analysis of Taylor Swift&amp;rsquo;s interviews suggests her speech pattern has changed over her career&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Republicans Can Do If They Really Want to Protect Free Speech</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/republicans-free-speech-fcc/684359/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The best way to defend Americans’ expressive rights is to pass laws.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 14:05:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>12 astonishing images from the 2025 Astrophotography Prize Photographer of the Year</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/2025-astrophotography-prize-photographer-of-the-year-images/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A ‘tornado in space’ and the ISS shine in these inspiring examples of the best in astrophotography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/2025-astrophotography-prize-photographer-of-the-year-images/"&gt;12 astonishing images from the 2025 Astrophotography Prize Photographer of the Year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>WWI-Era Shipwrecks in Mallows Bay Form Ecological Sanctuary</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/wwi-era-shipwrecks-in-mallows-bay-form-ecological-sanctuary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly 100 years ago dozens of ships were abandoned in a shallow bay in the Potomac River. Today plants and animals are thriving on the skeletons of these vessels&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reconstructed skull gives surprising clues to our enigmatic Ancestor X</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497765-reconstructed-skull-gives-surprising-clues-to-our-enigmatic-ancestor-x/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The shared ancestor of our species, the Neanderthals and the Denisovans may be far older than we thought – which could completely change our understanding of humanity's evolution</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 20:00:46 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Apple AirPods Pro 3 earbuds first impressions: The rightful Air to the throne</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/apple-airpods-pro-3-true-wireless-anc-earbuds-first-impressions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Upgraded housings, drivers, eartips, and algorithms mean the Apple AirPods Pro 3 earbuds dig deeper and hold the stage better, improving noise isolation and sonic sensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/apple-airpods-pro-3-true-wireless-anc-earbuds-first-impressions/"&gt;Apple AirPods Pro 3 earbuds first impressions: The rightful Air to the throne&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:15:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>AI systems can easily lie and deceive us – a fact researchers are painfully aware of</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-systems-can-easily-lie-and-deceive-us-a-fact-researchers-are-painfully-aware-of-263531</link><description>In stress-testing AI models, it’s not hard to push them to the brink and make them threaten to harm humans.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:40:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Warn, hide or stand out? How colour in the animal world is a battle for survival</title><link>https://theconversation.com/warn-hide-or-stand-out-how-colour-in-the-animal-world-is-a-battle-for-survival-265670</link><description>A global experiment has helped explain why some animals use stealthy patterns to hide from predators, while others use warning colours to avoid being eaten.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>11 dolphins stranded in Cape Cod rescued by nonprofit</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/stranded-dolphins-rescued/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;‘These strandings happen fast, and every minute counts.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/stranded-dolphins-rescued/"&gt;11 dolphins stranded in Cape Cod rescued by nonprofit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:02:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Comey Indictment Is Not Just Payback</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/comey-indictment/684377/?utm_source=feed</link><description>It’s a glimpse of Trump’s next attempt to seize power.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 21:35:45 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How AI Is Helping Archaeologists Make Discoveries</title><link>https://nautil.us/how-ai-is-helping-archaeologists-make-discoveries-1238095/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New clues about ancient civilizations are being unearthed from the data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/how-ai-is-helping-archaeologists-make-discoveries-1238095/"&gt;How AI Is Helping Archaeologists Make Discoveries&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Neuroscience and Art Collide in a Posthumous ‘Composition’ by Alvin Lucier in Revivification</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/neuroscience-and-art-collide-in-a-posthumous-composition-by-alvin-lucier-in/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A museum exhibit in Australia lets visitors hear music generated by brain cells derived from the blood of a dead composer.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asteroid ‘Families’ Reveal Solar System’s Secret History</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/asteroid-families-reveal-solar-systems-secret-history/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Many asteroids are related, but their family trees can be hard to trace&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Smallmouth Bass Evolve to Evade Electric Culling in Adirondack Lake</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/smallmouth-bass-evolve-to-evade-electric-culling-in-adirondack-lake/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists electrically culled invasive fish in a 20-year battle&amp;mdash;but the fish fought back with rapid evolution&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How fast you age may be controlled by a DNA repair boss in your cells</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497492-how-fast-you-age-may-be-controlled-by-a-dna-repair-boss-in-your-cells/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>When a key protein regulator dials down DNA repair mechanisms, our cells accumulate more mutations, which may cause us to age faster</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 12:00:17 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Atmospheric chaos has sent temperatures soaring in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497898-atmospheric-chaos-has-sent-temperatures-soaring-in-antarctica/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Stratospheric temperatures in Antarctica are spiking, which could see strange weather unfold across the southern hemisphere in the coming months</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 13:00:56 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk and the making of an AI-generated martyr</title><link>https://theconversation.com/charlie-kirk-and-the-making-of-an-ai-generated-martyr-265834</link><description>In a polarized environment, the elevation of a figure into a saint does more than honor the individual. It turns a political struggle into a sacred one.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 12:31:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Want knives? How to buy what people leave at airport security.</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/what-happens-to-tsa-confiscated-items/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to a very weird corner of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/what-happens-to-tsa-confiscated-items/"&gt;Want knives? How to buy what people leave at airport security.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Babies' brains 'tick' more slowly than ours, which may help them learn</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497755-babies-brains-tick-more-slowly-than-ours-which-may-help-them-learn/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The rhythm of an infant's brain activity seems to put them in constant learning mode, whereas that of an adult may allow them to retrieve conceptual knowledge</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Amateur paleontologist opens fossil museum in rural Minnesota</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/amateur-paleontologist-opens-fossil-museum-in-rural-minnesota/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jim Pollard is bringing bison bones, fossilized mammoth poop, and more to Blue Earth's 3,000 residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/amateur-paleontologist-opens-fossil-museum-in-rural-minnesota/"&gt;Amateur paleontologist opens fossil museum in rural Minnesota&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Did a star blow up and hit Earth 10 million years ago?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497946-did-a-star-blow-up-and-hit-earth-10-million-years-ago/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>There are signs deep beneath the Pacific Ocean that an exploding star once sent cosmic rays blasting out towards Earth, and now we have an idea of which stars may be to blame</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:09:42 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out Coway air purifiers for every room during this early Prime Day deal</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/coway-air-purifier-early-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon has Coway air purifiers for every home and budget on sale for their lowest prices of the year before the Prime Big Deal Days even get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/coway-air-purifier-early-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out Coway air purifiers for every room during this early Prime Day deal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:06:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Butterfly Wings Inspire Barrier-Breaking Nanotech</title><link>https://nautil.us/butterfly-wings-inspire-barrier-breaking-nanotech-1239257/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mimicking the charismatic insect’s trick for flashing iridescent blue allows devices to grow ever smaller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/butterfly-wings-inspire-barrier-breaking-nanotech-1239257/"&gt;Butterfly Wings Inspire Barrier-Breaking Nanotech&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:17:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Comey Indictment Is an Embarrassment</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/comey-indictment-trump-doj/684381/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The Justice Department should never have brought such a shoddy case.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:26:17 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Attack squirrel’ sends two people to the ER</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/attack-squirrel-california/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A friendly reminder to not feed wildlife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/attack-squirrel-california/"&gt;&amp;#8216;Attack squirrel&amp;#8217; sends two people to the ER&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:32:57 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Earth’s Largest Mirror Shattered by Science</title><link>https://nautil.us/earths-largest-mirror-shattered-by-science-1239349/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Bolivian salt flat long touted as a massive looking glass loses some of its shine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/earths-largest-mirror-shattered-by-science-1239349/"&gt;Earth’s Largest Mirror Shattered by Science&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:39:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How water fuels conflict in Pakistan</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-water-fuels-conflict-in-pakistan-262628</link><description>The potential of water to cause conflict is a live issue in Pakistan, with climate change only making matters worse.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:08:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novels with a certain structure are more likely to be classics</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497589-novels-with-a-certain-structure-are-more-likely-to-be-classics/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Novels need a gripping story to stay popular as the decades pass, but it seems that other less-obvious factors may also contribute to their lasting success</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 18:00:52 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Redesigned umbrella is smaller than an iPhone</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/small-umbrella-simprella/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The 'Simprella' weighs less than a few Snickers’ bars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/small-umbrella-simprella/"&gt;Redesigned umbrella is smaller than an iPhone&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 13:41:48 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>This ‘funny-looking rock’ holds 3,000 years of Iron Age secrets</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/iron-age-copper-breakthrough/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Experimenting with copper may have led to our eventual breakthroughs with making iron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/iron-age-copper-breakthrough/"&gt;This ‘funny-looking rock’ holds 3,000 years of Iron Age secrets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Lung inflammation may make traumatic events harder to forget</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497888-lung-inflammation-may-make-traumatic-events-harder-to-forget/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Severe lung inflammation has been linked to symptoms resembling post-traumatic stress disorder in mice, which could help us better treat and prevent the mental health condition</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 19:00:07 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The Emptiness of Attacking Critics for Their Hypocrisy</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/free-speech-cancel-culture-republicans/684382/?utm_source=feed</link><description>It’s hard to defend crackdowns on free speech. It’s easier to simply claim everyone’s doing it.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:17:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NIH Funds New Autism Studies on Genes and Environment as Trump Focuses on Tylenol</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/nih-funds-new-autism-studies-on-genes-and-environment-as-trump-focuses-on/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The National Institutes of Health is investing $50 million into research on genetic and environmental factors underlying autism&amp;mdash;news that was eclipsed by President Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s recent controversial claims about acetaminophen&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The tug-of-war between engineering and design to build the Hyundai Palisade XRT Pro</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/engineering-and-design-hyundai-palisade-xrt-pro/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The brand toughened up its popular family SUV, but first, the design and engineering team had to agree on the dimensions and recovery hook placement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/engineering-and-design-hyundai-palisade-xrt-pro/"&gt;The tug-of-war between engineering and design to build the Hyundai Palisade XRT Pro&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hurricane Humberto and Potential Tropical Storm Imelda Complicate Forecasts</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/hurricane-humberto-and-potential-tropical-storm-imelda-complicate-forecasts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hurricane Humberto and a system that may become Tropical Storm Imelda in the coming days are swirling quite close to each other in the western Atlantic Ocean&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 21:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Pediatrician’s Lament</title><link>https://nautil.us/a-pediatricians-lament-1239480/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How the blustery rhetoric of Trump and Kennedy makes life harder for local physicians&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/a-pediatricians-lament-1239480/"&gt;A Pediatrician’s Lament&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 23:00:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>I tried a sound bath to see if it actually made me calmer</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/do-sound-baths-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The science is still emerging, but I couldn’t deny how relaxed I felt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/do-sound-baths-work/"&gt;I tried a sound bath to see if it actually made me calmer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The best powered bookshelf speakers for 2025, tested and reviewed</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/best-powered-bookshelf-speakers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Spin records, stream playlists, or score your next session—these all-in-one systems keep up wherever you set up, from your desktop to a bookshelf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/best-powered-bookshelf-speakers/"&gt;The best powered bookshelf speakers for 2025, tested and reviewed&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Nexstar and Sinclair Lost Their Game of Chicken</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/kimmel-response-local-tv-stations-abc-conflict/684388/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Broadcast-media companies may be growing, but they still couldn’t afford to reject Jimmy Kimmel forever.</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Lab-Grown Organoids Could Transform Female Reproductive Medicine</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/lab-grown-organoids-could-transform-female-reproductive-medicine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial tissues that mimic the placenta, endometrium, ovary and vagina could point to treatments for common conditions such as preeclampsia and endometriosis&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flying in an open-air, single-seat helicopter is a true test of nerves</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/mirocopter-flight-video/</link><description>&lt;p&gt; YouTuber Mark Rumsey documents his adventures in an extremely barebones Mirocopter SCH-2A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/mirocopter-flight-video/"&gt;Flying in an open-air, single-seat helicopter is a true test of nerves&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>6 fun photos to celebrate Sea Otter Awareness week</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/6-photos-sea-otter-awareness-week/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The furry mammals keep kelp forests going. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/6-photos-sea-otter-awareness-week/"&gt;6 fun photos to celebrate Sea Otter Awareness week&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Two-in-one inhalers slash asthma attacks among young children</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497635-two-in-one-inhalers-slash-asthma-attacks-among-young-children/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Inhalers that combine relieving breathlessness with preventing it seem to be the most effective option for reducing asthma attacks in young children</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 07:00:54 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>People Are More Likely to Cheat When They Use AI</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/people-are-more-likely-to-cheat-when-they-use-ai/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Participants in a new study were more likely to cheat when delegating to AI&amp;mdash;especially if they could encourage machines to break rules without explicitly asking for it&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Politicized Prosecutions May Hit a Roadblock</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/nullify-political-prosecution/684378/?utm_source=feed</link><description>When the president puts his political enemies on trial on pretextual grounds, jurors have the option of refusing to convict.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 07:31:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How to take every kind of photo on your iPhone</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/how-to-take-every-kind-of-photo-on-your-iphone/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple's phones are more versatile than you might have thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/how-to-take-every-kind-of-photo-on-your-iphone/"&gt;How to take every kind of photo on your iPhone&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>This humanoid robot can cartwheel surprisingly well</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/humanoid-robot-cartwheel/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Fourier’s N1 is an open-source bot designed to boost collaboration between universities, labs, and hobbyists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/humanoid-robot-cartwheel/"&gt;This humanoid robot can cartwheel surprisingly well&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Taking Tylenol While Pregnant Is Safer Than Untreated Fevers, Doctors Say</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/taking-tylenol-while-pregnant-is-safer-than-untreated-fevers-doctors-say/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Untreated fevers during pregnancy can cause more harm than taking acetaminophen will&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Generative AI might end up being worthless — and that could be a good thing</title><link>https://theconversation.com/generative-ai-might-end-up-being-worthless-and-that-could-be-a-good-thing-266046</link><description>GenAI does some neat, helpful things, but it’s not yet the engine of a new economy — and it might not ever be.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 17:03:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>মার্কিন অভিজাত সমাজের আড়ালে লুকিয়ে থাকা রোয়াল্ড ডালের গুপ্তচর জীবন</title><link>https://www.tbsnews.net/bangla/Easel/news-details-393161</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 17:48:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>You should wash your clothes with cold water</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/wash-your-clothes-with-cold-water/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Modern laundry detergents work better in cold water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/wash-your-clothes-with-cold-water/"&gt;You should wash your clothes with cold water&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>More people are using AI in court, not a lawyer. It could cost you money – and your case</title><link>https://theconversation.com/more-people-are-using-ai-in-court-not-a-lawyer-it-could-cost-you-money-and-your-case-264340</link><description>Researchers found more than 80 cases of generative AI use in Australian courts so far – mostly by people representing themselves. That comes with serious risks.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 19:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Transport will make or break Australia’s new climate plan – and time is running out to fix it</title><link>https://theconversation.com/transport-will-make-or-break-australias-new-climate-plan-and-time-is-running-out-to-fix-it-265986</link><description>Unless transport emissions are tackled head-on, Australia’s new climate target cannot be met.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 19:02:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Extreme Animals in Our Backyards</title><link>https://nautil.us/earths-most-impressive-athletes-are-obese-1239450/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Alex Riley’s three greatest revelations while writing &lt;i&gt;Super Natural&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/earths-most-impressive-athletes-are-obese-1239450/"&gt;The Extreme Animals in Our Backyards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Illiberal America, MAGA Edition</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/maga-cancel-culture-revenge-tactics/684296/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Republicans had real grievances with progressive orthodoxy—and are using them to justify drastic reprisals.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Endangered Sharks Caught in Rare Mating Ritual beneath the Waves</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/endangered-sharks-caught-in-rare-mating-ritual-beneath-the-waves/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Food and Drug Administration plans to update the safety label for acetaminophen products, and the strongest storm on Earth this year struck several countries in East and Southeast Asia.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Extraordinary pictures show what a common antibiotic does to E. coli</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498016-extraordinary-pictures-show-what-a-common-antibiotic-does-to-e-coli/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A commonly used class of antibiotics seems to kill bacteria like E. coli by breaking down their tough armour</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:33:29 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Weaver Ants Form Complex Chains to Pull More Than 100 Times Their Weight</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/weaver-ants-form-complex-chains-to-pull-more-than-100-times-their-weight/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When more humans are added to a team, each member accomplishes less work&amp;mdash;but teams of weaver ants do better and better as more join&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When the wheels come off: Lessons from Sonoma on racing, resilience, and engine oil</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/valvoline-restore-and-protect-nascar-f1-ev-data-center-performance-fluids/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I went to Sonoma for a NASCAR race and found out heat is the bad guy, fluids are the secret weapon, and Valvoline’s engineers are basically mad scientists with pit passes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/valvoline-restore-and-protect-nascar-f1-ev-data-center-performance-fluids/"&gt;When the wheels come off: Lessons from Sonoma on racing, resilience, and engine oil&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 07:55:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Ultracold clocks could reveal how quantum physics alters time</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497886-ultracold-clocks-could-reveal-how-quantum-physics-alters-time/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The world’s best clocks may be sensitive to an odd mix of quantum and relativistic effects that would stretch time and test the boundaries of physics</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:00:34 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Will AI make cheaper personalized insurance premiums possible? Here’s why it’s a slippery slope</title><link>https://theconversation.com/will-ai-make-cheaper-personalized-insurance-premiums-possible-heres-why-its-a-slippery-slope-262787</link><description>In this age of algorithms, personalized insurance is encountering legal limits, especially the ban on discrimination. Can we balance accurate pricing, solidarity, and fairness?</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:20:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EcoFlow DELTA 3 portable power station series first impressions: More power, more versatile</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/ecoflow-delta-3-max-plus-ultra-plus-portable-power-station-first-impressions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The EcoFlow Delta 3 Ultra Plus and Delta 3 Max Plus deliver plenty of power for camping and home backup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/ecoflow-delta-3-max-plus-ultra-plus-portable-power-station-first-impressions/"&gt;EcoFlow DELTA 3 portable power station series first impressions: More power, more versatile&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 08:55:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The radioactive ‘miracle water’ that killed its believers</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/radioactive-water/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the 1920s, Radithor promised to cure everything from wrinkles to leukemia, but its unintended results were deadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/radioactive-water/"&gt;The radioactive &amp;#8216;miracle water&amp;#8217; that killed its believers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Wild chimps consume the equivalent of two glasses of wine a day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/chimps-alcohol-study/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The 'drunken monkey hypothesis' could explain why humans like alcohol so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/chimps-alcohol-study/"&gt;Wild chimps consume the equivalent of two glasses of wine a day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 09:45:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The most important mathematician you’ve (probably) never heard of</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497097-the-most-important-mathematician-youve-probably-never-heard-of/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Alexander Grothendieck was a titan in his field, making deep connections that fuelled a revolution in mathematics, before giving it all up and disappearing. Jacob Aron explores what his work meant</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:24:37 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Sunken WWII bombs make a surprising home for sea life</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/wwii-bombs-sea-life-baltic-sea/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new study finds algae, mussels, and starfish flock to munitions dumped in the Baltic Sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/wwii-bombs-sea-life-baltic-sea/"&gt;Sunken WWII bombs make a surprising home for sea life&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Grandfather builds the droids he was always looking for</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/kurt-zimmerman-star-wars-droids/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Kurt Zimmerman brought Star Wars from a galaxy far, far away to … Michigan.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/kurt-zimmerman-star-wars-droids/"&gt;Grandfather builds the droids he was always looking for&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:15:47 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Fully MAGA-fied Christianity</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/charlie-kirk-christian-trump/684394/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Politics, especially culture-war politics, now provides many fundamentalists and evangelicals with a sense of community and a common enemy.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:16:31 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Cannabis extract found to be effective for lower back pain</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498064-cannabis-extract-found-to-be-effective-for-lower-back-pain/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A clinical trial has found that VER-01, a drug derived from cannabis, eases chronic lower back pain without serious side effects or signs of addiction</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:00:16 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Do black holes exist and, if not, what have we really been looking at?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496031-do-black-holes-exist-and-if-not-what-have-we-really-been-looking-at/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Black holes are so strange that physicists have long wondered if they are quite what they seem. Now we are set to find out if they are instead gravastars, fuzzballs or something else entirely</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:00:19 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Our brain 'swivels' to focus on sounds from different directions</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498050-our-brain-swivels-to-focus-on-sounds-from-different-directions/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Many mammals physically pivot their ears to hone in on a particular sound, and now it seems that a similar action takes place in our brain</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:00:32 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A second runway at Gatwick airport could improve efficiency and bring down fares – an economist’s view</title><link>https://theconversation.com/a-second-runway-at-gatwick-airport-could-improve-efficiency-and-bring-down-fares-an-economists-view-265995</link><description>Planes circling over busy airports waiting for a landing slot waste fuel and drive up costs.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:18:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New broccoli hybrid can thrive in colder climates</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/new-broccoli/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;90 percent of broccoli in the US is grown in California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/new-broccoli/"&gt;New broccoli hybrid can thrive in colder climates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:35:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How Hurricane Humberto Is Pulling Tropical Storm Imelda Away from the U.S.</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-hurricane-humberto-is-pulling-tropical-storm-imelda-away-from-the-u-s/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a version of the Fujiwhara effect, Hurricane Humberto is pulling Tropical Storm Imelda eastward and away from the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>নারকেল: মানবসভ্যতার প্রাচীন সঙ্গী</title><link>https://www.tbsnews.net/bangla/Easel/news-details-395191</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:13:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World’s first mushroom-powered toilet could replace stinky porta-potties</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/first-mushroom-powered-toilet/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Fungi flush out the odor in this pilot program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/first-mushroom-powered-toilet/"&gt;World&amp;#8217;s first mushroom-powered toilet could replace stinky porta-potties&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Ghostly Swamp Lightning Explained</title><link>https://nautil.us/ghostly-swamp-lightning-explained-1239396/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The tiny sparks behind spooky myths might have also started life on Earth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/ghostly-swamp-lightning-explained-1239396/"&gt;Ghostly Swamp Lightning Explained&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Marsh Will-o’-the-Wisps Sparked by Strange Chemistry</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/marsh-will-o-the-wisps-sparked-by-strange-chemistry/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A phenomenon called microlightning may explain ghostly blue marsh lights&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out Samsonite luggage, backapacks, and accessories for ridiculously low prices before Prime Day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/samsonite-suitcase-backpack-deals-amazon/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Grab some high-end luggage that will last for years with these absurdly cheap deals on Samsonite bags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/samsonite-suitcase-backpack-deals-amazon/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out Samsonite luggage, backapacks, and accessories for ridiculously low prices before Prime Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:15:22 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>We may finally know what causes will-o’-the-wisps</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498087-we-may-finally-know-what-causes-will-o-the-wisps/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Mysterious flashes of light seen in swamps and bogs could be caused by burning methane or other gases, ignited by sparks that fly between bubbles in water</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 21:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>15 gorgeous images from the 2025 Bird Photographer of the Year awards</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/2025-bird-photographer-of-the-year-awards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A soaring solar eclipse, a bloodied petrel, and a resilient raven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/2025-bird-photographer-of-the-year-awards/"&gt;15 gorgeous images from the 2025 Bird Photographer of the Year awards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 19:01:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>AI in the classroom is hard to detect – time to bring back oral tests</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-in-the-classroom-is-hard-to-detect-time-to-bring-back-oral-tests-265955</link><description>A chatbot can produce text, but it can’t sustain a probing conversation about your reasoning. Our work suggests oral assessment has a role in the age of AI.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Future Cost of Low Employee Engagement</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/a-hidden-force/202509/the-future-cost-of-low-employee-engagement</link><description>A hesitant workforce can mask discontent, and unless leaders strengthen engagement and collaboration alongside AI, the future price will be steep.&lt;br /&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 21:02:31 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Remaking the Culture of American Politics</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/culture-matters/202509/remaking-the-culture-of-american-politics</link><description>The Culture Cycle shows how people can make, unmake, and remake culture with a shared blueprint and use key social and psychological levers for change.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 21:43:43 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Paradox of Vaccines</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-other-side-of-the-white-coat/202509/the-paradox-of-vaccines</link><description>Vaccines changed the world—but their success may be the very reason some now doubt them. Here’s why vaccine hesitancy is rising, and what we risk if we forget the past.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 21:50:09 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Stop Chasing Things That Make You Miserable</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/from-striving-to-thriving/202509/how-to-stop-chasing-things-that-make-you-miserable</link><description>Learn why chasing approval and success leaves you empty, and how nonattachment can free you to enjoy life with more presence, balance, and genuine satisfaction.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 22:03:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Embracing Uncertainty</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/psychological-science-bites/202509/embracing-uncertainty</link><description>As much as we love knowing, we have great difficulty tolerating uncertainty. What if we gave ourselves permission to explore that space too?</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 22:12:28 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Choose Your Hard</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/from-both-sides-of-the-couch/202509/choose-your-hard</link><description>Choosing your hard is linked to making a decision to pursue the difficult path with intentionality.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 22:35:49 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>It’s Me, Not the Method: When Sleep Advice Breaks New Mothers</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-sleep-training-trap/202509/its-me-not-the-method-when-sleep-advice-breaks-new-mothers</link><description>What if the parenting method isn’t failing—you’re just being too hard on yourself? Self-blame fuels maternal shame. This is what healing can really look like.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 22:55:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Many Phases in the Mental Health Recovery Journey for Caregivers</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/serious-mental-illness-recovery/202509/the-many-phases-in-the-mental-health-recovery-journey</link><description>Caregivers should understand the phases of mental health recovery so they can recognize signs, strengthen bonds, and support their loved ones with empathy.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 23:12:37 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>7 Frequently Asked Questions About Tylenol and Autism</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/neuroscience-in-translation/202509/7-frequently-asked-questions-about-tylenol-and-autism</link><description>Confused by the recent statements and reports about autism and Tylenol, vaccines, or Leucovorin? Find answers to some of the most frequently asked questions here.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 23:41:23 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Venus fly traps’ death-grip trigger discovered</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/how-venus-fly-trap-close/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The carnivorous plants know when it's time to snatch their prey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/how-venus-fly-trap-close/"&gt;Venus fly traps’ death-grip trigger discovered&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Seeking Signs of Life on Venus</title><link>https://nautil.us/seeking-signs-of-life-on-venus-1238038/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The first private mission to the morning star will sample for traces of biological activity in the planet’s clouds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/seeking-signs-of-life-on-venus-1238038/"&gt;Seeking Signs of Life on Venus&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deep Sleep Is This Mammal’s Super Power</title><link>https://nautil.us/deep-sleep-is-this-mammals-super-power-1239714/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How a threatened Australian marsupial is thriving in the face of drought&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/deep-sleep-is-this-mammals-super-power-1239714/"&gt;Deep Sleep Is This Mammal’s Super Power&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Library for Fish Sounds</title><link>https://nautil.us/a-library-for-fish-sounds-1239697/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Can eavesdropping on the ocean help to save its creatures? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/a-library-for-fish-sounds-1239697/"&gt;A Library for Fish Sounds&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six New Gecko Species Discovered by Loud Barking Mating Calls</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/six-new-gecko-species-discovered-by-loud-barking-mating-calls/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists found new gecko species hidden in plain sight in pristine deserts of southern Africa, thanks to their loud, barking mating calls&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Myth of the Campus Snowflake</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/college-students-free-speech/684352/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The students I encounter as a university president aren’t afraid of free speech—quite the contrary.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Astronomers captured an incredible view of M87’s black hole jet</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498113-astronomers-captured-an-incredible-view-of-m87s-black-hole-jet/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The black hole at the centre of a galaxy more than 50 million light years away is spewing out a jet of extremely hot plasma – though we have studied it for a century, we are only now seeing it in great detail</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The Judaism I Thought I Knew</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/jewish-identity-anti-semitism/684397/?utm_source=feed</link><description>“I’m just a cultural Jew,” I would tell people, knowing nothing about Jewish culture.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>8 Bizarre (and Terrifying) Deep-Sea Creatures</title><link>https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/bizarre-deep-sea-creatures?utm_source=RSS</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class="ff-og-image-inserted" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_29,w_724,h_407/c_fill,w_1440,ar_1440:810,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/voltaxMediaLibrary/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k5f8twwkvzkw4kg9dm.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9n q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;In the 1950s, it was believed we &lt;a href="https://www.astronomy.com/wp/https:/do-we-know-more-about-the-moon-than-the-deep-sea-no/"&gt;knew more&lt;/a&gt; about the surface of the moon than the deep seas on Earth. Since then, humans have landed on the moon’s surface and have dived &lt;a href="https://www.discovermagazine.com/planet-earth/what-has-been-found-in-the-deep-waters-of-the-mariana-trench"&gt;nearly seven miles&lt;/a&gt; in a submersible to the ocean’s deepest point. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9o q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="mt-[18px] md:mt-0 mb-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-0"&gt;In the 1950s, it was believed we &lt;a href="https://www.astronomy.com/wp/https:/do-we-know-more-about-the-moon-than-the-deep-sea-no/"&gt;knew more&lt;/a&gt; about the surface of the moon than the deep seas on Earth. Since then, humans have landed on the moon’s surface and have dived &lt;a href="https://www.discovermagazine.com/planet-earth/what-has-been-found-in-the-deep-waters-of-the-mariana-trench"&gt;nearly seven miles&lt;/a&gt; in a submersible to the ocean’s deepest point. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9q q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Scientists continue to make discoveries about both extreme environments, but so far, only one has been found to support animal life—and those creatures will haunt your dreams. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9r q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-1"&gt;Scientists continue to make discoveries about both extreme environments, but so far, only one has been found to support animal life—and those creatures will haunt your dreams. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9t q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ERp_dYlVnuc--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9u q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9v q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9x q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;From a ginormous relative of the garden &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/50835/20-regional-names-woodlice"&gt;pillbug&lt;/a&gt; to fish with translucent heads, these organisms are adapted to the dark, cold, pressurized environment of the deep sea.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9y q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-3"&gt;From a ginormous relative of the garden &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/50835/20-regional-names-woodlice"&gt;pillbug&lt;/a&gt; to fish with translucent heads, these organisms are adapted to the dark, cold, pressurized environment of the deep sea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a0 q:key=vcaa:--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a1 q:key=StMp:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=Lf_2--&gt;&lt;ol class="toc text-primary mt-4 flex flex-col gap-y-2.5 ps-10 list-decimal [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/bizarre-deep-sea-creatures?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-5"&gt;Giant Larvacean (&lt;em&gt;Bathochordaeus stygius)&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/bizarre-deep-sea-creatures?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-9"&gt;Fangtooth (&lt;em&gt;Anoplogaster cornuta&lt;/em&gt;)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/bizarre-deep-sea-creatures?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-19"&gt;Giant Isopod (&lt;em&gt;Bathynomus giganteus&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/bizarre-deep-sea-creatures?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-24"&gt;Gulper Eel (&lt;em&gt;Saccopharynx lavenbergi)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/bizarre-deep-sea-creatures?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-29"&gt;Giant Tubeworms (&lt;em&gt;Riftia pachyptila&lt;/em&gt;)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/bizarre-deep-sea-creatures?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-33"&gt;Barrel amphipod (&lt;em&gt;Phronima sedentaria&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/bizarre-deep-sea-creatures?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-37"&gt;Bloodybelly Comb Jelly (&lt;em&gt;Lampocteis cruentiventer&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/bizarre-deep-sea-creatures?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-41"&gt;Barreleye Fish (&lt;em&gt;Macropinna microstoma&lt;/em&gt;)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a3 q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;Giant Larvacean (&lt;em&gt;Bathochordaeus stygius)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a4 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-5"&gt;Giant Larvacean (&lt;em&gt;Bathochordaeus stygius)&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a6 q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L1wFb_ShW7k--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a7 q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a8 q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aa q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;The giant larvacean (&lt;em&gt;Bathochordaeus stygius)&lt;/em&gt; is one of the strangest critters of the deep: It has a tadpole-shaped body only an inch or two long. You may be wondering why it’s called a &lt;em&gt;giant&lt;/em&gt; larvacean, and it comes down to its unique way of eating. This gelatinous &lt;a href="https://depts.washington.edu/fhlk12/links/StudentProjects/Tun.biology.html" target="_blank"&gt;tunicate&lt;/a&gt;—a type of marine invertebrate—envelops itself in a coating of mucus, also known as a “&lt;a href="https://annualreport.mbari.org/2020/story/reconstructing-an-animals-intricate-feeding-filter" target="_blank"&gt;snot palace&lt;/a&gt;,” that can measure more than three feet in diameter, and it uses this snot net to catch drifting food particles. The mucus can snag carbon-rich marine snow as well as &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5559207/" target="_blank"&gt;microplastics&lt;/a&gt;, and when it gets too clogged with inedible stuff, the giant larvacean discards it. The blob then falls to the ocean floor where other animals eat it, and a new mucus house is grown.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ab q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-7"&gt;The giant larvacean (&lt;em&gt;Bathochordaeus stygius)&lt;/em&gt; is one of the strangest critters of the deep: It has a tadpole-shaped body only an inch or two long. You may be wondering why it’s called a &lt;em&gt;giant&lt;/em&gt; larvacean, and it comes down to its unique way of eating. This gelatinous &lt;a href="https://depts.washington.edu/fhlk12/links/StudentProjects/Tun.biology.html" target="_blank"&gt;tunicate&lt;/a&gt;—a type of marine invertebrate—envelops itself in a coating of mucus, also known as a “&lt;a href="https://annualreport.mbari.org/2020/story/reconstructing-an-animals-intricate-feeding-filter" target="_blank"&gt;snot palace&lt;/a&gt;,” that can measure more than three feet in diameter, and it uses this snot net to catch drifting food particles. The mucus can snag carbon-rich marine snow as well as &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5559207/" target="_blank"&gt;microplastics&lt;/a&gt;, and when it gets too clogged with inedible stuff, the giant larvacean discards it. The blob then falls to the ocean floor where other animals eat it, and a new mucus house is grown.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ad q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;As revolting as this picture may be, you should thank a giant larvacean. They actually help fight climate change by collecting and sequestering a ton of carbon from the ocean in their mucus. According to &lt;a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.1602374" target="_blank"&gt;a 2017 study&lt;/a&gt; by scientists at the Monterey Bay Aquarium Research Institute, published in the journal &lt;em&gt;Science Advances&lt;/em&gt;, giant larvaceans can capture more carbon than any other filter-feeding zooplankton.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ae q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-8"&gt;As revolting as this picture may be, you should thank a giant larvacean. They actually help fight climate change by collecting and sequestering a ton of carbon from the ocean in their mucus. According to &lt;a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.1602374" target="_blank"&gt;a 2017 study&lt;/a&gt; by scientists at the Monterey Bay Aquarium Research Institute, published in the journal &lt;em&gt;Science Advances&lt;/em&gt;, giant larvaceans can capture more carbon than any other filter-feeding zooplankton.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ag q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;Fangtooth (&lt;em&gt;Anoplogaster cornuta&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ah q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-9"&gt;Fangtooth (&lt;em&gt;Anoplogaster cornuta&lt;/em&gt;)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aj q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zkBJ-IMtWh8--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ak q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=al q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=an q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;The common &lt;a href="https://twilightzone.whoi.edu/explore-the-otz/creature-features/fangtooth/" target="_blank"&gt;fangtooth&lt;/a&gt;, a tiny fish with a formidable bite, is found worldwide in tropical and temperate waters between 1600 and 6500 feet below the ocean’s surface. It’s also been spotted at a depth of 16,000 feet. That’s as deep as a stack of 52 Statues of Liberty, including the pedestals.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ao q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-11"&gt;The common &lt;a href="https://twilightzone.whoi.edu/explore-the-otz/creature-features/fangtooth/" target="_blank"&gt;fangtooth&lt;/a&gt;, a tiny fish with a formidable bite, is found worldwide in tropical and temperate waters between 1600 and 6500 feet below the ocean’s surface. It’s also been spotted at a depth of 16,000 feet. That’s as deep as a stack of 52 Statues of Liberty, including the pedestals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aq q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;But its signature feature is its mouthful of dental daggers. The fangtooth (&lt;em&gt;Anoplogaster cornuta&lt;/em&gt;) has the &lt;a href="https://www.si.edu/newsdesk/snapshot/anoplogaster-cornuta-fangtooth" target="_blank"&gt;largest teeth&lt;/a&gt; of any marine species relative to body size. They’re so big that the fish can’t even close its mouth properly. Instead, it has evolved two sockets on either side of its brain where the bottom teeth slide in when its jaws shut.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ar q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-12"&gt;But its signature feature is its mouthful of dental daggers. The fangtooth (&lt;em&gt;Anoplogaster cornuta&lt;/em&gt;) has the &lt;a href="https://www.si.edu/newsdesk/snapshot/anoplogaster-cornuta-fangtooth" target="_blank"&gt;largest teeth&lt;/a&gt; of any marine species relative to body size. They’re so big that the fish can’t even close its mouth properly. Instead, it has evolved two sockets on either side of its brain where the bottom teeth slide in when its jaws shut.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=at q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;So why does this little guy need such big teeth? Scientists think that they might be an adaptation to living in darkness in a food-scarce environment. The giant chompers allow the 6-inch fish to &lt;a href="http://www.digitalfishlibrary.org/featured/fangtooth/" target="_blank"&gt;grab on&lt;/a&gt; to anything unlucky enough to pass by, even prey much larger than itself. The same explanation may apply to deep-sea creatures like viperfish, dragonfish, and anglerfish.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=au q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-13"&gt;So why does this little guy need such big teeth? Scientists think that they might be an adaptation to living in darkness in a food-scarce environment. The giant chompers allow the 6-inch fish to &lt;a href="http://www.digitalfishlibrary.org/featured/fangtooth/" target="_blank"&gt;grab on&lt;/a&gt; to anything unlucky enough to pass by, even prey much larger than itself. The same explanation may apply to deep-sea creatures like viperfish, dragonfish, and anglerfish.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aw q:key=vcaa:14--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ax q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ay q:key=vcaa:&lt;h3&gt;You Might Also Like ...&lt;/h3&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=az q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h3 class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-15"&gt;You Might Also Like ...&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b1 q:key=vcaa:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/635773/why-are-oceans-salty"&gt;Why Are Oceans Salty?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/posts/animal-superlatives"&gt;17 Wild Animal Superlatives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/coelacanth-footage-natural-habitat"&gt;Scientists Capture Footage of Ancient Coelacanth in Its Natural Habitat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b2 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b4 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b5 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-17"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b7 q:key=vcaa:18--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b8 q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b9 q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;Giant Isopod (&lt;em&gt;Bathynomus giganteus&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ba q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-19"&gt;Giant Isopod (&lt;em&gt;Bathynomus giganteus&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bc q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BX983EyMQ8o--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bd q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=be q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bg q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;In biology, &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3894904/" target="_blank"&gt;Bergmann’s Rule&lt;/a&gt; states that smaller species tend to live in warmer climates, and larger species in colder environments. Case in point: the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/56278/18-awesome-facts-about-giant-isopods"&gt;giant isopod&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Bathynomus giganteus&lt;/em&gt;), a marine arthropod related to the much smaller, friendlier garden pillbug or roly-poly. These &lt;a href="https://txmarspecies.tamug.edu/invertfamilydetails.cfm?famnameID=Ancinidae%C2%A0" target="_blank"&gt;benthic beasts&lt;/a&gt; can grow over a foot long and are commonly found 7000 feet below sea level, where they hunt smaller creatures and &lt;a href="https://www.aquariumofpacific.org/onlinelearningcenter/species/giant_isopod" target="_blank"&gt;scavenge whale falls&lt;/a&gt; and other foods drifting down to the seafloor.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bh q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-21"&gt;In biology, &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3894904/" target="_blank"&gt;Bergmann’s Rule&lt;/a&gt; states that smaller species tend to live in warmer climates, and larger species in colder environments. Case in point: the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/56278/18-awesome-facts-about-giant-isopods"&gt;giant isopod&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Bathynomus giganteus&lt;/em&gt;), a marine arthropod related to the much smaller, friendlier garden pillbug or roly-poly. These &lt;a href="https://txmarspecies.tamug.edu/invertfamilydetails.cfm?famnameID=Ancinidae%C2%A0" target="_blank"&gt;benthic beasts&lt;/a&gt; can grow over a foot long and are commonly found 7000 feet below sea level, where they hunt smaller creatures and &lt;a href="https://www.aquariumofpacific.org/onlinelearningcenter/species/giant_isopod" target="_blank"&gt;scavenge whale falls&lt;/a&gt; and other foods drifting down to the seafloor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bj q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Scientists don’t really know why they’re so big; their relative hugeness could be an adaptation to their cold, highly pressurized habitat—a theory called abyssal gigantism, which also falls in line with Bergmann’s Rule. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bk q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-22"&gt;Scientists don’t really know why they’re so big; their relative hugeness could be an adaptation to their cold, highly pressurized habitat—a theory called abyssal gigantism, which also falls in line with Bergmann’s Rule.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bm q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Another weird fact: Though giant isopods are found in most regions of the world’s oceans, all individuals are physically identical, which suggests a &lt;a href="https://www.aquariumofpacific.org/onlinelearningcenter/species/giant_isopod" target="_blank"&gt;lack of evolution&lt;/a&gt;—even though they’ve been around for about 160 million years. This characteristic might be a product of their low-light environment. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bn q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-23"&gt;Another weird fact: Though giant isopods are found in most regions of the world’s oceans, all individuals are physically identical, which suggests a &lt;a href="https://www.aquariumofpacific.org/onlinelearningcenter/species/giant_isopod" target="_blank"&gt;lack of evolution&lt;/a&gt;—even though they’ve been around for about 160 million years. This characteristic might be a product of their low-light environment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bp q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;Gulper Eel (&lt;em&gt;Saccopharynx lavenbergi)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bq q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-24"&gt;Gulper Eel (&lt;em&gt;Saccopharynx lavenbergi)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bs q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XRO0IjSoHGA--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bt q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bu q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bw q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;The gulper eel (&lt;em&gt;Saccopharynx lavenbergi)&lt;/em&gt;, also called a pelican eel, is roughly a meter of tail and mouth. This unusual fish, the only species in the genus &lt;em&gt;Eurypharynx&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.mbari.org/animal/whiptail-gulper-eel/" target="_blank"&gt;slinks&lt;/a&gt; through the water as delicately as a rhythm gymnast’s ribbon. But its streamlined profile and uniform coloring disguise its main feature: an absolutely gigantic mouth.  &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bx q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-26"&gt;The gulper eel (&lt;em&gt;Saccopharynx lavenbergi)&lt;/em&gt;, also called a pelican eel, is roughly a meter of tail and mouth. This unusual fish, the only species in the genus &lt;em&gt;Eurypharynx&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.mbari.org/animal/whiptail-gulper-eel/" target="_blank"&gt;slinks&lt;/a&gt; through the water as delicately as a rhythm gymnast’s ribbon. But its streamlined profile and uniform coloring disguise its main feature: an absolutely gigantic mouth.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bz q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;The eel’s teeny eyes aren’t much help with hunting in the pitch-dark sea, so the gulper eel relies on a bioluminescent organ at the tip of its tail to attract prey. When it locates a small fish or &lt;a href="https://australian.museum/learn/animals/fishes/pelican-eel-eurypharynx-pelecanoides/" target="_blank"&gt;crustacean&lt;/a&gt;, all bets are off. The eel’s massive jaws swing forward and its mouth opens to a diameter many times that of the rest of its body to literally gulp its prey. The skin of its “cheeks” and throat is so flexible that its entire head can &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=gulper+eel&amp;amp;rlz=1C5GCCM_en___US1111&amp;amp;oq=gulper+eel&amp;amp;gs_lcrp=EgZjaHJvbWUqBwgAEAAYjwIyBwgAEAAYjwIyCggBEC4YsQMYgAQyBwgCEAAYgAQyBwgDEAAYgAQyBwgEEAAYgAQyBggFEEUYPDIGCAYQRRg8MgYIBxBFGEDSAQgzMTQwajBqN6gCALACAA&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8#fpstate=ive&amp;amp;vld=cid:690af80d,vid:iT_EMKl2A3Y,st:0" target="_blank"&gt;blow up like a balloon&lt;/a&gt;, giving the gulper eel the shape of a lollipop, and allowing it to engulf prey much larger than the eel itself. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c0 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-27"&gt;The eel’s teeny eyes aren’t much help with hunting in the pitch-dark sea, so the gulper eel relies on a bioluminescent organ at the tip of its tail to attract prey. When it locates a small fish or &lt;a href="https://australian.museum/learn/animals/fishes/pelican-eel-eurypharynx-pelecanoides/" target="_blank"&gt;crustacean&lt;/a&gt;, all bets are off. The eel’s massive jaws swing forward and its mouth opens to a diameter many times that of the rest of its body to literally gulp its prey. The skin of its “cheeks” and throat is so flexible that its entire head can &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=gulper+eel&amp;amp;rlz=1C5GCCM_en___US1111&amp;amp;oq=gulper+eel&amp;amp;gs_lcrp=EgZjaHJvbWUqBwgAEAAYjwIyBwgAEAAYjwIyCggBEC4YsQMYgAQyBwgCEAAYgAQyBwgDEAAYgAQyBwgEEAAYgAQyBggFEEUYPDIGCAYQRRg8MgYIBxBFGEDSAQgzMTQwajBqN6gCALACAA&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8#fpstate=ive&amp;amp;vld=cid:690af80d,vid:iT_EMKl2A3Y,st:0" target="_blank"&gt;blow up like a balloon&lt;/a&gt;, giving the gulper eel the shape of a lollipop, and allowing it to engulf prey much larger than the eel itself.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c2 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Because they live at depths between 900 and 7000 feet and don’t often come closer to the surface, gulper eels are rarely encountered in the wild, but they occasionally get swept up in commercial fishing nets. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c3 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-28"&gt;Because they live at depths between 900 and 7000 feet and don’t often come closer to the surface, gulper eels are rarely encountered in the wild, but they occasionally get swept up in commercial fishing nets.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c5 q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;Giant Tubeworms (&lt;em&gt;Riftia pachyptila&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c6 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-29"&gt;Giant Tubeworms (&lt;em&gt;Riftia pachyptila&lt;/em&gt;)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c8 q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7j_RfzhddBM--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c9 q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ca q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cc q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Scientists weren’t aware of the existence of deep-sea hydrothermal vents until 1977, when researchers &lt;a href="https://oceanservice.noaa.gov/facts/vents.html" target="_blank"&gt;discovered&lt;/a&gt; an area of the super-hot, &lt;a href="https://ocean.si.edu/ocean-life/invertebrates/tubeworms-hydrothermal-vent" target="_blank"&gt;mineral-rich springs&lt;/a&gt; bursting from the seafloor near the Galapagos Islands. Even more exciting? Encountering bizarre animals, like the giant tubeworm, thriving in what was thought to be an uninhabitable environment.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cd q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-31"&gt;Scientists weren’t aware of the existence of deep-sea hydrothermal vents until 1977, when researchers &lt;a href="https://oceanservice.noaa.gov/facts/vents.html" target="_blank"&gt;discovered&lt;/a&gt; an area of the super-hot, &lt;a href="https://ocean.si.edu/ocean-life/invertebrates/tubeworms-hydrothermal-vent" target="_blank"&gt;mineral-rich springs&lt;/a&gt; bursting from the seafloor near the Galapagos Islands. Even more exciting? Encountering bizarre animals, like the giant tubeworm, thriving in what was thought to be an uninhabitable environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cf q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;There were colonies of giant tubeworms (&lt;em&gt;Riftia pachyptila&lt;/em&gt;) crowding the vents. The 6-foot invertebrates are &lt;a href="https://www.mbari.org/animal/giant-tubeworm/" target="_blank"&gt;the heaviest worms&lt;/a&gt; and one of the fastest-growing species on Earth. They lack mouths and digestive systems—so, instead of eating, the worms harbor symbiotic bacteria in their bodies that transform the vents’ hydrogen sulfide emissions into energy. If the worms feel threatened, they can retract their red, feather-like gills inside the &lt;a href="https://nautiluslive.org/album/2015/06/20/life-extremes-tube-worms" target="_blank"&gt;protective white tubes&lt;/a&gt; surrounding their bodies. Thanks to their incredible adaptations, these extremophiles and the ecosystems they support may give us insight on how life could exist on &lt;a href="https://sites.imsa.edu/hadron/2023/11/09/using-extremophiles-to-study-the-potential-of-life-on-mars/" target="_blank"&gt;other planets&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cg q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-32"&gt;There were colonies of giant tubeworms (&lt;em&gt;Riftia pachyptila&lt;/em&gt;) crowding the vents. The 6-foot invertebrates are &lt;a href="https://www.mbari.org/animal/giant-tubeworm/" target="_blank"&gt;the heaviest worms&lt;/a&gt; and one of the fastest-growing species on Earth. They lack mouths and digestive systems—so, instead of eating, the worms harbor symbiotic bacteria in their bodies that transform the vents’ hydrogen sulfide emissions into energy. If the worms feel threatened, they can retract their red, feather-like gills inside the &lt;a href="https://nautiluslive.org/album/2015/06/20/life-extremes-tube-worms" target="_blank"&gt;protective white tubes&lt;/a&gt; surrounding their bodies. Thanks to their incredible adaptations, these extremophiles and the ecosystems they support may give us insight on how life could exist on &lt;a href="https://sites.imsa.edu/hadron/2023/11/09/using-extremophiles-to-study-the-potential-of-life-on-mars/" target="_blank"&gt;other planets&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ci q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;Barrel amphipod (&lt;em&gt;Phronima sedentaria&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cj q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-33"&gt;Barrel amphipod (&lt;em&gt;Phronima sedentaria&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cl q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5CUQ40jWX5g--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cm q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cn q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cp q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Imagine being a &lt;a href="https://twilightzone.whoi.edu/explore-the-otz/creature-features/creature-feature-salp/" target="_blank"&gt;salp&lt;/a&gt;, a type of marine invertebrate that’s basically a handful of transparent goo with a brain. One minute you’re minding your own business, efficiently using jet propulsion to move about the water column, and the next minute you’re getting eaten alive by a barrel amphipod. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cq q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-35"&gt;Imagine being a &lt;a href="https://twilightzone.whoi.edu/explore-the-otz/creature-features/creature-feature-salp/" target="_blank"&gt;salp&lt;/a&gt;, a type of marine invertebrate that’s basically a handful of transparent goo with a brain. One minute you’re minding your own business, efficiently using jet propulsion to move about the water column, and the next minute you’re getting eaten alive by a barrel amphipod.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cs q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Salps are no match for these inch-long, &lt;a href="https://www.mbari.org/animal/barrel-amphipod/" target="_blank"&gt;shrimp-like crustaceans&lt;/a&gt;. Barrel amphipods (&lt;em&gt;Phronima sedentaria&lt;/em&gt;) depend on salps for food and shelter in a deep-sea environment with few places to hide. First, the amphipod snags a passing salp with its sharp claws. It eviscerates the salp and eats its guts, then climbs inside the hollowed-out invertebrate, ensconcing itself in its new abode, a.k.a. barrel. But they don’t settle down; the creatures take their barrels with them wherever they go. These amphipods can even remodel their “homes” by secreting chemicals that strengthen the gelatinous structures. Because when you live more than &lt;a href="https://www.sealifebase.se/summary/Phronima-sedentaria.html"&gt;two-thirds of a mile&lt;/a&gt; below the surface of the ocean, housing is at a premium.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ct q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-36"&gt;Salps are no match for these inch-long, &lt;a href="https://www.mbari.org/animal/barrel-amphipod/" target="_blank"&gt;shrimp-like crustaceans&lt;/a&gt;. Barrel amphipods (&lt;em&gt;Phronima sedentaria&lt;/em&gt;) depend on salps for food and shelter in a deep-sea environment with few places to hide. First, the amphipod snags a passing salp with its sharp claws. It eviscerates the salp and eats its guts, then climbs inside the hollowed-out invertebrate, ensconcing itself in its new abode, a.k.a. barrel. But they don’t settle down; the creatures take their barrels with them wherever they go. These amphipods can even remodel their “homes” by secreting chemicals that strengthen the gelatinous structures. Because when you live more than &lt;a href="https://www.sealifebase.se/summary/Phronima-sedentaria.html"&gt;two-thirds of a mile&lt;/a&gt; below the surface of the ocean, housing is at a premium.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cv q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;Bloodybelly Comb Jelly (&lt;em&gt;Lampocteis cruentiventer&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cw q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-37"&gt;Bloodybelly Comb Jelly (&lt;em&gt;Lampocteis cruentiventer&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cy q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6luG9mDaGgw--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cz q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d0 q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d2 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;The bloodybelly comb jelly (&lt;em&gt;Lampocteis cruentiventer&lt;/em&gt;) really is &lt;a href="https://www.mbari.org/animal/bloody-belly-comb-jelly/"&gt;called that&lt;/a&gt; by actual scientists. These 6-inch, &lt;a href="https://www.kongcompany.com/catalogue/KK/"&gt;KONG-shaped&lt;/a&gt; globs are deep red to hide themselves in the twilight world, where red coloring acts like camouflage against the darkness. It’s a necessary adaptation, because the bloodybelly comb jelly’s favorite foods are bioluminescent. Without its red disguise, the comb jelly’s predators would be able to spot its meals glowing through its semi-transparent stomach.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d3 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-39"&gt;The bloodybelly comb jelly (&lt;em&gt;Lampocteis cruentiventer&lt;/em&gt;) really is &lt;a href="https://www.mbari.org/animal/bloody-belly-comb-jelly/"&gt;called that&lt;/a&gt; by actual scientists. These 6-inch, &lt;a href="https://www.kongcompany.com/catalogue/KK/"&gt;KONG-shaped&lt;/a&gt; globs are deep red to hide themselves in the twilight world, where red coloring acts like camouflage against the darkness. It’s a necessary adaptation, because the bloodybelly comb jelly’s favorite foods are bioluminescent. Without its red disguise, the comb jelly’s predators would be able to spot its meals glowing through its semi-transparent stomach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d5 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;These comb jellies are bioluminescent, too, and may use these signals for &lt;a href="https://vikingecotours.com/videos-stories/bioluminescent-comb-jellies"&gt;communication&lt;/a&gt; or as a defense mechanism. Whatever light is available in the ocean’s depths diffracts and refracts off its hair-like cilia, which resemble tiny combs arranged in rows up and down the jelly’s belly. The movement of the cilia help the jelly swim—and make it light up like Times Square.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d6 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-40"&gt;These comb jellies are bioluminescent, too, and may use these signals for &lt;a href="https://vikingecotours.com/videos-stories/bioluminescent-comb-jellies"&gt;communication&lt;/a&gt; or as a defense mechanism. Whatever light is available in the ocean’s depths diffracts and refracts off its hair-like cilia, which resemble tiny combs arranged in rows up and down the jelly’s belly. The movement of the cilia help the jelly swim—and make it light up like Times Square.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d8 q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;Barreleye Fish (&lt;em&gt;Macropinna microstoma&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d9 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-41"&gt;Barreleye Fish (&lt;em&gt;Macropinna microstoma&lt;/em&gt;)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=db q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Akv36y8WLYA--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dc q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dd q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=df q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;We’ve met quite a few semi- or fully-transparent denizens of the deep, but the &lt;a href="https://www.mbari.org/animal/barreleye-fish/" target="_blank"&gt;barreleye fish&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Macropinna microstoma&lt;/em&gt;) takes it to the next level. The back half of this guy looks like your average, 6-inch fish. The front half is a different story: the top of its head is completely see-through, revealing its eyes and brain encased in a fluid-filled bubble. Two indentations at the front of its head, which look like they &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be eyes, are actually the fish’s olfactory sensors.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dg q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-43"&gt;We’ve met quite a few semi- or fully-transparent denizens of the deep, but the &lt;a href="https://www.mbari.org/animal/barreleye-fish/" target="_blank"&gt;barreleye fish&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Macropinna microstoma&lt;/em&gt;) takes it to the next level. The back half of this guy looks like your average, 6-inch fish. The front half is a different story: the top of its head is completely see-through, revealing its eyes and brain encased in a fluid-filled bubble. Two indentations at the front of its head, which look like they &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be eyes, are actually the fish’s olfactory sensors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=di q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Its eyes are bright green and barrel-shaped (hence its name) and point straight up. The green hue might filter out certain wavelengths of light and aid them in seeing other creatures’ bioluminescence. Research dives by the Monterey Bay Aquarium Research Institute in 2009 &lt;a href="https://marinesanctuary.org/blog/sea-wonder-barreleye/" target="_blank"&gt;revealed&lt;/a&gt; that the fish can also rotate their eyes to face ahead, which probably helps them forage for zooplankton more accurately. But why it developed such extreme adaptations to life in the ocean’s &lt;a href="https://www.montereybayaquarium.org/animals/animals-a-to-z/barreleye" target="_blank"&gt;twilight zone&lt;/a&gt; is still a bit of a mystery.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dj q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-44"&gt;Its eyes are bright green and barrel-shaped (hence its name) and point straight up. The green hue might filter out certain wavelengths of light and aid them in seeing other creatures’ bioluminescence. Research dives by the Monterey Bay Aquarium Research Institute in 2009 &lt;a href="https://marinesanctuary.org/blog/sea-wonder-barreleye/" target="_blank"&gt;revealed&lt;/a&gt; that the fish can also rotate their eyes to face ahead, which probably helps them forage for zooplankton more accurately. But why it developed such extreme adaptations to life in the ocean’s &lt;a href="https://www.montereybayaquarium.org/animals/animals-a-to-z/barreleye" target="_blank"&gt;twilight zone&lt;/a&gt; is still a bit of a mystery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dl q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story was adapted from an episode of The List Show on YouTube. Don’t forget to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MentalFloss" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;subscribe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; for fascinating new videos every week.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dm q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-45"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story was adapted from an episode of The List Show on YouTube. Don’t forget to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MentalFloss" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;subscribe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; for fascinating new videos every week.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org"&gt;Adblock test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org/acceptable.html"&gt;(Why?)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How China’s New Emissions Pledge Could Radically Alter Climate Change</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-chinas-new-emissions-pledge-could-radically-alter-climate-change/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s plan to reduce greenhouse gases will largely determine the world&amp;rsquo;s emissions trajectory, researchers say&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Don't Drown in Empathy</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/threshold/202509/dont-drown-in-empathy</link><description>Discover why understanding others’ perspectives—without absorbing their pain—can transform your relationships, boost resilience, and prevent burnout.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:05:44 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Garmin fitness trackers and smartwatches are up to 45% off during Amazon’s early Prime Day deals</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/garmin-fitness-tracker-smartwatch-early-prime-day-deal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Whether you want an intense adventure watch or a simple fitness tracker, many of Garmin's most popular models are deeply discounted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/garmin-fitness-tracker-smartwatch-early-prime-day-deal/"&gt;Garmin fitness trackers and smartwatches are up to 45% off during Amazon&amp;#8217;s early Prime Day deals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:57:07 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>October Stargazing: A supermoon, new comet, and a whole lot of meteors</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/stargazing-guide-october-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Comet C/2025 A6 (Lemmon) was only discovered in January 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/stargazing-guide-october-2025/"&gt;October Stargazing: A supermoon, new comet, and a whole lot of meteors&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>People Are More Likely to Cheat When Using AI</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/urban-survival/202509/people-are-more-likely-to-cheat-when-using-ai</link><description>Will outsourcing to AI erode our moral conscience? New research reveals people are more likely to be dishonest when delegating tasks to AI systems.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:00:17 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>3 Mindsets That May Be Keeping You From Reaching Your Potential</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/social-instincts/202509/3-mindsets-that-may-be-keeping-you-from-reaching-your-potential</link><description>Mindsets that could be sabotaging your chances at success.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:07:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Retraumatization and Its Impact on Trauma Recovery</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/stress-fracture/202509/retraumatization-and-its-impact-on-trauma-recovery</link><description>Retraumatization can disrupt healing. Learn to recognize the situations that can place trauma victims at risk.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:14:40 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How Time in Nature Powers Your Creativity</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/creative-insights/202509/how-time-in-nature-powers-your-creativity</link><description>One of the most natural ways to stimulate your creativity is waiting right outside your back door, down the street, in a nearby park, or on a family vacation.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:18:15 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Why we should be skeptical of the hasty global push to test 15-year-olds’ AI literacy in 2029</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-we-should-be-skeptical-of-the-hasty-global-push-to-test-15-year-olds-ai-literacy-in-2029-263695</link><description>Canada and other OECD countries’ plans to test students’ AI literacy in 2029 threatens to obscure essential questions about the marketing of AI.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 13:31:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Purging the Ghost of Past Love</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-freedom-to-change/202509/purging-the-ghost-of-past-love</link><description>You don't have to feel stuck longing for that past love and not feeling fully satisfied with the one you're with. Learn to let go of your old schema and live in the present.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:35:28 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Navigate Age-Gap Relationships</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/this-sexual-self/202509/how-to-navigate-age-gap-relationships</link><description>Age-gap relationships — exceeding 10 years or more — have been a source of debate. Are they finding more acceptance in today’s world?</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:12:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>What Fuels Our Desire for Status Symbols?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/authenticity-101/202509/what-fuels-our-desire-for-status-symbols</link><description>All status symbols are signposts to other people to inform them that we are trustworthy members of their tribe.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:13:21 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Purpose: The Secret Sauce for Living Longer and Better</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/what-to-do-as-you-grow-older/202509/purpose-the-secret-sauce-for-living-longer-and-better</link><description>To increase the quantity and improve the quality of your life, create "purpose" based on research in sociology, psychology, and neuroplasticity.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:18:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Blamespeak: Can Words Lead to Violence?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/5-types-of-people-who-can-ruin-your-life/202509/blamespeak-can-words-lead-to-violence</link><description>Disagreements over ideas and behavior are common. But when words target individuals and groups with emotional repetition of personal attacks, violence becomes a risk.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:18:39 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Are We Alone? NASA’s Habitable Worlds Observatory Aims to Find Out</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/are-we-alone-nasas-habitable-worlds-observatory-aims-to-find-out/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Habitable Worlds Observatory is poised to tell us whether Earth-like planets are common&amp;mdash;if it can get off the ground&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Is Resilience, Really?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/bending-without-breaking/202509/what-is-resilience-really</link><description>Resilience isn’t innate—it’s built. Psychological flexibility from acceptance and commitment therapy, rooted in ancient wisdom, offers practical insights.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:39:44 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>3 Relationship Lessons from "The Summer I Turned Pretty"</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/bystander-intervention-in-action/202509/3-relationship-lessons-from-the-summer-i-turned-pretty</link><description>"The Summer I Turned Pretty" is about more than summer flings on a pretty beach. It’s also about communication, boundaries and how to avoid losing yourself in a relationship.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:42:46 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>5 Keys to Reviving a Childhood Dream</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/when-kids-call-the-shots/202509/5-keys-to-reviving-a-childhood-dream</link><description>Haunted by an unfulfilled dream? It's never too late to begin again.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:47:31 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Author Lily King on Romantic Regret</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/well-read/202509/author-lily-king-on-romantic-regret</link><description>Regret is a painful, but universal experience that is especially common as we approach middle age. Here's what research, and Lily King's latest novel, has to say about regret.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:50:31 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Can You Decipher These Translated Song Lyrics? Tune Twist Quiz #60</title><link>https://www.mentalfloss.com/quizzes/tune-twist-quiz-60?utm_source=RSS</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class="ff-og-image-inserted" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_3840,h_2160/c_fill,w_1440,ar_1440:810,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/voltaxMediaLibrary/mmsport/mentalfloss/01j920cj22yp8sbyhc7m.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9n q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;In Tune Twist, we run the lyrics of a hit song through multiple languages, then translate them back into English—and this autumn, we’re featuring somewhat spooky songs in the run up to Halloween. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9o q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="mt-[18px] md:mt-0 mb-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-0"&gt;In Tune Twist, we run the lyrics of a hit song through multiple languages, then translate them back into English—and this autumn, we’re featuring somewhat spooky songs in the run up to Halloween. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9q q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Here’s a hint that might help you identify this tune: The song, which came out in 2019, was the lead single off the artist’s first album in 10 years (that album came out in 2020), and it was accompanied by a nearly six-minute-long music video. The director “developed the story into a ‘mini movie,’ ” the singer said at the time. “But, to be quite honest, it’s hard for me to watch because it takes me back to some of the darkest times in my life.”&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9r q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-1"&gt;Here’s a hint that might help you identify this tune: The song, which came out in 2019, was the lead single off the artist’s first album in 10 years (that album came out in 2020), and it was accompanied by a nearly six-minute-long music video. The director “developed the story into a ‘mini movie,’ ” the singer said at the time. “But, to be quite honest, it’s hard for me to watch because it takes me back to some of the darkest times in my life.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9t q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Can you figure out what the song is, or who performed it? Test your deciphering skills and your musical knowledge below.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9u q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-2"&gt;Can you figure out what the song is, or who performed it? Test your deciphering skills and your musical knowledge below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9w q:key=vcaa:https://www.riddle.com/embed/a/N1gPz6ki?--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9x q:key=SRoa:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9y q:key=EEns:oZ_1--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a0 q:key=vcaa:4--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a1 q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a2 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a3 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a5 q:key=vcaa:6--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a6 q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a7 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take Our Latest &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/quizzes/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quizzes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a8 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-7"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take Our Latest &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/quizzes/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quizzes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aa q:key=vcaa:https://content-enrichment-service.mmsport.minutesvc.com/oembed?url=https://content-enrichment-service.mmsport.minutesvc.com/properties/mentalfloss/embeds/01j6yxa15b2gmq4--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ab q:key=jBas:mL_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org"&gt;Adblock test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org/acceptable.html"&gt;(Why?)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 14:56:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can an Over-the-Counter Nasal Spray Prevent COVID and Colds?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/fevered-mind/202509/can-an-over-the-counter-nasal-spray-prevent-covid-and-colds</link><description>Azelastine, a common nasal spray for allergies, reduced the risk of COVID-19 and colds in one small trial. Larger studies are needed before recommending widespread use.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:57:09 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Camels depicted in 12,000-year-old rock art</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/camels-rock-art-cave-saudi-arabia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The 'incredibly beautiful' cave carvings show how humans thrived in the Arabian desert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/camels-rock-art-cave-saudi-arabia/"&gt;Camels depicted in 12,000-year-old rock art&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Rock Art Discovery Reveals Unknown Arabian Nomads from 12,000 Years Ago</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/rock-art-discovery-reveals-unknown-arabian-nomads-from-12-000-years-ago/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Camels in ancient Arabia may have led hunter-gatherers through deserts once thought uninhabitable&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Much Does It Matter to Match Your Partner's Mood?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/fulfillment-at-any-age/202509/how-much-does-it-matter-to-match-your-partners-mood</link><description>Every relationship has good days and bad ones. A new study on mood takes a look at what it means to be in emotional synchrony with your romantic partner.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:00:47 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Become a Super Learner</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/when-disaster-strikes-inside-disaster-psychology/202509/how-to-become-a-super-learner</link><description>Science-based techniques can help you learn more effectively.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:12:30 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Recent Advances in Motivational Interviewing With Couples</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/queer-relationships-no-straight-lines/202509/recent-advances-in-motivational-interviewing-with</link><description>Motivational interviewing (MI) is a widely used evidence-based intervention applied to many health behaviors. Learn more about recent research on the use of MI with couples.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:35:06 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Sea sponges may have been Earth’s first living creatures</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/earth-first-animal-sea-sponge/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The prehistoric invertebrates likely arrived about 541 million years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/earth-first-animal-sea-sponge/"&gt;Sea sponges may have been Earth’s first living creatures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:50:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>If You Don't Have Kids, What's Your Legacy?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/unapparent/202509/if-you-dont-have-kids-whats-your-legacy</link><description>Personal Perspective: When you don't have kids, you can design your own legacy.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:53:08 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Maybe AI Was Never a Tool</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-digital-self/202509/maybe-ai-was-never-a-tool</link><description>Using artificial intelligence "responsibly" assumes it is just another tool—it isn't.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The 20 International Foods Most Commonly Mispronounced by Americans</title><link>https://www.mentalfloss.com/language/pronunciation/international-foods-most-commonly-mispronounced-by-americans?utm_source=RSS</link><description>&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9n q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;One of the perks of traveling and sight-seeing—or of eating out in a big city or a food festival—is the opportunity to try dishes from countries and cultures far outside your own. Of course, some international dishes have proved popular enough to become all but everyday staples around the world, so you’re now just as likely to see &lt;em&gt;ciabatta&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;tzatziki&lt;/em&gt; on the menu in your local sandwich shop as you are in a restaurant in Italy or Greece.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9o q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="mt-[18px] md:mt-0 mb-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-0"&gt;One of the perks of traveling and sight-seeing—or of eating out in a big city or a food festival—is the opportunity to try dishes from countries and cultures far outside your own. Of course, some international dishes have proved popular enough to become all but everyday staples around the world, so you’re now just as likely to see &lt;em&gt;ciabatta&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;tzatziki&lt;/em&gt; on the menu in your local sandwich shop as you are in a restaurant in Italy or Greece.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9q q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;An unfortunate pitfall of trying and adopting international foods, though, is that many of us English speakers aren’t all that confident when it comes to tackling their equally international names. And now, a new study by language-learning website &lt;a href="https://preply.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Preply&lt;/a&gt; has uncovered the top 20 most frequently mispronounced international foods among Americans (along with guidelines on how to pronounce them).&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9r q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-1"&gt;An unfortunate pitfall of trying and adopting international foods, though, is that many of us English speakers aren’t all that confident when it comes to tackling their equally international names. And now, a new study by language-learning website &lt;a href="https://preply.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Preply&lt;/a&gt; has uncovered the top 20 most frequently mispronounced international foods among Americans (along with guidelines on how to pronounce them).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9t q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Building on &lt;a href="https://preply.com/en/blog/holiday-language/" target="_blank"&gt;another recent study&lt;/a&gt; Preply carried out into the phenomenon of&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/geography/maps/countries-where-americans-are-intimidated-to-speak-language-mapped"&gt; language anxiety&lt;/a&gt;, the study’s authors took to Google to count the number of times Americans searched the prompts “how to pronounce [the name of a food],” “how to say [the name of a food],” and “[the name of a food] pronunciation.” With these figures added together, the foods in question were then ranked by the total quantity of search volume their tricky pronunciations had elicited among Americans.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9u q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-2"&gt;Building on &lt;a href="https://preply.com/en/blog/holiday-language/" target="_blank"&gt;another recent study&lt;/a&gt; Preply carried out into the phenomenon of&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/geography/maps/countries-where-americans-are-intimidated-to-speak-language-mapped"&gt; language anxiety&lt;/a&gt;, the study’s authors took to Google to count the number of times Americans searched the prompts “how to pronounce [the name of a food],” “how to say [the name of a food],” and “[the name of a food] pronunciation.” With these figures added together, the foods in question were then ranked by the total quantity of search volume their tricky pronunciations had elicited among Americans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9w q:key=vcaa:--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9x q:key=StMp:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=Lf_2--&gt;&lt;ol class="toc text-primary mt-4 flex flex-col gap-y-2.5 ps-10 list-decimal [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/language/pronunciation/international-foods-most-commonly-mispronounced-by-americans?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-4"&gt;A Deep Dive into the Top 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/language/pronunciation/international-foods-most-commonly-mispronounced-by-americans?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-25"&gt;The 20 International Food Names Americans Struggle to Pronounce&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9z q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;A Deep Dive into the Top 5&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a0 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-4"&gt;A Deep Dive into the Top 5&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a2 q:key=vcaa:&lt;h3&gt;Gyros&lt;/h3&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a3 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h3 class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-5"&gt;Gyros&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a5 q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_2120,h_1413,x_0,y_0/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k610rjykqpcq8qvv1x--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a6 q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a7 q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=a7 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a8 q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=a8 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a9 q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aa q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ab q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=ab q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=aa q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="Chicken Souvlaki Gyro with Tzatziki Sauce" class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="1413" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_2120,h_1413/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k610rjykqpcq8qvv1x.jpg" title="Chicken Souvlaki Gyro with Tzatziki Sauce" width="2120" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Gyros. | LauriPatterson/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=af q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Gyros are Greek pita bread sandwich, often filled with meat and served with salad, vegetables, and yogurt. As for that name—which the survey discovered earns a staggering 81,000 Google searches every month—nope,&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/language/pronunciation/how-to-pronounce-gyro"&gt; that’s not a hard &lt;em&gt;g&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. And even more trickily, English doesn’t really have a perfect equivalent of the sound in its original Greek that that letter &lt;em&gt;g&lt;/em&gt; is meant to represent (which is a little like a cross between a “y” and a “zh”). According to Merriam-Webster, though, you can get away with &lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/gyro#dictionary-entry-2" target="_blank"&gt;either&lt;/a&gt; “YEE-ro” or “ZHEE-ro.” &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ag q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-7"&gt;Gyros are Greek pita bread sandwich, often filled with meat and served with salad, vegetables, and yogurt. As for that name—which the survey discovered earns a staggering 81,000 Google searches every month—nope,&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/language/pronunciation/how-to-pronounce-gyro"&gt; that’s not a hard &lt;em&gt;g&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. And even more trickily, English doesn’t really have a perfect equivalent of the sound in its original Greek that that letter &lt;em&gt;g&lt;/em&gt; is meant to represent (which is a little like a cross between a “y” and a “zh”). According to Merriam-Webster, though, you can get away with &lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/gyro#dictionary-entry-2" target="_blank"&gt;either&lt;/a&gt; “YEE-ro” or “ZHEE-ro.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ai q:key=vcaa:&lt;h3&gt;Açaí&lt;/h3&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aj q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h3 class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-8"&gt;Açaí&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=al q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_2119,h_1412,x_0,y_0/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k6111am8v0269knvgn--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=am q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=an q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=an q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ao q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=ao q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ap q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aq q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ar q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=ar q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=aq q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="Acai bowl with various fruits and berries" class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="1412" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_2119,h_1412/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k6111am8v0269knvgn.jpg" title="Acai bowl with various fruits and berries" width="2119" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Açaí bowl. | Alexander Spatari/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=av q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;The second food on Preply’s list of mispronunciations—&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/635056/how-to-pronounce-acai"&gt;&lt;em&gt;açaí&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the superfood berry used in ever-popular and uber-healthy açai bowls—earned a full 25,000 fewer Google searches every month than the No. 1 slot, with a total of 56,600. Still, pronouncing the word is no less tricky, especially because it manages to cram &lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/acai" target="_blank"&gt;three syllables&lt;/a&gt; into just four letters: “ah-sah-EE.” &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aw q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-10"&gt;The second food on Preply’s list of mispronunciations—&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/635056/how-to-pronounce-acai"&gt;&lt;em&gt;açaí&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the superfood berry used in ever-popular and uber-healthy açai bowls—earned a full 25,000 fewer Google searches every month than the No. 1 slot, with a total of 56,600. Still, pronouncing the word is no less tricky, especially because it manages to cram &lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/acai" target="_blank"&gt;three syllables&lt;/a&gt; into just four letters: “ah-sah-EE.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ay q:key=vcaa:11--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=az q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b0 q:key=vcaa:&lt;h3&gt;You Might Also Like ...&lt;/h3&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b1 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h3 class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-12"&gt;You Might Also Like ...&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b3 q:key=vcaa:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/geography/maps/most-mispronounced-word-in-each-state"&gt;Mapped: The Word Each State Has the Most Trouble Pronouncing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/language/pronunciation/commonly-mispronounced-alcoholic-drink-names"&gt;14 Alcoholic Drink Names You’re Probably Mispronouncing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/60267/10-words-whose-pronunciation-has-changed-over-time"&gt;10 Common Words We Don’t Pronounce Like We Used to&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b4 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b6 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b7 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-14"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b9 q:key=vcaa:15--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ba q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bb q:key=vcaa:&lt;h3&gt;Pho&lt;/h3&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bc q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h3 class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-16"&gt;Pho&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=be q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_2121,h_1414,x_0,y_0/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k611362dz5dg62s49f--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bf q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bg q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=bg q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bh q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=bh q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bi q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bj q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bk q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=bk q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=bj q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="Man eating Vietnamese Pho soup with noodles and beef, personal perspective view" class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="1414" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_2121,h_1414/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k611362dz5dg62s49f.jpg" title="Man eating Vietnamese Pho soup with noodles and beef, personal perspective view" width="2121" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Pho soup. | Alexander Spatari/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bo q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Coming in with an average of 39,000 Google searches per month, the Vietnamese meat and rice-noodle broth &lt;em&gt;pho&lt;/em&gt; has been around in English &lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/pho" target="_blank"&gt;since the 1930s&lt;/a&gt;, according to Merriam-Webster. We might have ditched its original diacritics for our letter &lt;em&gt;o&lt;/em&gt; (the correct Vietnamese spelling would be phở), but we’ve nonetheless retained its Vietnamese pronunciation: &lt;em&gt;pho&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t rhyme with &lt;em&gt;foe&lt;/em&gt;, but should be pronounced simply as “fuh”—a little like the sound &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; gets cut down to in fast-paced conversation. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bp q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-18"&gt;Coming in with an average of 39,000 Google searches per month, the Vietnamese meat and rice-noodle broth &lt;em&gt;pho&lt;/em&gt; has been around in English &lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/pho" target="_blank"&gt;since the 1930s&lt;/a&gt;, according to Merriam-Webster. We might have ditched its original diacritics for our letter &lt;em&gt;o&lt;/em&gt; (the correct Vietnamese spelling would be phở), but we’ve nonetheless retained its Vietnamese pronunciation: &lt;em&gt;pho&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t rhyme with &lt;em&gt;foe&lt;/em&gt;, but should be pronounced simply as “fuh”—a little like the sound &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; gets cut down to in fast-paced conversation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=br q:key=vcaa:&lt;h3&gt;Worcestershire Sauce&lt;/h3&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bs q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h3 class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-19"&gt;Worcestershire Sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bu q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_3021,h_1699,x_0,y_500/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k6115jaxwmzqhmn7e6--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bv q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bw q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=bw q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bx q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=bx q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=by q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bz q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c0 q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=c0 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=bz q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="Worcestershire Sauce" class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="1699" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_500,w_3021,h_1699/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k6115jaxwmzqhmn7e6.jpg" title="Worcestershire Sauce" width="3021" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Worcestershire sauce. | Dorling Kindersley: Dave King/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c4 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;British place names are often&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/geography/maps/commonly-mispronounced-uk-place-names-mapped"&gt; notoriously tricky&lt;/a&gt; to pronounce among non-Brits, of course, but the fact that the English county of Worcestershire is famously home to an ever-popular relish-like sauce now found in kitchens and pantries &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/herefordandworcester/culture/2002/02/lea_perrins.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;across the globe&lt;/a&gt; has brought its minefield of a name to English speakers all over the world. The trick is not to get bogged down in all 14 of those letters, because &lt;em&gt;Worcestershire&lt;/em&gt; is just&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/language/pronunciation/how-to-pronounce-worcestershire-sauce"&gt; pronounced&lt;/a&gt; “WUSS-tuh-shuh”—a pronunciation that earns it an average of 34,000 Google searches in the U.S. every month. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c5 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-21"&gt;British place names are often&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/geography/maps/commonly-mispronounced-uk-place-names-mapped"&gt; notoriously tricky&lt;/a&gt; to pronounce among non-Brits, of course, but the fact that the English county of Worcestershire is famously home to an ever-popular relish-like sauce now found in kitchens and pantries &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/herefordandworcester/culture/2002/02/lea_perrins.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;across the globe&lt;/a&gt; has brought its minefield of a name to English speakers all over the world. The trick is not to get bogged down in all 14 of those letters, because &lt;em&gt;Worcestershire&lt;/em&gt; is just&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/language/pronunciation/how-to-pronounce-worcestershire-sauce"&gt; pronounced&lt;/a&gt; “WUSS-tuh-shuh”—a pronunciation that earns it an average of 34,000 Google searches in the U.S. every month.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c7 q:key=vcaa:&lt;h3&gt;Gnocchi&lt;/h3&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c8 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h3 class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-22"&gt;Gnocchi&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ca q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_1977,h_1318,x_0,y_0/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k6116fqmkmqzfh2nkc--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cb q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cc q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=cc q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cd q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=cd q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ce q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cf q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cg q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=cg q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=cf q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="Freshly rolled gnocchi on a kitchen bench." class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="1318" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_1977,h_1318/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k6116fqmkmqzfh2nkc.jpg" title="Freshly rolled gnocchi on a kitchen bench." width="1977" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Freshly rolled gnocchi. | John White Photos/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ck q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;To a lot of English speakers, these pasta-like Italian potato dumplings are &lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/gnocchi" target="_blank"&gt;pronounced&lt;/a&gt; a little like the word &lt;em&gt;knock&lt;/em&gt; just with a &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; added to the end of it. In the native Italian, though (and to more globally-minded English speakers, for that matter), there’s a hidden “y” sound in the middle of this name too: &lt;em&gt;gnocchi &lt;/em&gt;is really more like “NYOH-kee,” than “NOH-kee,” a fact that earns it over 33,000 Google searches every month.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cl q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-24"&gt;To a lot of English speakers, these pasta-like Italian potato dumplings are &lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/gnocchi" target="_blank"&gt;pronounced&lt;/a&gt; a little like the word &lt;em&gt;knock&lt;/em&gt; just with a &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; added to the end of it. In the native Italian, though (and to more globally-minded English speakers, for that matter), there’s a hidden “y” sound in the middle of this name too: &lt;em&gt;gnocchi &lt;/em&gt;is really more like “NYOH-kee,” than “NOH-kee,” a fact that earns it over 33,000 Google searches every month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cn q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;The 20 International Food Names Americans Struggle to Pronounce &lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=co q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-25"&gt;The 20 International Food Names Americans Struggle to Pronounce&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cq q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_2121,h_1414,x_0,y_0/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k611sjf9y592v22x2y--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cr q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cs q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=cs q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ct q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=ct q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cu q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cv q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cw q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=cw q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=cv q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="Summer treat, healthy breakfast with crepes, fresh strawberry, cheese and coffee" class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="1414" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_2121,h_1414/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k611sjf9y592v22x2y.jpg" title="Summer treat, healthy breakfast with crepes, fresh strawberry, cheese and coffee" width="2121" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Crepes. | istetiana/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d0 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Elsewhere on Preply’s list, the rest of the top 10 was made up of &lt;em&gt;quinoa&lt;/em&gt; (“KEEN-wah”) in sixth place, followed by &lt;em&gt;caprese&lt;/em&gt; (“kuh-PREY-zey”), &lt;em&gt;charcuterie&lt;/em&gt; (“shahr-KOO-tuh-ree”), &lt;em&gt;macaron&lt;/em&gt; (“mack-uh-ROHN”), and the aforementioned Greek &lt;em&gt;tzatziki&lt;/em&gt; (“TSAT-see-kee”). It was Italian names that came out on top the most frequently, however, with eight words making the final list: Alongside &lt;em&gt;gnocchi&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;caprese&lt;/em&gt; salad, the survey ranked &lt;em&gt;focaccia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;bruschetta&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;ciabatta&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;prosciutto&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;mascarpone,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;tiramisu&lt;/em&gt; in the Top 20 overall. See the full list below.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d1 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-27"&gt;Elsewhere on Preply’s list, the rest of the top 10 was made up of &lt;em&gt;quinoa&lt;/em&gt; (“KEEN-wah”) in sixth place, followed by &lt;em&gt;caprese&lt;/em&gt; (“kuh-PREY-zey”), &lt;em&gt;charcuterie&lt;/em&gt; (“shahr-KOO-tuh-ree”), &lt;em&gt;macaron&lt;/em&gt; (“mack-uh-ROHN”), and the aforementioned Greek &lt;em&gt;tzatziki&lt;/em&gt; (“TSAT-see-kee”). It was Italian names that came out on top the most frequently, however, with eight words making the final list: Alongside &lt;em&gt;gnocchi&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;caprese&lt;/em&gt; salad, the survey ranked &lt;em&gt;focaccia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;bruschetta&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;ciabatta&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;prosciutto&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;mascarpone,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;tiramisu&lt;/em&gt; in the Top 20 overall. See the full list below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d3 q:key=vcaa:28--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d4 q:key=ndZW:mL_1--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-auto max-w-[90vw]"&gt;&lt;table class="border-collapse text-left w-full"&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="bg-lightGrey py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rank&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th class="bg-lightGrey py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Food&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th class="bg-lightGrey py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Average Monthly Google Searches in the U.S.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th class="bg-lightGrey py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pronunciation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gyros&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;81,300 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“YEE-ro” or “ZHEE-ro”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Açai&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;56,600&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“ah-sah-EE”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pho&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;39,000&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“fuh”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Worcestershire [sauce]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;34,300&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“WUSS-tuh-shuh”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gnocchi&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;33,700&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“NYOH-kee”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;6.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quinoa&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;20,900&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“KEEN-wah”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Caprese&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;20,700&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“kuh-PREY-zey”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;8.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Charcuterie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;16,600&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“shahr-KOO-tuh-ree”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;9.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Macaron&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;15,400&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“mack-uh-ROHN”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tzatziki&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;15,300&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“TSAT-see-kee”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;11.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Focaccia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;14,500&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“foh-KAH-chuh”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;12.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bruschetta&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;13,800&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“broo-SKET-uh”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;13. (tie)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chipotle, Croissant&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;12,600&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“chi-POHT-lay,” “krua-SAHN”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;15. (tie)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ciabatta, Edamame&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;9200&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“chuh-BAH-tuh,” “eh-dah-MAH-may”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;17.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prosciutto&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;8600&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“proh-SHOO-toh”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;18.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boeuf bourguignon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;6720&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“buff boor-gheen-YON”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;19.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crêpe&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;6620&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“krep”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="border-b-[1px] border-b-lightGrey"&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;20. (tie)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mascarpone, Ramen, Tiramisu&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;6200&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="py-3 px-10 my-0 mx-auto"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“MAS-car-POH-nee,” “RAH-men,” “tira-mee-SOO”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org"&gt;Adblock test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org/acceptable.html"&gt;(Why?)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:02:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Using Emotional Power to Envision the Impossible</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-emotional-toolkit/202509/using-emotional-power-to-envision-the-impossible</link><description>People sometimes feel trapped and helpless in their situations. There is one emotion that can be powerful enough to transform how we view the world and ourselves.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:09:59 -0400</pubDate></item></channel></rss>