<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/merged-feed/merged.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS from multiple sources</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/merged-feed/merged.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 09:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Drought can make farmers feel worried and hopeless: Ghana study finds social networks help</title><link>https://theconversation.com/drought-can-make-farmers-feel-worried-and-hopeless-ghana-study-finds-social-networks-help-262627</link><description>Drought adversely affects the mental health of Ghanaian farmers.</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 14:02:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why do smart people get hooked on wellness trends? Personality traits may play a role</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-do-smart-people-get-hooked-on-wellness-trends-personality-traits-may-play-a-role-263041</link><description>Certain personality traits may help explain why some educated, well-intentioned people sometimes reject conventional medicine in favour of fringe practices.</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:35:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Are you really an ISFJ? The truth about personality tests – and why we keep taking them</title><link>https://theconversation.com/are-you-really-an-isfj-the-truth-about-personality-tests-and-why-we-keep-taking-them-261183</link><description>Tests such as Myers-Briggs promise self-discovery – but here’s why you shouldn’t take them too seriously.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 05:11:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1 in 3 teens has thought about suicide this year. Here’s what to look for – and where to get help</title><link>https://theconversation.com/1-in-3-teens-has-thought-about-suicide-this-year-heres-what-to-look-for-and-where-to-get-help-263422</link><description>A suicide attempt doesn’t always involve prior planning or thinking. But there are warnings signs.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 05:18:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why people embrace conspiracy theories: it’s about community, not gullibility</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-people-embrace-conspiracy-theories-its-about-community-not-gullibility-262276</link><description>Far from being isolated outsiders, conspiracy theorists enjoy thriving communities that recruit and organise activism.</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 12:09:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eating disorder symptoms in teens can be traced back to family hardship, new study shows</title><link>https://theconversation.com/eating-disorder-symptoms-in-teens-can-be-traced-back-to-family-hardship-new-study-shows-263529</link><description>It’s a stereotype that eating disorders mainly affect people from wealthy backgrounds.</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 01:28:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Burnt out and radicalised: how workplace exhaustion breeds extremist thinking – new study</title><link>https://theconversation.com/burnt-out-and-radicalised-how-workplace-exhaustion-breeds-extremist-thinking-new-study-261123</link><description>Our research found a link between burnout and support for extremist violence.</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 08:28:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Defendants in sexual assault cases are just as likely to misremember the event as alleged victims – new study</title><link>https://theconversation.com/defendants-in-sexual-assault-cases-are-just-as-likely-to-misremember-the-event-as-alleged-victims-new-study-262841</link><description>In court, scrutiny is normally focused on the alleged victim’s ability to recall details from the event.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 10:05:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Phubbing’: why ignoring your partner for your phone infuriates certain people – and causes them to retaliate</title><link>https://theconversation.com/phubbing-why-ignoring-your-partner-for-your-phone-infuriates-certain-people-and-causes-them-to-retaliate-263963</link><description>Research shows that ‘phubbing’ – ignoring a partner to look at your phone – can lower relationship satisfaction and spark retaliation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 10:50:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why scammers fake illness for cash, according to a psychologist</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-scammers-fake-illness-for-cash-according-to-a-psychologist-263264</link><description>What type of person lies to friends and family about having cancer?</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 20:03:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What does it mean to become an adult? In Namibia, it’s caring for others</title><link>https://theconversation.com/what-does-it-mean-to-become-an-adult-in-namibia-its-caring-for-others-263223</link><description>There is no single way of becoming an adult in the world.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 13:53:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>65,000 Pennsylvania kids have a parent in prison or jail − here’s what research says about the value of in-person visits</title><link>https://theconversation.com/65-000-pennsylvania-kids-have-a-parent-in-prison-or-jail-heres-what-research-says-about-the-value-of-in-person-visits-262185</link><description>In-person visits in prisons and jails can strengthen family relationships and reduce recidivism.</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 12:28:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What we’ve learned about narcissism over the past 30 years</title><link>https://theconversation.com/what-weve-learned-about-narcissism-over-the-past-30-years-258505</link><description>Narcissism is a picture that includes insecurity, emotional sensitivity and surprising fragility.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 14:27:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mass hysteria at Heathrow airport – how social contagion works</title><link>https://theconversation.com/mass-hysteria-at-heathrow-airport-how-social-contagion-works-264900</link><description>Heathrow’s Terminal 4 evacuation shows the power of social contagion.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:02:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How our minds trick us into thinking we are being greener than we really are</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-our-minds-trick-us-into-thinking-we-are-being-greener-than-we-really-are-263959</link><description>Adding “green” products to your food basket doesn’t reduce its carbon footprint – even though we think it does.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:37:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Telling incoming aliens from space rocks… on a scale of 1 to 10!</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735601-600-telling-incoming-aliens-from-space-rocks-on-a-scale-of-1-to-10/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Feedback is mystified by a new way to assess interstellar visitors and the risks they pose, be they lumps of ice or alien craft. Just pray they don’t top out on the Loeb Scale</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Racism isn’t innate – here are five psychological stages that may lead to it</title><link>https://theconversation.com/racism-isnt-innate-here-are-five-psychological-stages-that-may-lead-to-it-264391</link><description>There is no genetic or biological basis for dividing the human race into distinct “races.”</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The real scientific insights from Bryan Johnson’s immortality quest</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495156-the-real-scientific-insights-from-bryan-johnsons-immortality-quest/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Tech millionaire turned longevity pioneer Bryan Johnson devotes more than 6 hours a day to trialling different methods to turn back the clock. Can the rest of us learn anything from his radical approach?</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:01 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What’s the secret to living well beyond the average life expectancy?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495136-whats-the-secret-to-living-well-beyond-the-average-life-expectancy/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Many of us know people who live into their 90s, but hardly anyone makes it to 100. Studies are now revealing that factors that really make a difference</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:11 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How to nurture the right mindset for living to 100</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495108-how-to-nurture-the-right-mindset-for-living-to-100/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>It’s not just diet and exercise that governs how well you age. Your mindset, social connections and sense of purpose make a big difference, and it’s never too late to start working on them</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:13 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Why caring for your microbiome is crucial if you want to live to 100</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494981-why-caring-for-your-microbiome-is-crucial-if-you-want-to-live-to-100/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Our friendly – and not so friendly – gut bacteria lie at the core of healthy ageing. Research is now revealing what it takes to maintain a youthful microbiome</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:48 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The exercises you need to do to reach 100 in great shape</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494852-the-exercises-you-need-to-do-to-reach-100-in-great-shape/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>To be truly fit in older age, you need to work on specific aspects of your fitness – and research shows that it’s never too late to reap the benefits</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The science revealing how the right diet can add a decade to your life</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494953-the-science-revealing-how-the-right-diet-can-add-a-decade-to-your-life/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Evidence shows that eating a longevity diet can dramatically lengthen your lifespan – and the sooner you start, the more of a difference it makes</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:57 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>30,000-year-old toolkit shows what ancient hunter carried in a pouch</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496225-30000-year-old-toolkit-shows-what-ancient-hunter-carried-in-a-pouch/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A set of 29 stone tools, including blades and points for hunting, butchering and cutting wood, were found neatly arranged as if carried in a leather pouch that decayed</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 19:01:13 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Serious mental illness often brings rapid weight gain – but support is missing</title><link>https://theconversation.com/serious-mental-illness-often-brings-rapid-weight-gain-but-support-is-missing-264842</link><description>People with schizophrenia and bipolar disorder gain 5kg in five years. The average person gains 1.5kg.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 09:24:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Impostor syndrome: the cost of being ‘superwoman’ at work and beyond</title><link>https://theconversation.com/impostor-syndrome-the-cost-of-being-superwoman-at-work-and-beyond-265218</link><description>Female leaders are under pressure to excel, professionally and personally, without showing weakness or strain. The emergence of neoliberal feminism helps explain why, and a milestone in psychology describes what can result.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 10:22:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Steven Pinker’s new book shows how he’s become a contradictory figure</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735610-200-steven-pinkers-new-book-shows-how-hes-become-a-contradictory-figure/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Steven Pinker’s new book When Everyone Knows That Everyone Knows makes a compelling case for common knowledge. Shame the politics muddies the waters</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A radical idea to fix plastics recycling</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735611-900-a-radical-idea-to-fix-plastics-recycling/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Making all shampoo or detergent bottles look the same isn't anti-capitalist, and it's the only way to make a truly circular economy for plastics, says Saabira Chaudhuri</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Where’s my jetpack got to? And other sci-fi tech queries</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735610-100-wheres-my-jetpack-got-to-and-other-sci-fi-tech-queries/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>We are still waiting for the retro-futuristic tech and social revolutions envisioned in science fiction’s old gold, writes Annalee Newitz – not to mention advances in reproduction</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Ian McEwan’s new novel weaves climate change into literary mystery</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735610-500-ian-mcewans-new-novel-weaves-climate-change-into-literary-mystery/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Ian McEwan’s excellent What We Can Know is set in a UK largely swallowed up by rising seas. Emily H. Wilson explores the story of a scholar hunting a great lost poem – which may have something to with climate change</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Three simple rules for a great post-workout meal</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735610-800-three-simple-rules-for-a-great-post-workout-meal/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Taking care of your body’s nutritional needs after training doesn't have to be a headache. Grace Wade sums up three key pillars she uses to refuel with confidence</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Dramatic photos show bid to save the Javan slow loris</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735612-000-dramatic-photos-show-bid-to-save-the-javan-slow-loris/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The photos tell an unusual rescue story – the release of the critically endangered Javan slow lorises into Ujung Kulon National Park on Java Island, Indonesia, last month.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Vitamin D supplements may lower your level of one type of vitamin D</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496879-vitamin-d-supplements-may-lower-your-level-of-one-type-of-vitamin-d/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Taking vitamin D2 supplements seems to reduce levels of vitamin D3 in our body</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:01:51 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Simple menu tweak can nudge people into choosing climate-friendly food</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496570-simple-menu-tweak-can-nudge-people-into-choosing-climate-friendly-food/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Rejigging the meal choices on offer in a canteen can prompt people to make healthier, climate-friendlier decisions</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 09:00:10 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Quantum computers are finally on the verge of being useful</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496013-quantum-computers-are-finally-on-the-verge-of-being-useful/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Two experiments with different quantum computers showcase their growing ability to simulate materials and quantum matter that have so far proven elusive in the lab</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:00:29 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Curious kids: why do we dream?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/curious-kids-why-do-we-dream-264817</link><description>Why scientists still can’t agree what dreams are for.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 12:09:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Some viruses like to cheat – and that may be good for our health</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496881-some-viruses-like-to-cheat-and-that-may-be-good-for-our-health/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Mutations can result in viruses that infect cells, but can't copy themselves without help from other viruses - now it seems these cheats may outnumber normal viruses in a third of influenza cases, reducing the severity of infections</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:00:41 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Stunning amber deposits hold insects from the time of the dinosaurs</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496954-stunning-amber-deposits-hold-insects-from-the-time-of-the-dinosaurs/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A sand quarry in Ecuador has yielded South America’s first amber with bio-inclusions, including a spider's web and a collection of mosquitoes, beetles, flies, wasps and biting midges that lived 112 million years ago</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:00:23 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Starting HRT in early menopause may reduce women's risk of Alzheimer's</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496596-starting-hrt-in-early-menopause-may-reduce-womens-risk-of-alzheimers/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Hormone replacement therapy used within five years of the onset of menopause is associated with a lower risk of Alzheimer’s disease, while starting it later in life is associated with an increased risk</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:36:30 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Does ASMR really help with anxiety? A psychology expert explains the evidence</title><link>https://theconversation.com/does-asmr-really-help-with-anxiety-a-psychology-expert-explains-the-evidence-252181</link><description>The autonomous sensory meridian response may be linked to certain personality types and traits such as introversion.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:26:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>7 things we can do today to meet Australia’s new climate goal</title><link>https://theconversation.com/7-things-we-can-do-today-to-meet-australias-new-climate-goal-265023</link><description>Australia has the technologies to meet and exceed its new emissions target. The work now is to ensure they’re deployed at scale.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 03:39:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Quantum computers have finally achieved unconditional supremacy</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496944-quantum-computers-have-finally-achieved-unconditional-supremacy/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>For the first time, researchers have mathematically proven that a quantum computer needs less computational power to solve a particular task than an ordinary computer, in a way that can never be beaten</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:00:46 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Naming and categorizing objects is part of how young kids develop executive function skills – new research</title><link>https://theconversation.com/naming-and-categorizing-objects-is-part-of-how-young-kids-develop-executive-function-skills-new-research-255943</link><description>Kids with good executive function tend to grow up to be financially stable, healthy, productive adults. Past attempts to teach these skills have flopped. New brain research on language may change that.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 12:39:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Where you store fat may influence the effect it has on your brain</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496947-where-you-store-fat-may-influence-the-effect-it-has-on-your-brain/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Data from more than 18,000 people suggests that where excess fat is stored in the body influences its effects on brain structure, activity and health</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:55:22 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Atmospheric hydrogen is rising, which may be a problem for the climate</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497053-atmospheric-hydrogen-is-rising-which-may-be-a-problem-for-the-climate/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Ice core records of atmospheric hydrogen reveal a huge rise in concentration since the Industrial Revolution which has contributed to global warming – and could sway the debate over hydrogen as a fuel</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:31:33 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>One blood sample could reveal the age of 11 of your organs and systems</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497154-one-blood-sample-could-reveal-the-age-of-11-of-your-organs-and-systems/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The rate that our heart or liver ages may differ from that of our immune or hormonal systems, and now it seems that a single blood test could break that down</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 17:00:24 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Unforgeable quantum money can be stored in an ultracold ‘debit card’</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497081-unforgeable-quantum-money-can-be-stored-in-an-ultracold-debit-card/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Using the quantum states of particles of light as currency could make for unforgeable transactions, and a new experiment has added a way to save some of that quantum money for future use, too</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>New research shows Black Summer’s megafires left lasting scars far beyond property damage</title><link>https://theconversation.com/new-research-shows-black-summers-megafires-left-lasting-scars-far-beyond-property-damage-264195</link><description>The study found poorer communities, renters and women carried the heaviest burdens long after the Black Summer fires were put out.</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 19:35:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>With 2035 emissions targets set, what Australia does next will help shape global efforts to keep 1.5°C alive</title><link>https://theconversation.com/with-2035-emissions-targets-set-what-australia-does-next-will-help-shape-global-efforts-to-keep-1-5-c-alive-265665</link><description>Australia’s new emission target comes amid worrying signs of backsliding on climate action. As global leaders gather at the UN, Australia can play a role.</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 19:36:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is reading always better for your brain than listening to audiobooks?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497112-is-reading-always-better-for-your-brain-than-listening-to-audiobooks/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Reading books and listening to audiobooks tap into different elements of cognition, each with their own benefits. So which one should you choose, and when?</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:00:40 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Cutting down the Amazon will bring extreme rain, wind and heat</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497158-cutting-down-the-amazon-will-bring-extreme-rain-wind-and-heat/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>We used to think that deforestation in the Amazon would dry out the local climate, but the effects may be even more extreme and varied</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:28:43 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Why are there so many protests? The US public is highly polarized, and that drives people to act</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-are-there-so-many-protests-the-us-public-is-highly-polarized-and-that-drives-people-to-act-263021</link><description>Anger at the other side, as represented by the political party opposing yours, is a powerful motivator to engage in protests.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 12:15:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How users can make their AI companions feel real – from picking personality traits to creating fan art</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-users-can-make-their-ai-companions-feel-real-from-picking-personality-traits-to-creating-fan-art-265442</link><description>The strong bonds that users are forming with their AI chatbots rest on the human imagination at work.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 12:17:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How US-UK tech deal could yield significant benefits for the British public – expert Q&amp;A</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-us-uk-tech-deal-could-yield-significant-benefits-for-the-british-public-expert-qanda-265707</link><description>The £150bn package could yield real benefits in public health, as well as other areas of technology.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 13:16:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A deeper understanding of endometriosis is suggesting new treatments</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496240-a-deeper-understanding-of-endometriosis-is-suggesting-new-treatments/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The revelation that&amp;nbsp;endometriosis is linked to autoimmune disorders is opening up a whole new way to treat this painful and poorly understood condition</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:00:29 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Venus has lava tubes, and they're weird</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497220-venus-has-lava-tubes-and-theyre-weird/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>It has been suggested that lava tubes - underground tunnels carved out by molten rock - might be on Venus, and now we have direct evidence that this is the case</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:36:36 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>AI use by UK justice system risks papering over the cracks caused by years of underfunding</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-use-by-uk-justice-system-risks-papering-over-the-cracks-caused-by-years-of-underfunding-264749</link><description>The justice system is suffering from underfunding and AI won’t solve all the problems.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:16:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI and credit: How can we keep machines from reproducing social biases?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-and-credit-how-can-we-keep-machines-from-reproducing-social-biases-257756</link><description>Can we move from algorithmic discrimination to inclusive finance?</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dangerous climate change threatens Northern Australia’s big ‘food bowl’ dreams</title><link>https://theconversation.com/dangerous-climate-change-threatens-northern-australias-big-food-bowl-dreams-265727</link><description>Big plans are afoot to turn Northern Australia into Asia’s “food bowl”. But the reality of climate change can’t be ignored.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 20:19:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Close relatives of emperor penguins lived in NZ some 3 million years ago. What caused their extinction?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/close-relatives-of-emperor-penguins-lived-in-nz-some-3-million-years-ago-what-caused-their-extinction-265585</link><description>Great penguins once lived in much warmer waters, but then retreated to the Southern Ocean. In a warming world, they might be able to shift their range again.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 23:27:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fish ‘fingerprints’ in the ocean reveal which species are moving homes due to climate change</title><link>https://theconversation.com/fish-fingerprints-in-the-ocean-reveal-which-species-are-moving-homes-due-to-climate-change-264683</link><description>Tracking these shifts is crucial for understanding how climate change is transforming our oceans.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 23:47:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What happens when AI comes to the cotton fields</title><link>https://theconversation.com/what-happens-when-ai-comes-to-the-cotton-fields-261526</link><description>AI can help farmers be more effective and sustainable, but its use varies from state to state. A project in Georgia aims to bring the technology to the state’s cotton farmers.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 12:49:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air quality analysis reveals minimal changes after xAI data center opens in pollution-burdened Memphis neighborhood</title><link>https://theconversation.com/air-quality-analysis-reveals-minimal-changes-after-xai-data-center-opens-in-pollution-burdened-memphis-neighborhood-265152</link><description>Analysis of the air quality data available for southwest Memphis finds that pollution has long been quite bad, but the turbines powering an xAI data center have not made it much worse.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 12:50:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Long Road to an RSV Antibody to Protect the Most Vulnerable</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/a-long-road-to-an-rsv-antibody-to-protect-the-most-vulnerable/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tragic RSV vaccine trials in the 1960s set the field back for decades. Here&amp;rsquo;s how scientists finally made breakthroughs in RSV immunization&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Fight to End Childhood RSV in Indian Country</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-fight-to-end-childhood-rsv-in-indian-country/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;American Indian and Alaska Native infants experience the highest rates of RSV-related hospitalization in the U.S., but a breakthrough immunization is helping to close the gap&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Indigenous Storytelling Is Transforming RSV Care in Native Communities</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-indigenous-storytelling-is-transforming-rsv-care-in-native-communities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Abigail Echo-Hawk, a preeminent Native American public health expert, discusses RSV, &amp;ldquo;data genocide&amp;rdquo; and positive change driven by Indigenous storytelling&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Global Burden of RSV</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-global-burden-of-rsv/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) continues to affect infants and older and immunocompromised people around the world. These graphics reveal where the burden lies and what the effects of immunizations are&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New RSV Preventives Dramatically Reduce Infant Illness and Death</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/new-rsv-preventatives-dramatically-reduce-infant-illness-and-death/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The year 2023 marked the debut of groundbreaking innovations to prevent severe RSV infections in infants. Now protected babies are way less likely to develop severe infections or to end up in the ICU&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Promise of RSV Prevention</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-promise-of-rsv-prevention/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;RSV is the leading cause of infant hospitalizations in the U.S. But that could soon change as research advances lead to new preventive drugs for everyone&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Final RSV Frontier Is within Reach</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-final-rsv-frontier-is-within-reach/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The journey toward an RSV vaccine for children has been wrought with tragedy and setbacks. But six decades after scientists embarked on that path, they are nearing the finish line&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hints of exotic dark matter particles could be hiding in LHC data</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497100-hints-of-exotic-dark-matter-particles-could-be-hiding-in-lhc-data/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Particles similar to axions, the leading candidate for dark matter that has long eluded detection, may have already been created in particle colliders – and remained hidden in the data</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:00:17 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The truth about narcissists: How to handle them, and can they change?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496324-the-truth-about-narcissists-how-to-handle-them-and-can-they-change/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Although narcissistic personality disorder is rarer than you might think, psychological research suggests it can come in two different types, one of which may be underdiagnosed</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:00:23 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Dinosaur found with a crocodile in its jaws named as new species</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497299-dinosaur-found-with-a-crocodile-in-its-jaws-named-as-new-species/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A fossil from about 66 million years ago reveals a species of dinosaur that is new to science, with claws that would have ripped through its prey's flesh</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:00:45 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The US-UK tech prosperity deal carries promise but also peril for the general public</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-us-uk-tech-prosperity-deal-carries-promise-but-also-peril-for-the-general-public-265728</link><description>The deliberate alignment of AI systems with the values of corporations and individuals could sour the investment.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 16:17:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Moon Is Rusting—Thanks to ‘Wind’ Blown from Earth</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-moon-is-rusting-thanks-to-wind-blown-from-earth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lunar minerals can rust when bombarded with high-energy oxygen particles, experiments show&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mapping the structure of the brain doesn't fully explain its function</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497291-mapping-the-structure-of-the-brain-doesnt-fully-explain-its-function/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Comparing a map of the neurons in a nematode worm - the connectome - with a map of how signals travel across those neurons has revealed a surprising number of differences, suggesting that the structure of the brain alone doesn't explain how it works</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 19:00:37 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What we know, and don't, about the link between painkillers and autism</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497384-what-we-know-and-dont-about-the-link-between-painkillers-and-autism/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Scientific evidence is lacking to support the US government’s decisions to caution against using a common painkiller in pregnancy and fast-track the approval of an experimental medication for autism</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 21:30:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Spectacle, weirdness and novelty: what early cinema tells us about the appeal of ‘AI slop’</title><link>https://theconversation.com/spectacle-weirdness-and-novelty-what-early-cinema-tells-us-about-the-appeal-of-ai-slop-265071</link><description>Just as the gimmicky first films evolved into a sophisticated medium, will we look back on today’s AI-generated video as the beginnings of a new art form?</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 01:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>We Can Stop Teen Suicide</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/we-can-stop-teen-suicide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By understanding warning signs and talking to your child, parents can help reduce the risk of teen suicide&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mary Roach’s New Book Replaceable You Explores Challenges in Replacing Body Parts</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/mary-roachs-new-book-replaceable-you-explores-challenges-in-replacing-body/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mary Roach unpacks the millennia-long effort to replace failing body parts&amp;mdash;and the reasons that modern medicine still struggles to match the original designs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquakes Release Energy Mostly Through Heat, Not Ground Shaking</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/earthquakes-release-energy-mostly-through-heat-not-ground-shaking/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Up to 98 percent of the energy of an earthquake goes into flash heating rocks, not shaking the ground, new research shows. The finding could help yield better earthquake forecasts&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Ganges River is drying faster than ever – here’s what it means for the region and the world</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-ganges-river-is-drying-faster-than-ever-heres-what-it-means-for-the-region-and-the-world-265891</link><description>Climate change and overuse are creating a crisis for south Asia’s most important river.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:10:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How researchers are making precision agriculture more affordable</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-researchers-are-making-precision-agriculture-more-affordable-265366</link><description>Researchers have developed a tool that allows farmers to quickly and affordably test soil samples, get results in real-time, and obtain fertilizer recommendations.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 15:55:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World’s oldest person had a young microbiome and 'exceptional genome'</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497328-worlds-oldest-person-had-a-young-microbiome-and-exceptional-genome/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Scientists have studied the genetics and lifestyle factors that enabled María Branyas Morera, officially the oldest person in the world until she died last year, to reach 117 years old</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:00:05 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How faster-than-light explosions could reveal the universe’s secrets</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495828-how-faster-than-light-explosions-could-reveal-the-universes-secrets/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Some things we see in space appear to outpace light. Now we are learning to harness these bizarre optical illusions to understand the mysteries of neutron stars, gamma ray bursts and more</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:00:24 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Device with 6100 qubits is a step towards largest quantum computer yet</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497439-device-with-6100-qubits-is-a-step-towards-largest-quantum-computer-yet/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>An array of 6100 ultracold caesium atoms controlled by lasers is the largest collection of qubits ever assembled, and researchers hope they can soon turn it into the world's most advanced quantum computer</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:00:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>America’s Zombie Democracy</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/america-authoritarian-regime-ai-suicide/684350/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Its trappings remain, but authoritarianism and AI are hollowing out our humanity.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:33:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>We can avoid the agonising wait for advances in women's healthcare</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735623-000-we-can-avoid-the-agonising-wait-for-advances-in-womens-healthcare/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Simply listening to the experiences of women with conditions such as endometriosis will help to end the long-standing inequalities they face when it comes to medical progress</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Two climate scientists on how to use emotion in the climate crisis</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735620-400-two-climate-scientists-on-how-to-use-emotion-in-the-climate-crisis/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>From anger to hope, Kate Marvel and Tim Lenton explain how to tackle the tricky feelings aroused by climate change and harness them to take action</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Are you an introvert or extrovert? Surprisingly, the answer is neither</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735622-700-are-you-an-introvert-or-extrovert-surprisingly-the-answer-is-neither/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>We are quick to place ourselves on the extremes of the social spectrum, but the truth is that personality is more malleable than you think, says Claudia Canavan</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How Taylor Swift is helping botany gain celebrity status</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735622-900-how-taylor-swift-is-helping-botany-gain-celebrity-status/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Feedback is delighted to learn that researchers have discovered what Taylor Swift is accidentally doing to rescue the science of plants from mid-ness. Just take a look at her videos – sorry, botany teaching aids</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What made solar power the most desirable energy source on the planet?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735622-800-what-made-solar-power-the-most-desirable-energy-source-on-the-planet/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>In this latest instalment of Future Chronicles, an imagined history of future inventions, Rowan Hooper explains how the creation of living solar panels transformed their impact on the world</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A compelling book about the end of the Neanderthals is a rare treat</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735620-500-a-compelling-book-about-the-end-of-the-neanderthals-is-a-rare-treat/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Forget the tropes about how violence or maybe volcanic eruptions killed off our ancient cousins, The Last Neanderthal by Ludovic Slimak offers a very different take on how they died out</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazing images expose inner world of mind-blowing plants and fungi</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735620-300-amazing-images-expose-inner-world-of-mind-blowing-plants-and-fungi/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Surreal images from a new book, Microcosms, show how confocal microscopy that uses laser scanning creates a super-sharp new journey around mind-altering plants and fungi</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>If you feel you don't really belong, here is some science-based advice</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735621-000-if-you-feel-you-dont-really-belong-here-is-some-science-based-advice/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Thinking you don’t fit in is agonising, whether you are starting at university or changing jobs. Our advice columnist, David Robson, shares some tips to change how you feel</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>We finally found the hot wind coming out of our black hole</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497671-we-finally-found-the-hot-wind-coming-out-of-our-black-hole/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Since the 1970s, astronomers have predicted that Sagittarius A*, the supermassive black hole at the centre of the Milky Way, should be sending out hot wind – they have just caught the first glimpse of it</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 20:01:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What Is Leucovorin, the Unproven Autism Drug Backed by Trump Officials?</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/what-is-leucovorin-the-unproven-autism-drug-backed-by-trump-officials/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration is backing leucovorin as a treatment for autism, despite limited evidence. Some doctors and researchers are concerned&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine’s Plan to Starve the Russian War Machine</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/ukraines-strategy-to-win-the-war/684356/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Negotiations have stalled. Trump keeps changing his policies. Ukrainians, backed by Europeans, are taking matters into their own hands. ​​​</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 15:25:32 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Goodbye petrostates, hello ‘electrostates’: how the clean energy shift is reshaping the world order</title><link>https://theconversation.com/goodbye-petrostates-hello-electrostates-how-the-clean-energy-shift-is-reshaping-the-world-order-264267</link><description>The global shift toward renewable energy is challenging old geopolitical power structures. So where does Australia stand?</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:31:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Huntington’s disease breakthrough: what to know about the gene therapy</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497677-huntingtons-disease-breakthrough-what-to-know-about-the-gene-therapy/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Huntington’s disease has been successfully treated for the first time using a gene therapy, which may be available in the US as soon as next year</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 22:07:17 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Nightmare Bacteria’ Infections Spiking, Leaving Key Carbapenem Antibiotics Useless, CDC Warns</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/nightmare-bacteria-infections-spiking-leaving-key-carbapenem-antibiotics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The infection rate of one type of carbapenem-resistant Enterobacterales bacteria has risen by more than 460 percent in recent years. Scientists say people receiving treatment in hospitals are at highest risk&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Could we have cracked one of the world's toughest climate problems?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497594-could-we-have-cracked-one-of-the-worlds-toughest-climate-problems/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>It is almost impossible to make cement without emissions, but carbon-capture-and-storage technology is finally being deployed to decarbonise the sector</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 01:01:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Digital brains’ that ‘think’ and ‘feel’: why do we personify AI models, and are these metaphors actually helpful?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/digital-brains-that-think-and-feel-why-do-we-personify-ai-models-and-are-these-metaphors-actually-helpful-265883</link><description>Metaphors help us understand complexity, but they can also be dangerous, or even misleading.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 08:49:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate change is making trees grow larger in the Amazon rainforest</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497707-climate-change-is-making-trees-grow-larger-in-the-amazon-rainforest/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Rising carbon dioxide levels have boosted the growth of trees in the Amazon rainforest over the past few decades, but it is unclear if this trend will continue</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 11:00:04 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Grattan on Friday: As the government rejects Trump’s stands, Liberal leadership aspirant Andrew Hastie sounds decidedly Trumpian</title><link>https://theconversation.com/grattan-on-friday-as-the-government-rejects-trumps-stands-liberal-leadership-aspirant-andrew-hastie-sounds-decidedly-trumpian-265860</link><description>The prime minister avoided any major pitfalls during his week in the US. Back at home, the Liberal party’s infighting has shown no signs of stopping.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:06:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bird Flu and Human Flu Viruses Could Mix in Cow Udders and Spark a Pandemic</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/bird-flu-and-human-flu-viruses-could-mix-in-cow-udders-and-spark-a-pandemic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Cells in cow udders could act as a site for human flu and bird flu viruses to swap genes and generate dangerous novel strains&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lower Than Cowards</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/freedom-trump-threats-kimmel/684358/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The surrender of America’s elites</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 07:31:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Good Conversations Don’t Require Everybody to Agree, Neuroscience Shows</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/good-conversations-dont-require-everybody-to-agree-neuroscience-shows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Brain imaging is illuminating the patterns linked to productive, positive dialogue&lt;b&gt;,&lt;/b&gt; and those insights could help people connect with others&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cheetahs naturally turned into mummies in caves in Saudi Arabia</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497320-cheetahs-naturally-turned-into-mummies-in-caves-in-saudi-arabia/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The constant temperature and low humidity of a cave network in Saudi Arabia turned cheetahs, some of which died thousands of years ago, into mummies</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:00:12 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Rivers are heating up faster than the air − that’s a problem for aquatic life and people</title><link>https://theconversation.com/rivers-are-heating-up-faster-than-the-air-thats-a-problem-for-aquatic-life-and-people-263718</link><description>River heat waves are rising faster than the pace of air heat waves. That’s a problem for fish, drinking water quality, and food and energy production.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:19:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks retreat from climate change commitments – but it’s business more than politics</title><link>https://theconversation.com/banks-retreat-from-climate-change-commitments-but-its-business-more-than-politics-265176</link><description>The Net-Zero Banking Alliance, intended to curb lending to carbon-intensive sectors, wasn’t effective and more importantly never made much business sense.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:20:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The science of defiance: A psychology researcher explains why people comply – and how to resist</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-science-of-defiance-a-psychology-researcher-explains-why-people-comply-and-how-to-resist-264567</link><description>You don’t need to be a rebel to defy. Defiance isn’t about personality, it’s a practice – one that’s becoming essential in workplaces, politics and everyday life.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:22:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4 films that show how humans can fortify – or botch – their relationship with AI</title><link>https://theconversation.com/4-films-that-show-how-humans-can-fortify-or-botch-their-relationship-with-ai-263603</link><description>From 1980s sci-fi films to today’s blockbusters, filmmakers have wrestled with questions about what happens when humans rely on intelligent machines.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:23:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Does vagus nerve stimulation work? A scientific cure-all explained.</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/what-is-vagus-nerve-stimulation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From treating seizures to depression, stimulating the body's longest nerve has real benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/what-is-vagus-nerve-stimulation/"&gt;Does vagus nerve stimulation work? A scientific cure-all explained.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>AI in Africa: 5 issues that must be tackled for digital equality</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-in-africa-5-issues-that-must-be-tackled-for-digital-equality-265611</link><description>Policy-makers must grapple with an uncomfortable truth: without deliberate action, AI will magnify global divides.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:36:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why September 27, 2025 is the ‘coolest mathematical date of our lifetime’</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/september-27-math-date/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Get ready for a whacky series of numerical coincidences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/september-27-math-date/"&gt;Why September 27, 2025 is the &amp;#8216;coolest mathematical date of our lifetime&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:06:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Nanoparticles may be the secret ingredient in making ultimate plastics</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497683-nanoparticles-may-be-the-secret-ingredient-in-making-ultimate-plastics/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Mixing nanoparticles into some common plastics made them harder to break and possibly easier to process, pointing towards a way to make better materials or packaging</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:41:37 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>3D-printed skin stretches, bleeds like the real thing</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/3d-printed-skin-bleeds/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capsules embedded between layers of this fake tissue simulate human blood and pus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/3d-printed-skin-bleeds/"&gt;3D-printed skin stretches, bleeds like the real thing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:47:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelensky says a destructive drone arms race looms – but dystopia isn’t inevitable</title><link>https://theconversation.com/zelensky-says-a-destructive-drone-arms-race-looms-but-dystopia-isnt-inevitable-263644</link><description>The new age of drones and AI may be terrifying, but there are reasons for thinking the dystopian possibilities of future war will be contained.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:24:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>If I Work Harder, Will You Love Me?</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/workaholic-love-practical-solutions/684353/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The tragedy of workaholism is the false belief that you can trade toil for affection. Knowing that is the first step to recovery.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Cat owners donate more money than dog owners</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/cat-owners-donate-more-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An analysis of nearly $70 billion in donations showed feline lovers contributed slightly more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/cat-owners-donate-more-money/"&gt;Cat owners donate more money than dog owners&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:27:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Punch Cards, Pipeline Problems, and the Future of Women in Computing</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/punch-cards-pipeline-problems-and-the-future-of-women-in-computing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Carla Brodley, founding executive director of the Center for Inclusive Computing at Northeastern University, explains how to make computer science education more accessible to everyone&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alaska’s Fat Bear Week is more than a bit of fun – for the animals, size is a matter of survival</title><link>https://theconversation.com/alaskas-fat-bear-week-is-more-than-a-bit-of-fun-for-the-animals-size-is-a-matter-of-survival-266099</link><description>Bears need to put on fat in order to survive the harsh Alaskan winters.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:31:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vanishing waters in a warming world</title><link>https://theconversation.com/vanishing-waters-in-a-warming-world-266001</link><description>Bad news for the rivers and the lakes that we’re used to.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:31:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Walmart’s gaming PC clearance sale drops prices on laptops, desktops, graphics cards, and more</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/walmart-desktop-laptop-pc-gaming-deals-sale/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Whatever you need to upgrade your PC gaming experience, Walmart has it on sale right now. That includes laptops, desktops, graphics cards, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/walmart-desktop-laptop-pc-gaming-deals-sale/"&gt;Walmart&amp;#8217;s gaming PC clearance sale drops prices on laptops, desktops, graphics cards, and more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:50:42 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Taylor Swift’s Speech Pattern Changed over Time, Linguistics Study Shows</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/taylor-swift-speech-pattern-changed-over-time-linguistics-study-shows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An analysis of Taylor Swift&amp;rsquo;s interviews suggests her speech pattern has changed over her career&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Republicans Can Do If They Really Want to Protect Free Speech</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/republicans-free-speech-fcc/684359/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The best way to defend Americans’ expressive rights is to pass laws.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 14:05:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>12 astonishing images from the 2025 Astrophotography Prize Photographer of the Year</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/2025-astrophotography-prize-photographer-of-the-year-images/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A ‘tornado in space’ and the ISS shine in these inspiring examples of the best in astrophotography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/2025-astrophotography-prize-photographer-of-the-year-images/"&gt;12 astonishing images from the 2025 Astrophotography Prize Photographer of the Year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>WWI-Era Shipwrecks in Mallows Bay Form Ecological Sanctuary</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/wwi-era-shipwrecks-in-mallows-bay-form-ecological-sanctuary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly 100 years ago dozens of ships were abandoned in a shallow bay in the Potomac River. Today plants and animals are thriving on the skeletons of these vessels&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reconstructed skull gives surprising clues to our enigmatic Ancestor X</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497765-reconstructed-skull-gives-surprising-clues-to-our-enigmatic-ancestor-x/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The shared ancestor of our species, the Neanderthals and the Denisovans may be far older than we thought – which could completely change our understanding of humanity's evolution</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 20:00:46 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Apple AirPods Pro 3 earbuds first impressions: The rightful Air to the throne</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/apple-airpods-pro-3-true-wireless-anc-earbuds-first-impressions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Upgraded housings, drivers, eartips, and algorithms mean the Apple AirPods Pro 3 earbuds dig deeper and hold the stage better, improving noise isolation and sonic sensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/apple-airpods-pro-3-true-wireless-anc-earbuds-first-impressions/"&gt;Apple AirPods Pro 3 earbuds first impressions: The rightful Air to the throne&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:15:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>AI systems can easily lie and deceive us – a fact researchers are painfully aware of</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-systems-can-easily-lie-and-deceive-us-a-fact-researchers-are-painfully-aware-of-263531</link><description>In stress-testing AI models, it’s not hard to push them to the brink and make them threaten to harm humans.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:40:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Warn, hide or stand out? How colour in the animal world is a battle for survival</title><link>https://theconversation.com/warn-hide-or-stand-out-how-colour-in-the-animal-world-is-a-battle-for-survival-265670</link><description>A global experiment has helped explain why some animals use stealthy patterns to hide from predators, while others use warning colours to avoid being eaten.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>11 dolphins stranded in Cape Cod rescued by nonprofit</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/stranded-dolphins-rescued/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;‘These strandings happen fast, and every minute counts.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/stranded-dolphins-rescued/"&gt;11 dolphins stranded in Cape Cod rescued by nonprofit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:02:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Comey Indictment Is Not Just Payback</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/comey-indictment/684377/?utm_source=feed</link><description>It’s a glimpse of Trump’s next attempt to seize power.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 21:35:45 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Neuroscience and Art Collide in a Posthumous ‘Composition’ by Alvin Lucier in Revivification</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/neuroscience-and-art-collide-in-a-posthumous-composition-by-alvin-lucier-in/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A museum exhibit in Australia lets visitors hear music generated by brain cells derived from the blood of a dead composer.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asteroid ‘Families’ Reveal Solar System’s Secret History</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/asteroid-families-reveal-solar-systems-secret-history/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Many asteroids are related, but their family trees can be hard to trace&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Smallmouth Bass Evolve to Evade Electric Culling in Adirondack Lake</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/smallmouth-bass-evolve-to-evade-electric-culling-in-adirondack-lake/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists electrically culled invasive fish in a 20-year battle&amp;mdash;but the fish fought back with rapid evolution&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How fast you age may be controlled by a DNA repair boss in your cells</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497492-how-fast-you-age-may-be-controlled-by-a-dna-repair-boss-in-your-cells/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>When a key protein regulator dials down DNA repair mechanisms, our cells accumulate more mutations, which may cause us to age faster</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 12:00:17 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Atmospheric chaos has sent temperatures soaring in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497898-atmospheric-chaos-has-sent-temperatures-soaring-in-antarctica/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Stratospheric temperatures in Antarctica are spiking, which could see strange weather unfold across the southern hemisphere in the coming months</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 13:00:56 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk and the making of an AI-generated martyr</title><link>https://theconversation.com/charlie-kirk-and-the-making-of-an-ai-generated-martyr-265834</link><description>In a polarized environment, the elevation of a figure into a saint does more than honor the individual. It turns a political struggle into a sacred one.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 12:31:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Want knives? How to buy what people leave at airport security.</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/what-happens-to-tsa-confiscated-items/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to a very weird corner of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/what-happens-to-tsa-confiscated-items/"&gt;Want knives? How to buy what people leave at airport security.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Babies' brains 'tick' more slowly than ours, which may help them learn</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497755-babies-brains-tick-more-slowly-than-ours-which-may-help-them-learn/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The rhythm of an infant's brain activity seems to put them in constant learning mode, whereas that of an adult may allow them to retrieve conceptual knowledge</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Amateur paleontologist opens fossil museum in rural Minnesota</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/amateur-paleontologist-opens-fossil-museum-in-rural-minnesota/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jim Pollard is bringing bison bones, fossilized mammoth poop, and more to Blue Earth's 3,000 residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/amateur-paleontologist-opens-fossil-museum-in-rural-minnesota/"&gt;Amateur paleontologist opens fossil museum in rural Minnesota&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Did a star blow up and hit Earth 10 million years ago?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497946-did-a-star-blow-up-and-hit-earth-10-million-years-ago/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>There are signs deep beneath the Pacific Ocean that an exploding star once sent cosmic rays blasting out towards Earth, and now we have an idea of which stars may be to blame</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:09:42 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out Coway air purifiers for every room during this early Prime Day deal</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/coway-air-purifier-early-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon has Coway air purifiers for every home and budget on sale for their lowest prices of the year before the Prime Big Deal Days even get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/coway-air-purifier-early-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out Coway air purifiers for every room during this early Prime Day deal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:06:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Comey Indictment Is an Embarrassment</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/comey-indictment-trump-doj/684381/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The Justice Department should never have brought such a shoddy case.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:26:17 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Attack squirrel’ sends two people to the ER</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/attack-squirrel-california/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A friendly reminder to not feed wildlife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/attack-squirrel-california/"&gt;&amp;#8216;Attack squirrel&amp;#8217; sends two people to the ER&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:32:57 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How water fuels conflict in Pakistan</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-water-fuels-conflict-in-pakistan-262628</link><description>The potential of water to cause conflict is a live issue in Pakistan, with climate change only making matters worse.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:08:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novels with a certain structure are more likely to be classics</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497589-novels-with-a-certain-structure-are-more-likely-to-be-classics/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Novels need a gripping story to stay popular as the decades pass, but it seems that other less-obvious factors may also contribute to their lasting success</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 18:00:52 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Redesigned umbrella is smaller than an iPhone</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/small-umbrella-simprella/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The 'Simprella' weighs less than a few Snickers’ bars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/small-umbrella-simprella/"&gt;Redesigned umbrella is smaller than an iPhone&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 13:41:48 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>This ‘funny-looking rock’ holds 3,000 years of Iron Age secrets</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/iron-age-copper-breakthrough/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Experimenting with copper may have led to our eventual breakthroughs with making iron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/iron-age-copper-breakthrough/"&gt;This ‘funny-looking rock’ holds 3,000 years of Iron Age secrets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Lung inflammation may make traumatic events harder to forget</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497888-lung-inflammation-may-make-traumatic-events-harder-to-forget/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Severe lung inflammation has been linked to symptoms resembling post-traumatic stress disorder in mice, which could help us better treat and prevent the mental health condition</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 19:00:07 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The Emptiness of Attacking Critics for Their Hypocrisy</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/free-speech-cancel-culture-republicans/684382/?utm_source=feed</link><description>It’s hard to defend crackdowns on free speech. It’s easier to simply claim everyone’s doing it.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:17:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NIH Funds New Autism Studies on Genes and Environment as Trump Focuses on Tylenol</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/nih-funds-new-autism-studies-on-genes-and-environment-as-trump-focuses-on/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The National Institutes of Health is investing $50 million into research on genetic and environmental factors underlying autism&amp;mdash;news that was eclipsed by President Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s recent controversial claims about acetaminophen&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The tug-of-war between engineering and design to build the Hyundai Palisade XRT Pro</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/engineering-and-design-hyundai-palisade-xrt-pro/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The brand toughened up its popular family SUV, but first, the design and engineering team had to agree on the dimensions and recovery hook placement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/engineering-and-design-hyundai-palisade-xrt-pro/"&gt;The tug-of-war between engineering and design to build the Hyundai Palisade XRT Pro&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hurricane Humberto and Potential Tropical Storm Imelda Complicate Forecasts</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/hurricane-humberto-and-potential-tropical-storm-imelda-complicate-forecasts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hurricane Humberto and a system that may become Tropical Storm Imelda in the coming days are swirling quite close to each other in the western Atlantic Ocean&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 21:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The best powered bookshelf speakers for 2025, tested and reviewed</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/best-powered-bookshelf-speakers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Spin records, stream playlists, or score your next session—these all-in-one systems keep up wherever you set up, from your desktop to a bookshelf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/best-powered-bookshelf-speakers/"&gt;The best powered bookshelf speakers for 2025, tested and reviewed&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>I tried a sound bath to see if it actually made me calmer</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/do-sound-baths-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The science is still emerging, but I couldn’t deny how relaxed I felt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/do-sound-baths-work/"&gt;I tried a sound bath to see if it actually made me calmer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Nexstar and Sinclair Lost Their Game of Chicken</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/kimmel-response-local-tv-stations-abc-conflict/684388/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Broadcast-media companies may be growing, but they still couldn’t afford to reject Jimmy Kimmel forever.</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Lab-Grown Organoids Could Transform Female Reproductive Medicine</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/lab-grown-organoids-could-transform-female-reproductive-medicine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial tissues that mimic the placenta, endometrium, ovary and vagina could point to treatments for common conditions such as preeclampsia and endometriosis&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flying in an open-air, single-seat helicopter is a true test of nerves</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/mirocopter-flight-video/</link><description>&lt;p&gt; YouTuber Mark Rumsey documents his adventures in an extremely barebones Mirocopter SCH-2A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/mirocopter-flight-video/"&gt;Flying in an open-air, single-seat helicopter is a true test of nerves&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>6 fun photos to celebrate Sea Otter Awareness week</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/6-photos-sea-otter-awareness-week/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The furry mammals keep kelp forests going. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/6-photos-sea-otter-awareness-week/"&gt;6 fun photos to celebrate Sea Otter Awareness week&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Two-in-one inhalers slash asthma attacks among young children</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497635-two-in-one-inhalers-slash-asthma-attacks-among-young-children/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Inhalers that combine relieving breathlessness with preventing it seem to be the most effective option for reducing asthma attacks in young children</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 07:00:54 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>People Are More Likely to Cheat When They Use AI</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/people-are-more-likely-to-cheat-when-they-use-ai/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Participants in a new study were more likely to cheat when delegating to AI&amp;mdash;especially if they could encourage machines to break rules without explicitly asking for it&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Politicized Prosecutions May Hit a Roadblock</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/nullify-political-prosecution/684378/?utm_source=feed</link><description>When the president puts his political enemies on trial on pretextual grounds, jurors have the option of refusing to convict.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 07:31:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How to take every kind of photo on your iPhone</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/how-to-take-every-kind-of-photo-on-your-iphone/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple's phones are more versatile than you might have thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/how-to-take-every-kind-of-photo-on-your-iphone/"&gt;How to take every kind of photo on your iPhone&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>This humanoid robot can cartwheel surprisingly well</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/humanoid-robot-cartwheel/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Fourier’s N1 is an open-source bot designed to boost collaboration between universities, labs, and hobbyists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/humanoid-robot-cartwheel/"&gt;This humanoid robot can cartwheel surprisingly well&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Taking Tylenol While Pregnant Is Safer Than Untreated Fevers, Doctors Say</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/taking-tylenol-while-pregnant-is-safer-than-untreated-fevers-doctors-say/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Untreated fevers during pregnancy can cause more harm than taking acetaminophen will&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Generative AI might end up being worthless — and that could be a good thing</title><link>https://theconversation.com/generative-ai-might-end-up-being-worthless-and-that-could-be-a-good-thing-266046</link><description>GenAI does some neat, helpful things, but it’s not yet the engine of a new economy — and it might not ever be.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 17:03:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>You should wash your clothes with cold water</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/wash-your-clothes-with-cold-water/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Modern laundry detergents work better in cold water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/wash-your-clothes-with-cold-water/"&gt;You should wash your clothes with cold water&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>More people are using AI in court, not a lawyer. It could cost you money – and your case</title><link>https://theconversation.com/more-people-are-using-ai-in-court-not-a-lawyer-it-could-cost-you-money-and-your-case-264340</link><description>Researchers found more than 80 cases of generative AI use in Australian courts so far – mostly by people representing themselves. That comes with serious risks.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 19:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Transport will make or break Australia’s new climate plan – and time is running out to fix it</title><link>https://theconversation.com/transport-will-make-or-break-australias-new-climate-plan-and-time-is-running-out-to-fix-it-265986</link><description>Unless transport emissions are tackled head-on, Australia’s new climate target cannot be met.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 19:02:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Illiberal America, MAGA Edition</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/maga-cancel-culture-revenge-tactics/684296/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Republicans had real grievances with progressive orthodoxy—and are using them to justify drastic reprisals.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Endangered Sharks Caught in Rare Mating Ritual beneath the Waves</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/endangered-sharks-caught-in-rare-mating-ritual-beneath-the-waves/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Food and Drug Administration plans to update the safety label for acetaminophen products, and the strongest storm on Earth this year struck several countries in East and Southeast Asia.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Extraordinary pictures show what a common antibiotic does to E. coli</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498016-extraordinary-pictures-show-what-a-common-antibiotic-does-to-e-coli/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A commonly used class of antibiotics seems to kill bacteria like E. coli by breaking down their tough armour</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:33:29 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Weaver Ants Form Complex Chains to Pull More Than 100 Times Their Weight</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/weaver-ants-form-complex-chains-to-pull-more-than-100-times-their-weight/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When more humans are added to a team, each member accomplishes less work&amp;mdash;but teams of weaver ants do better and better as more join&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When the wheels come off: Lessons from Sonoma on racing, resilience, and engine oil</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/valvoline-restore-and-protect-nascar-f1-ev-data-center-performance-fluids/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I went to Sonoma for a NASCAR race and found out heat is the bad guy, fluids are the secret weapon, and Valvoline’s engineers are basically mad scientists with pit passes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/valvoline-restore-and-protect-nascar-f1-ev-data-center-performance-fluids/"&gt;When the wheels come off: Lessons from Sonoma on racing, resilience, and engine oil&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 07:55:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Ultracold clocks could reveal how quantum physics alters time</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497886-ultracold-clocks-could-reveal-how-quantum-physics-alters-time/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The world’s best clocks may be sensitive to an odd mix of quantum and relativistic effects that would stretch time and test the boundaries of physics</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:00:34 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Will AI make cheaper personalized insurance premiums possible? Here’s why it’s a slippery slope</title><link>https://theconversation.com/will-ai-make-cheaper-personalized-insurance-premiums-possible-heres-why-its-a-slippery-slope-262787</link><description>In this age of algorithms, personalized insurance is encountering legal limits, especially the ban on discrimination. Can we balance accurate pricing, solidarity, and fairness?</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:20:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EcoFlow DELTA 3 portable power station series first impressions: More power, more versatile</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/ecoflow-delta-3-max-plus-ultra-plus-portable-power-station-first-impressions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The EcoFlow Delta 3 Ultra Plus and Delta 3 Max Plus deliver plenty of power for camping and home backup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/ecoflow-delta-3-max-plus-ultra-plus-portable-power-station-first-impressions/"&gt;EcoFlow DELTA 3 portable power station series first impressions: More power, more versatile&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 08:55:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The radioactive ‘miracle water’ that killed its believers</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/radioactive-water/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the 1920s, Radithor promised to cure everything from wrinkles to leukemia, but its unintended results were deadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/radioactive-water/"&gt;The radioactive &amp;#8216;miracle water&amp;#8217; that killed its believers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Wild chimps consume the equivalent of two glasses of wine a day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/chimps-alcohol-study/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The 'drunken monkey hypothesis' could explain why humans like alcohol so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/chimps-alcohol-study/"&gt;Wild chimps consume the equivalent of two glasses of wine a day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 09:45:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The most important mathematician you’ve (probably) never heard of</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497097-the-most-important-mathematician-youve-probably-never-heard-of/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Alexander Grothendieck was a titan in his field, making deep connections that fuelled a revolution in mathematics, before giving it all up and disappearing. Jacob Aron explores what his work meant</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:24:37 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Sunken WWII bombs make a surprising home for sea life</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/wwii-bombs-sea-life-baltic-sea/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new study finds algae, mussels, and starfish flock to munitions dumped in the Baltic Sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/wwii-bombs-sea-life-baltic-sea/"&gt;Sunken WWII bombs make a surprising home for sea life&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Lifelong Star Wars fan builds the droids of his childhood dreams</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/kurt-zimmerman-star-wars-droids/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Kurt Zimmerman brought Star Wars from a galaxy far, far away to … Michigan.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/kurt-zimmerman-star-wars-droids/"&gt;Lifelong Star Wars fan builds the droids of his childhood dreams&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:15:47 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Fully MAGA-fied Christianity</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/charlie-kirk-christian-trump/684394/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Politics, especially culture-war politics, now provides many fundamentalists and evangelicals with a sense of community and a common enemy.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:16:31 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Cannabis extract found to be effective for lower back pain</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498064-cannabis-extract-found-to-be-effective-for-lower-back-pain/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A clinical trial has found that VER-01, a drug derived from cannabis, eases chronic lower back pain without serious side effects or signs of addiction</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:00:16 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Do black holes exist and, if not, what have we really been looking at?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496031-do-black-holes-exist-and-if-not-what-have-we-really-been-looking-at/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Black holes are so strange that physicists have long wondered if they are quite what they seem. Now we are set to find out if they are instead gravastars, fuzzballs or something else entirely</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:00:19 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Our brain 'swivels' to focus on sounds from different directions</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498050-our-brain-swivels-to-focus-on-sounds-from-different-directions/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Many mammals physically pivot their ears to hone in on a particular sound, and now it seems that a similar action takes place in our brain</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:00:32 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A second runway at Gatwick airport could improve efficiency and bring down fares – an economist’s view</title><link>https://theconversation.com/a-second-runway-at-gatwick-airport-could-improve-efficiency-and-bring-down-fares-an-economists-view-265995</link><description>Planes circling over busy airports waiting for a landing slot waste fuel and drive up costs.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:18:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New broccoli hybrid can thrive in colder climates</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/new-broccoli/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;90 percent of broccoli in the US is grown in California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/new-broccoli/"&gt;New broccoli hybrid can thrive in colder climates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:35:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How Hurricane Humberto Is Pulling Tropical Storm Imelda Away from the U.S.</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-hurricane-humberto-is-pulling-tropical-storm-imelda-away-from-the-u-s/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a version of the Fujiwhara effect, Hurricane Humberto is pulling Tropical Storm Imelda eastward and away from the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World’s first mushroom-powered toilet could replace stinky porta-potties</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/first-mushroom-powered-toilet/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Fungi flush out the odor in this pilot program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/first-mushroom-powered-toilet/"&gt;World&amp;#8217;s first mushroom-powered toilet could replace stinky porta-potties&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Marsh Will-o’-the-Wisps Sparked by Strange Chemistry</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/marsh-will-o-the-wisps-sparked-by-strange-chemistry/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A phenomenon called microlightning may explain ghostly blue marsh lights&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out Samsonite luggage, backapacks, and accessories for ridiculously low prices before Prime Day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/samsonite-suitcase-backpack-deals-amazon/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Grab some high-end luggage that will last for years with these absurdly cheap deals on Samsonite bags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/samsonite-suitcase-backpack-deals-amazon/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out Samsonite luggage, backapacks, and accessories for ridiculously low prices before Prime Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:15:22 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>We may finally know what causes will-o’-the-wisps</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498087-we-may-finally-know-what-causes-will-o-the-wisps/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Mysterious flashes of light seen in swamps and bogs could be caused by burning methane or other gases, ignited by sparks that fly between bubbles in water</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 21:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>15 gorgeous images from the 2025 Bird Photographer of the Year awards</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/2025-bird-photographer-of-the-year-awards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A soaring solar eclipse, a bloodied petrel, and a resilient raven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/2025-bird-photographer-of-the-year-awards/"&gt;15 gorgeous images from the 2025 Bird Photographer of the Year awards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 19:01:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>AI in the classroom is hard to detect – time to bring back oral tests</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-in-the-classroom-is-hard-to-detect-time-to-bring-back-oral-tests-265955</link><description>A chatbot can produce text, but it can’t sustain a probing conversation about your reasoning. Our work suggests oral assessment has a role in the age of AI.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venus fly traps’ death-grip trigger discovered</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/how-venus-fly-trap-close/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The carnivorous plants know when it's time to snatch their prey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/how-venus-fly-trap-close/"&gt;Venus fly traps’ death-grip trigger discovered&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Deep Sleep Is This Mammal’s Super Power</title><link>https://nautil.us/deep-sleep-is-this-mammals-super-power-1239714/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How a threatened Australian marsupial is thriving in the face of drought&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/deep-sleep-is-this-mammals-super-power-1239714/"&gt;Deep Sleep Is This Mammal’s Super Power&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Library for Fish Sounds</title><link>https://nautil.us/a-library-for-fish-sounds-1239697/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Can eavesdropping on the ocean help to save its creatures? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/a-library-for-fish-sounds-1239697/"&gt;A Library for Fish Sounds&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six New Gecko Species Discovered by Loud Barking Mating Calls</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/six-new-gecko-species-discovered-by-loud-barking-mating-calls/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists found new gecko species hidden in plain sight in pristine deserts of southern Africa, thanks to their loud, barking mating calls&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Myth of the Campus Snowflake</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/college-students-free-speech/684352/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The students I encounter as a university president aren’t afraid of free speech—quite the contrary.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Astronomers captured an incredible view of M87’s black hole jet</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498113-astronomers-captured-an-incredible-view-of-m87s-black-hole-jet/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The black hole at the centre of a galaxy more than 50 million light years away is spewing out a jet of extremely hot plasma – though we have studied it for a century, we are only now seeing it in great detail</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The Judaism I Thought I Knew</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/jewish-identity-anti-semitism/684397/?utm_source=feed</link><description>“I’m just a cultural Jew,” I would tell people, knowing nothing about Jewish culture.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How China’s New Emissions Pledge Could Radically Alter Climate Change</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-chinas-new-emissions-pledge-could-radically-alter-climate-change/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s plan to reduce greenhouse gases will largely determine the world&amp;rsquo;s emissions trajectory, researchers say&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Garmin fitness trackers and smartwatches are up to 45% off during Amazon’s early Prime Day deals</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/garmin-fitness-tracker-smartwatch-early-prime-day-deal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Whether you want an intense adventure watch or a simple fitness tracker, many of Garmin's most popular models are deeply discounted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/garmin-fitness-tracker-smartwatch-early-prime-day-deal/"&gt;Garmin fitness trackers and smartwatches are up to 45% off during Amazon&amp;#8217;s early Prime Day deals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:57:07 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>October Stargazing: A supermoon, new comet, and a whole lot of meteors</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/stargazing-guide-october-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Comet C/2025 A6 (Lemmon) was only discovered in January 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/stargazing-guide-october-2025/"&gt;October Stargazing: A supermoon, new comet, and a whole lot of meteors&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Why we should be skeptical of the hasty global push to test 15-year-olds’ AI literacy in 2029</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-we-should-be-skeptical-of-the-hasty-global-push-to-test-15-year-olds-ai-literacy-in-2029-263695</link><description>Canada and other OECD countries’ plans to test students’ AI literacy in 2029 threatens to obscure essential questions about the marketing of AI.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 13:31:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Are We Alone? NASA’s Habitable Worlds Observatory Aims to Find Out</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/are-we-alone-nasas-habitable-worlds-observatory-aims-to-find-out/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Habitable Worlds Observatory is poised to tell us whether Earth-like planets are common&amp;mdash;if it can get off the ground&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Camels depicted in 12,000-year-old rock art</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/camels-rock-art-cave-saudi-arabia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The 'incredibly beautiful' cave carvings show how humans thrived in the Arabian desert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/camels-rock-art-cave-saudi-arabia/"&gt;Camels depicted in 12,000-year-old rock art&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Rock Art Discovery Reveals Unknown Arabian Nomads from 12,000 Years Ago</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/rock-art-discovery-reveals-unknown-arabian-nomads-from-12-000-years-ago/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Camels in ancient Arabia may have led hunter-gatherers through deserts once thought uninhabitable&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sea sponges may have been Earth’s first living creatures</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/earth-first-animal-sea-sponge/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The prehistoric invertebrates likely arrived about 541 million years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/earth-first-animal-sea-sponge/"&gt;Sea sponges may have been Earth’s first living creatures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:50:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The exceptionally tasty new fermented foods being cooked up in the lab</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496986-the-exceptionally-tasty-new-fermented-foods-being-cooked-up-in-the-lab/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Fermented foods make up a third of what we eat and were mostly discovered by accident centuries ago. Now a fermentation revolution is promising extraordinary new flavours and novel ways to boost gut health</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Ancient artists created giant camel engravings in the Arabian desert</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498144-ancient-artists-created-giant-camel-engravings-in-the-arabian-desert/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Almost 200 engravings created around 12,000 years ago have been discovered in Saudi Arabia, including depictions of camels etched into cliff faces over 40 metres high</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 17:00:44 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>'Funny' videos of stressed and frightened pets are no laughing matter</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498164-funny-videos-of-stressed-and-frightened-pets-are-no-laughing-matter/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Social media is awash with videos of cats and dogs getting startled or hurt for our entertainment. We should all be more alert to poor animal welfare, says Christa Lesté-Lasserre</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 17:54:42 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Egg cells made with DNA from human skin fertilised in the lab</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498183-egg-cells-made-with-dna-from-human-skin-fertilised-in-the-lab/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>An innovative use of skin cells could provide a route for gay couples or women with fertility problems to have children that both partners are genetically related to</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:05:44 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A Prophet’s Diagnosis</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/michigan-shooting-mormon-prophet-peace/684408/?utm_source=feed</link><description>With violence and strife erupting all around us, can Russell Nelson’s message of hope, humility, and peace elevate us above that?</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 14:39:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Buy a vintage military airplane for $25</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/buy-vintage-airplane-wyoming/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Just don’t expect to fly any of these Cold War relics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/buy-vintage-airplane-wyoming/"&gt;Buy a vintage military airplane for $25&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 14:54:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>When China makes a climate pledge, the world should listen</title><link>https://theconversation.com/when-china-makes-a-climate-pledge-the-world-should-listen-266346</link><description>Beijing has a track record of only promising what it plans to deliver. But too often the world’s attention is elsewhere.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:20:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1,500th discovered bat species is a ‘god of the island’</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/new-bat-species-bioko-island/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What better way to kick off Bat Appreciation Month?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/new-bat-species-bioko-island/"&gt;1,500th discovered bat species is a ‘god of the island’&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:03:55 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>We now know why a belly button becomes an 'innie'</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498288-we-now-know-why-a-belly-button-becomes-an-innie/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Scientists have discovered a new abdominal structure called the umbilical sheath, which anchors the remnant of the umbilical cord to deep abdominal tissues and helps determine the shape of your navel</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 21:27:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Tylenol Safe for Children? What Research Shows About Acetaminophen</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/is-tylenol-safe-for-children-what-research-shows-about-acetaminophen/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President Trump says Tylenol is not safe for young children. Here&amp;rsquo;s what the science says about acetaminophen&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Breville early Amazon Prime Day deals: Treat yourself to a high-end espresso machine or smart oven</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/breville-smart-oven-espresso-machine-early-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Invest in a new espresso machine, smart oven, or other kitchen appliances from Breville and you won't want to eat out anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/breville-smart-oven-espresso-machine-early-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Breville early Amazon Prime Day deals: Treat yourself to a high-end espresso machine or smart oven&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>We teach young people to write. In the age of AI, we must teach them how to see</title><link>https://theconversation.com/we-teach-young-people-to-write-in-the-age-of-ai-we-must-teach-them-how-to-see-259283</link><description>Generative AI changes how we see – and how we decide what’s real.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 23:44:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pete Hegseth Is Living the Dream</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/pete-hegseth-quantico/684423/?utm_source=feed</link><description>A man who retired as a major lectures hundreds of generals about the need to meet his standards.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 21:45:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Life inside Enceladus? Cassini Uncovers Complex Organic Chemistry in Saturn’s Ocean Moon</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/is-life-inside-enceladus-cassini-uncovers-complex-organic-chemistry-in/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A fresh analysis of old data has found rich organic chemistry within the hidden ocean of Saturn&amp;rsquo;s moon Enceladus&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The best new science fiction books of October 2025</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497314-the-best-new-science-fiction-books-of-october-2025/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Science fiction legend Ursula K. Le Guin is honoured with a new collection out this month, and sci-fi fans can also look forward to fiction from astronaut Chris Hadfield and award-winning authors Ken Liu and Mary Robinette Kowal</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Should We Bring the Dead Back to Life?</title><link>https://nautil.us/should-we-bring-the-dead-back-to-life-1239968/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The hidden dangers of virtual ghosts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/should-we-bring-the-dead-back-to-life-1239968/"&gt;Should We Bring the Dead Back to Life?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New Life for Rotting Seaweed</title><link>https://nautil.us/new-life-for-rotting-seaweed-1238008/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Problematic piles of &lt;i&gt;Sargassum&lt;/i&gt; could serve as useful raw material for a variety of products&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/new-life-for-rotting-seaweed-1238008/"&gt;New Life for Rotting Seaweed&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Demetre Daskalakis on RFK, Jr., Vaccine Schedule Changes and CDC’s Future</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/demetre-daskalakis-on-rfk-jr-vaccine-schedule-changes-and-cdcs-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The former director of a CDC center reveals how political ideology is undermining science, threatening vaccine policy and endangering public health across the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Engineered Microbes Pull Critical Minerals from Mining Waste</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/engineered-microbes-pull-critical-minerals-from-mining-waste/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Biomining uses engineered microbes to harvest critical minerals&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Plants are incredibly sensitive – what we learned about their response system could help protect humans</title><link>https://theconversation.com/plants-are-incredibly-sensitive-what-we-learned-about-their-response-system-could-help-protect-humans-264937</link><description>A new study created a detailed map of how plants respond to cues in the world around them.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:05:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How WWII made Hershey and Mars Halloween candy kings</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/hershey-mars-wwii/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From sugar shortages to military contracts, World War II helped make M&amp;#38;Ms and Hershey’s bars into symbols of American abundance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/hershey-mars-wwii/"&gt;How WWII made Hershey and Mars Halloween candy kings&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How brain organoids are revealing what truly makes humans unique</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498307-how-brain-organoids-are-revealing-what-truly-makes-humans-unique/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Madeline Lancaster created the first brain organoids, which have revolutionised our understanding of how the brain works - but also raised ethical questions</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A life-long car lover recreated the Griswold’s famous station wagon</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/griswold-car-lake-george/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A Q&amp;#38;A with Tom Dittus, the man behind the Lake George Family Truckster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/griswold-car-lake-george/"&gt;A life-long car lover recreated the Griswold&amp;#8217;s famous station wagon&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:05:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How Genetics and Diet Helped the World’s Oldest Woman Live to 117</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-genetics-and-diet-helped-the-worlds-oldest-woman-live-to-117/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Maria Branyas Morera was the oldest person in the world when she died. Scientists analysed her genes, metabolism and more&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cat-sized Jurassic reptile had the jaws of a python</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/jurassic-snake-ancestor-scotland/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;'Breugnathair elgolensis' also sported stubby gecko legs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/jurassic-snake-ancestor-scotland/"&gt;Cat-sized Jurassic reptile had the jaws of a python&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>U.S. Military Continues mRNA Vaccine Research after RFK, Jr., Cuts Funding</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/u-s-military-continues-mrna-vaccine-research-after-rfk-jr-cuts-funding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Department of Defense funds biomedical research to ensure military and pandemic preparedness. This includes mRNA vaccine projects that RFK, Jr., recently defunded&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NASA's asteroid deflection test had unexpected and puzzling outcome</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498319-nasas-asteroid-deflection-test-had-unexpected-and-puzzling-outcome/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The DART mission achieved its goal of changing one asteroid’s orbit around another, but questions remain about why the orbit continued to alter over the following month</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:00:43 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An AI tool is trying to predict your risk of getting many diseases years in advance – here’s how it works</title><link>https://theconversation.com/an-ai-tool-is-trying-to-predict-your-risk-of-getting-many-diseases-years-in-advance-heres-how-it-works-265909</link><description>Delphi-2M is the first open source, large-scale model for predicting a patient’s disease risk and when it may occur.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:31:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is clearing out its most popular Kindle eReaders with these early Prime Day deals</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/amazon-kindle-ereader-early-prime-day-deals-paperwhite-scribe/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;These are the lowest prices we have seen on Kindles across the board since the beginning of the year. That means money left over for books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/amazon-kindle-ereader-early-prime-day-deals-paperwhite-scribe/"&gt;Amazon is clearing out its most popular Kindle eReaders with these early Prime Day deals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:52:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>'We're precipitating an extermination rather than an extinction event'</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495980-were-precipitating-an-extermination-rather-than-an-extinction-event/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Broadcaster and campaigner Chris Packham is on a mission to cut overconsumption, take on fossil fuel giants and create a fairer world</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:00:33 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The mystery of highly reactive oxygen has finally been solved</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498273-the-mystery-of-highly-reactive-oxygen-has-finally-been-solved/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Singlet oxygen can be damaging in both cells and batteries but it has taken almost 60 years to work out exactly when it shows up in chemical reactions within both</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:00:42 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Autism may have subtypes that are genetically distinct from each other</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498323-autism-may-have-subtypes-that-are-genetically-distinct-from-each-other/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Autism may exist in multiple forms, with the condition's genetics and signs differing according to the age at diagnosis</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:00:53 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Daydream Your Way to Life-Changing Insights</title><link>https://nautil.us/daydream-your-way-to-life-changing-insights-1240109/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Certain kinds of mind wandering can lead to powerful epiphanies &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/daydream-your-way-to-life-changing-insights-1240109/"&gt;Daydream Your Way to Life-Changing Insights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First Treatment that Slows Huntington's Disease Comes after Years of Heartbreak</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/first-treatment-that-slows-huntingtons-disease-comes-after-years-of/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After years of heartbreak, researchers have found an experimental treatment that can slow the progression of Huntington&amp;rsquo;s disease, according to early results from a small clinical trial&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Women really do live longer than men. Here’s why.</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/why-women-live-longer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Female mammals live 12 percent longer than males, on average. It's a different story for birds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/why-women-live-longer/"&gt;Women really do live longer than men. Here&amp;#8217;s why.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Why abandoning psychedelic research in the 1970s was a blow to science</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735630-100-why-abandoning-psychedelic-research-in-the-1970s-was-a-blow-to-science/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Work on medical uses of mind-altering substances was sidelined for decades by the political backlash against drugs, a misstep that has echoes in today’s intolerance of some fields of study</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What might the humble house mouse be trying to tell us?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735632-800-what-might-the-humble-house-mouse-be-trying-to-tell-us/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Feedback is amazed to find that the audible vocalisations of the house mouse is all but unstudied in favour of the ultrasonic sounds humans can’t hear. SQUEAK!</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Why 'beauty factories' could solve two massive cosmological mysteries</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735630-200-why-beauty-factories-could-solve-two-massive-cosmological-mysteries/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Facilities that make particles called B mesons may seem obscure, but they could help explain why there is more matter than antimatter and what dark matter is, says Chanda Prescod-Weinstein</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Exploring PMS is a great idea, but The Period Brain can be simplistic</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735630-500-exploring-pms-is-a-great-idea-but-the-period-brain-can-be-simplistic/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Premenstrual syndrome and its symptoms is neglected by science, so Sarah Hill's new book is welcome. But it needs more on genetics, not just lifestyle changes, says Alexandra Thompson</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Endearing photos of bats show clever adaptations like long tongues</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735630-300-endearing-photos-of-bats-show-clever-adaptations-like-long-tongues/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>In his book The Genius Bat, ecologist Yossi Yovel explains why these mammals are a vital part of ecosystems, pollinating plants and keeping insect populations in check</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Disturbing Netflix mystery explores a world out to 'solve' adolescence</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735630-700-disturbing-netflix-mystery-explores-a-world-out-to-solve-adolescence/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Set at a strange academy in small-town Vermont, Netflix’s Wayward aims to pacify unruly teens by master manipulation. Bethan Ackerley finds a creepy, troubled world</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>New Scientist recommends Chris Hadfield's Final Orbit</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735630-600-new-scientist-recommends-chris-hadfields-final-orbit/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The books, TV, games and more that New Scientist staff have enjoyed this week</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Americans receive the most scam calls in the world</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/spam-calls-worse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No, it's not just you AND it's getting worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/spam-calls-worse/"&gt;Americans receive the most scam calls in the world&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>PR firms are spreading climate misinformation on behalf of fossil fuel companies. Could Australia stop them?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/pr-firms-are-spreading-climate-misinformation-on-behalf-of-fossil-fuel-companies-could-australia-stop-them-266353</link><description>This week, Australian policymakers heard about the real and growing problem of climate misinformation. Stopping it would mean regulating the PR industry.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:37:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jane Goodall, Conservationist Who Transformed Our Understanding of Chimpanzees, Dies at 91</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/jane-goodall-conservationist-who-transformed-our-understanding-of/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The anthropologist was famous for her pioneering research with chimpanzees and her influence on conservation&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Evolution may explain why women live longer than men</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498396-evolution-may-explain-why-women-live-longer-than-men/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>In most mammals, females live longer than males, but in birds the trend goes the other way – a study of over 1000 species points to possible reasons for these differences</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 20:00:28 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientists predict the universe will end in ‘big crunch’</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/universe-ends-big-crunch/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Starts with a bang, ends with a crunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/universe-ends-big-crunch/"&gt;Scientists predict the universe will end in &amp;#8216;big crunch&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:43:16 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Bail Out Argentina</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/argentina-trump-milei-bailout/684427/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The Trump administration got this one right.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:06:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Jane Goodall, dogged advocate for the natural world, has died aged 91</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498629-jane-goodall-dogged-advocate-for-the-natural-world-has-died-aged-91/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Acclaimed conservationist and chimpanzee expert Jane Goodall has died, leaving behind a legacy of empathy for primates and the natural world</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 21:30:19 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What Made Horses Rideable</title><link>https://nautil.us/what-made-horses-rideable-1240132/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How horse genetics and human culture co-evolved&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/what-made-horses-rideable-1240132/"&gt;What Made Horses Rideable&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Get an Elephant’s Attention</title><link>https://nautil.us/how-to-get-an-elephants-attention-1240180/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The secret lies in our shared language of gestures&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/how-to-get-an-elephants-attention-1240180/"&gt;How to Get an Elephant’s Attention&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Many People Have Ever Lived on Earth?</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-many-people-have-ever-lived-on-earth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Is it really possible that half of all people who have ever been age 65 or older are still alive today? We explore the amazing mathematics of demography to find out&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How playing a musical instrument helps children learn to read</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498314-how-playing-a-musical-instrument-helps-children-learn-to-read/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Learning to play an instrument has long been linked to improved reading skills among children, and we may finally understand why</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:00:57 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How Jane Goodall changed the way we see animals – and the world</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498651-how-jane-goodall-changed-the-way-we-see-animals-and-the-world/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Jane Goodall, who chronicled the social lives of chimps, has died, but she leaves a lasting legacy on how we view the natural world</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:02:18 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Bad Bunny’s Super Bowl</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/bad-bunny-super-bowl/684411/?utm_source=feed</link><description>MAGA isn’t going to like this halftime show.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:37:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Most of your actions are driven by habit, not thought – here’s why that’s not a bad thing</title><link>https://theconversation.com/most-of-your-actions-are-driven-by-habit-not-thought-heres-why-thats-not-a-bad-thing-266277</link><description>And how you can use psychology to help you break out of the habits you want to lose.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:58:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How VR and AI could help the next generation grow kinder and more connected</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-vr-and-ai-could-help-the-next-generation-grow-kinder-and-more-connected-263181</link><description>Virtual reality might seem like an unlikely way to help kids develop empathy, but the right VR environment can do just that.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:43:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swap your boiler for a money-saving heat pump</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/heat-pump-benefits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Heat pumps can save you about $370 per year and are good for the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/heat-pump-benefits/"&gt;Swap your boiler for a money-saving heat pump&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Rogue planet gains 6 billion tonnes per second in record growth spurt</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498489-rogue-planet-gains-6-billion-tonnes-per-second-in-record-growth-spurt/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A free-floating planet has been seen devouring astonishing amounts of matter, hinting that stars and planets are more alike than we thought</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:00:51 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>iOS 26 adds a new app to your iPhone. Here’s how to use it.</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/preview-app-iphone/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You're not imagining it—there is a new app on your iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/preview-app-iphone/"&gt;iOS 26 adds a new app to your iPhone. Here&amp;#8217;s how to use it.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>ডাবের আশ্চর্য শহরযাত্রা!</title><link>https://www.tbsnews.net/bangla/Easel/news-details-396111</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:14:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is China a climate goodie or baddie – or both?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/is-china-a-climate-goodie-or-baddie-or-both-266502</link><description>The country is a key driver of both emissions and solutions.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:53:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Truth About Amelia Earhart</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/amelia-earhart-truth-conspiracy/684430/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Conspiracy theories about her disappearance do a disservice to the pilot’s remarkable, flawed legacy.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:57:44 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Antarctica may have crossed a tipping point that leads to rising seas</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498509-antarctica-may-have-crossed-a-tipping-point-that-leads-to-rising-seas/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Scientists are beginning to understand the sudden loss of sea ice in Antarctica – and there is growing evidence that it represents a permanent shift with potentially catastrophic consequences</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:00:44 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The safest way to use a chainsaw, according to science</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/chainsaw-safety-tips/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Training and wearing the same material in bulletproof vests are key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/chainsaw-safety-tips/"&gt;The safest way to use a chainsaw, according to science&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:03:21 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Mind-Altering Effect of a Good Workout Routine</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/happiness-exercise-routine-emotions/684409/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Few things lift your mood more than going to the gym. Exercise your body, and your mind will thank you.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>নারকেল ‘ফারাওয়ের বাদাম’!</title><link>https://www.tbsnews.net/bangla/Easel/news-details-396471</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:17:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Other Martyr</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/george-floyd-charlie-kirk-martyr/684434/?utm_source=feed</link><description>MAGA has found its George Floyd.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:44:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Extreme fear of the dentist linked to childhood trauma</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/dental-fear-trauma/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A study of over 5,000 teens found a strong connection between childhood stress and dental anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/dental-fear-trauma/"&gt;Extreme fear of the dentist linked to childhood trauma&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:20:37 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>This U.S. Government Shutdown Is Very Bad for Science</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/this-u-s-government-shutdown-is-very-bad-for-science/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President Trump&amp;rsquo;s budget office lays out guidelines for mass federal lay-offs as the U.S. government grinds to a halt&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Should we worry AI will create deadly bioweapons? Not yet, but one day</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498478-should-we-worry-ai-will-create-deadly-bioweapons-not-yet-but-one-day/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>AI tools are being used to design proteins and even viruses, leading to fears these could eventually be used to evade bioweapon controls</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 20:00:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Jane Goodall’s Legacy of Challenging What It Means to Be a Scientist</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/jane-goodall-legacy-of-challenging-what-it-means-to-be-a-scientist/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Here are three big ways that Jane Goodall transformed science&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 20:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Luxury jet replaces cabin windows with video screens</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/private-jet-no-windows-otto-aerospace/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;HD cameras beam panoramic images inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/private-jet-no-windows-otto-aerospace/"&gt;Luxury jet replaces cabin windows with video screens&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Divers Who Stretch the Limits of Human Biology</title><link>https://nautil.us/the-divers-who-stretch-the-limits-of-human-biology-1240106/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The most dangerous job on Earth is at the bottom of the sea&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/the-divers-who-stretch-the-limits-of-human-biology-1240106/"&gt;The Divers Who Stretch the Limits of Human Biology&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 21:11:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Indomitable Jane Goodall</title><link>https://nautil.us/the-indomitable-jane-goodall-1240427/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Reflections from those who knew the primatologist best&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/the-indomitable-jane-goodall-1240427/"&gt;The Indomitable Jane Goodall&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 23:20:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia’s new food security strategy: what’s on the table, and what’s missing?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/australias-new-food-security-strategy-whats-on-the-table-and-whats-missing-264791</link><description>A government inquiry has made 35 recommendations to improve Australia’s food security, but there are some key gaps.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 01:05:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why coral reefs damaged by blast fishing struggle to recover — even after decades</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-coral-reefs-damaged-by-blast-fishing-struggle-to-recover-even-after-decades-265733</link><description>Blast-fished reefs are unlikely to recover naturally without human intervention.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:36:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Our verdict on ‘The Dispossessed’: A tricky but rewarding novel</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498143-our-verdict-on-the-dispossessed-a-tricky-but-rewarding-novel/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The New Scientist Book Club has just finished reading Ursula K. Le Guin’s The Dispossessed. Most of our members enjoyed it, even if the sheer volume of ideas in the book made it a challenging read</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:00:32 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Read an extract from Our Brains, Our Selves by Masud Husain</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496548-read-an-extract-from-our-brains-our-selves-by-masud-husain/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>In this passage from Our Brains, Our Selves, winner of the Royal Society Trivedi Science Book Prize, neuroscientist Masud Husain recounts how novelist Marcel Proust became convinced, wrongly, that he'd had a stroke</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:00:36 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Our Brains, Our Selves won the Royal Society science book prize</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497944-why-our-brains-our-selves-won-the-royal-society-science-book-prize/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Sandra Knapp, chair of the judging panel for the 2025 Royal Society Trivedi Science Book Prize, explains why neurologist Masud Husain’s collection of case studies is such an enlightening, compassionate book</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:00:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An Anechoic Chamber at Nokia Bell Labs Reveals the Hidden Sounds of Your Body</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/an-anechoic-chamber-at-nokia-bell-labs-reveals-the-hidden-sounds-of-your/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Step into a room so quiet you can hear your own heartbeat&amp;mdash;and your nervous system.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kids as young as 4 innately use sorting algorithms to solve problems</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498204-kids-as-young-as-4-innately-use-sorting-algorithms-to-solve-problems/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>It was previously thought that children younger than 7 couldn't find efficient solutions to complex problems, but new research suggests that much earlier, children can happen upon known sorting algorithms used by computer scientists</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:00:11 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>20 bird species can understand each other’s anti-cuckoo call</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498809-20-bird-species-can-understand-each-others-anti-cuckoo-call/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Several species of birds from different continents use and understand similar alarm calls when they see an invader that might lay an egg in their nest – this shared call hints at the origin of language</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:00:45 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How Can Galaxies Recede from Us Faster Than the Speed of Light?</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-can-galaxies-recede-from-us-faster-than-the-speed-of-light/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When space itself expands, weird things can happen&amp;mdash;like galaxies breaking the universe&amp;rsquo;s ultimate speed limit&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What is Knot Theory? Solve These Puzzles to Find Out</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/what-is-knot-theory-solve-these-puzzles-to-find-out/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Learn the fundamentals of the burgeoning field of knot theory while solving some puzzles along the way&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ocean Acidification Threshold Pushes Earth Past Another Planetary Boundary</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/ocean-acidification-threshold-pushes-earth-past-another-planetary-boundary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earth has breached a critical boundary for ocean acidification, with potentially grim effects for ocean ecosystems and human livelihoods&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Multi-generational vulture nests hold 700 years of human artifacts</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/bearded-vulture-nest-archaeology/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Crossbow bolts, sandals, slingshots, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/bearded-vulture-nest-archaeology/"&gt;Multi-generational vulture nests hold 700 years of human artifacts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 08:33:20 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘AI actor’ Tilly Norwood is dividing Hollywood – but real acting requires humanity</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-actor-tilly-norwood-is-dividing-hollywood-but-real-acting-requires-humanity-266525</link><description>The outcry from established actors was immediate and heartfelt.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 12:37:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Children can be systematic problem-solvers at younger ages than psychologists had thought – new research</title><link>https://theconversation.com/children-can-be-systematic-problem-solvers-at-younger-ages-than-psychologists-had-thought-new-research-266438</link><description>By cranking up the difficulty on the test task, researchers found that children are capable of finding systematic solutions to complex problems far earlier than psychologists had believed.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 12:39:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What past education technology failures can teach us about the future of AI in schools</title><link>https://theconversation.com/what-past-education-technology-failures-can-teach-us-about-the-future-of-ai-in-schools-265172</link><description>It can take years to collect evidence that shows effective uses of new technologies in schools. Unfortunately, early guesses sometimes go seriously wrong.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 12:40:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The search for Cleopatra’s long-lost tomb leads to sunken seaport</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/cleopatra-lost-tomb-documentary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new documentary explores this 2,000-year-old mystery and a connection to the RMS 'Titanic.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/cleopatra-lost-tomb-documentary/"&gt;The search for Cleopatra’s long-lost tomb leads to sunken seaport&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out iRobot Roomba vacuums for as low as $149 with these early Prime Day deals</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/roomba-robot-vacuum-cleaner-early-amazon-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You've always wanted a robotic butler, but a Roomba is as close as you're going to get. These are the lowest Roomba prices we have seen this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/roomba-robot-vacuum-cleaner-early-amazon-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out iRobot Roomba vacuums for as low as $149 with these early Prime Day deals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:28:47 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Ants can be used to make ‘tangy’ yogurt</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/ant-yogurt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An old family recipe from Bulgaria goes under the microscope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/ant-yogurt/"&gt;Ants can be used to make &amp;#8216;tangy&amp;#8217; yogurt&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Exceptional star is the most pristine object known in the universe</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498843-exceptional-star-is-the-most-pristine-object-known-in-the-universe/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A star found in the Large Magellanic Cloud is remarkably unpolluted by heavier elements, suggesting it is descended from the universe’s earliest stars</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:00:12 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan’s favorite beer is in peril</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/asahi-beer-cyber-attack/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Asahi Super Dry's manufacturer is suffering from a major cyberattack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/asahi-beer-cyber-attack/"&gt;Japan&amp;#8217;s favorite beer is in peril&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:22:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>There is an odd streak in the universe – and we still don’t know why</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498128-there-is-an-odd-streak-in-the-universe-and-we-still-dont-know-why/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Astronomers have long thought the universe should look generally the same in every direction, but an anomaly in the radiation from the big bang persists even after a new analysis from radio telescopes</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:00:27 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Your happiness in life may not be U-shaped - here's how it could vary</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498760-your-happiness-in-life-may-not-be-u-shaped-heres-how-it-could-vary/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>We thought happiness peaked at the beginning and end of life, but a study from Germany suggests a more pessimistic outlook for our later years</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:54:51 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Researchers are reanimating 40,000-year-old microbes</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/permafrost-microbes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;They're alive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/permafrost-microbes/"&gt;Researchers are reanimating 40,000-year-old microbes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 14:06:38 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Sex Ed, Lunchrooms, and Recess: Lessons From a 5th Grader's Life</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/mindful-metaphors/202510/sex-ed-lunchrooms-and-recess-lessons-from-a-5th-graders-life</link><description>A 5th grader's schedule allows metaphorical application of three important life skills: lean into learning, include times for social eating, and play outdoors.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 15:23:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Stop Obsessing Over Passion: What Your Brain Really Needs</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/motivate/202510/stop-obsessing-over-passion-what-your-brain-really-needs</link><description>Think passion fuels success? Science says otherwise—your brain runs on control, rewards, and choice, not motivational myths.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 15:56:52 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Google’s latest AI photo-editing tool means you might not need Photoshop</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/google-ai-photo-editing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gemini 2.5 Flash Image is a major image editing upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/google-ai-photo-editing/"&gt;Google&amp;#8217;s latest AI photo-editing tool means you might not need Photoshop&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>What Resale Reveals About the Psychology of Status and Self</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/mindful-leadership/202510/what-resale-reveals-about-the-psychology-of-status-and-self</link><description>Discover how the psychology of resale shapes status, identity, and brand meaning—and why context matters as much as the luxury itself.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:13:05 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Periscope: Book Weeding, Fact-Checking, and Imperiled Fruit Fly Data</title><link>https://nautil.us/the-periscope-book-weeding-fact-checking-and-imperiled-fruit-fly-data-1240588/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What &lt;i&gt;Nautilus&lt;/i&gt; executive editor Katherine Courage has been tuning into recently&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/the-periscope-book-weeding-fact-checking-and-imperiled-fruit-fly-data-1240588/"&gt;The Periscope: Book Weeding, Fact-Checking, and Imperiled Fruit Fly Data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 20:28:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rage Baiting: It's Not Your Father's Bullying Any More</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/facing-lifes-challenges/202510/rage-baiting-its-not-your-fathers-bullying-any-more</link><description>Parents often have difficulty experiencing their child being upset by a peer. How do you re-find your emotional balance and help your child deal with their upset?</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:47:43 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Kash Patel’s Challenge Coin Is Perfect for Him</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/kash-patel-military-memento-internet/684456/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The FBI director has created a memento that symbolizes his unfitness.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:09:09 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Art of the Subtle Put-Down</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/one-among-many/202510/the-art-of-the-subtle-put-down</link><description>Social communication favors those who get to ask the questions. They can make others feel inadequate or insensitive. Defense options, though, do exist.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:18:44 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Purge of Terrorism Prosecutors</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/terrorism-prosecutors-fired-trump-doj/684447/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The politicization of the Justice Department is making Americans less safe.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:32:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Artificial Intelligence Perpetuating Loneliness?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/talking-about-trauma/202509/is-artificial-intelligence-perpetuating-loneliness</link><description>Advancements in AI allow chatbots to serve as substitutes for friends and loved ones. However, this has been shown to encourage social withdrawal, perpetuating loneliness.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:50:23 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Peace Is a Modern Invention</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/in-gods-we-trust/202510/peace-is-a-modern-invention</link><description>The question of peace as the modern baseline of international life.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 18:05:11 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Win Smarter, Not Harder</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/dear-life-please-improve/202510/win-smarter-not-harder</link><description>You can grind harder than anyone, yet still fail. Don’t just hustle harder—figure out which game to play.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 18:15:02 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Your Lived Experience and Advocacy</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/inside-out-outside-in/202510/your-lived-experience-and-advocacy</link><description>Personal narratives of challenges in mental health are powerful ways to destigmatize mental illness and foster prevention, resilience, and policy that will help young people.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 18:26:16 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>What Is the Average Age Gap in Relationships Worldwide?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-asymmetric-brain/202510/what-is-the-average-age-gap-in-relationships-worldwide</link><description>Have you ever wondered what is the average age gap in relationships between men and women worldwide? A large international study provided the answer!</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 18:43:13 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Money Boundaries and Mental Health</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/mental-wealth/202510/money-boundaries-and-mental-health</link><description>Money boundaries shape not only our bank accounts but also our relationships and mental health. Discover how shifting from Doormat or Diva to Dignified can transform your life.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 18:44:24 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Peptides in Mental Health: A New Frontier</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-shameless-psychiatrist/202510/peptides-in-mental-health-a-new-frontier</link><description>Nootropics like NAD+, Selank, and GLP-1 agonists offer alternative options beyond traditional pharmaceutical treatments for mental health issues.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 18:58:15 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Writers Block: It's Not in Your Head</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/bodhisattva-wannabe/202510/writers-block-its-not-in-your-head</link><description>Do you wonder how best to court the creative muse? I think the answer can be found—in fascia.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 19:18:05 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Attachment Isn’t What You Think It Is</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/connection-and-coping/202510/attachment-isnt-what-you-think-it-is</link><description>Labels like anxious or avoidant are everywhere. Learn what attachment actually is and how to use it to strengthen your relationship.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 20:12:40 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>কানাকুয়ো আর পাখির কুসংস্কার</title><link>https://www.tbsnews.net/bangla/Easel/news-details-396796</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 08:17:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Dark Energy Born inside Black Holes?</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/is-dark-energy-born-inside-black-holes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A controversial prediction about black holes and the expansion force of the universe could explain a cosmology mystery&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lead Inclusively by Harnessing the Power of Joy</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/better-and-happier/202509/lead-inclusively-by-harnessing-the-power-of-joy</link><description>When companies retreat from DEI, it hurts employees and profits. Leaders can reimagine inclusivity by harnessing the power of joy.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 07:43:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>5 low back stretches to relieve aches and pains</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/low-back-stretches-for-aches-and-pains/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Simple moves to build strength and help prevent injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/low-back-stretches-for-aches-and-pains/"&gt;5 low back stretches to relieve aches and pains&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>A Deal That Would End Universities’ Independence</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/higher-education-compact-trump-deal/684457/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The free-speech provisions of the so-called compact are an exercise in contradiction.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The ‘Best’ Colleges Aren’t the Best Forever</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/ivy-league-schools-prestige/684454/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Prestige isn’t permanent.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>13 inspiring photos of thriving deep-sea animals</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/13-inspiring-photos-of-thriving-deep-sea-animals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A recent Schmidt Ocean Institute expedition off the coast of Uruguay discovered at least 30 suspected new species and explored a sunken warship. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/13-inspiring-photos-of-thriving-deep-sea-animals/"&gt;13 inspiring photos of thriving deep-sea animals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Deal With Being Disliked at the Office</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-three-minute-therapist/202508/how-to-deal-with-being-disliked-at-the-office</link><description>Being disliked at the office presents both practical and emotional challenges, but you can think your way toward a new outlook that fosters more manageable feelings.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 10:38:34 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Detect "Bio-Baiting" on Dating Profiles</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/a-funny-bone-to-pick/202509/how-to-detect-bio-baiting-on-dating-profiles</link><description>Here's a shocker. People can lie on their dating profiles to make themselves seem more attractive and desirable. It's being called "bio-baiting." Here's how to detect it.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 10:54:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Zoosomatics: Moving With Dogs and Other Animals Helps Us All</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/animal-emotions/202509/zoosomatics-moving-with-dogs-and-other-animals-helps-us-all</link><description>Marco Adda offers a new view of how to interact with nonhumans and explores how we can learn from other animals’ movement, perception, and presence to help everyone involved.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 11:03:15 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Four Simple Strategies to Boost Your Brain Power</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/fulfillment-at-any-age/202510/four-simple-strategies-to-boost-your-brain-power</link><description>If you don't move, your brain cells die.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 11:04:49 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Brain Fog in Long COVID Linked to Increase in AMPA Receptors</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-asymmetric-brain/202510/brain-fog-in-long-covid-linked-to-increase-in-ampa-receptors</link><description>Many patients with long COVID experience brain fog, but the reasons are not well understood. A new study links brain fog to a type of neurotransmitter receptor.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 11:30:46 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Crisis and Risk Psychology in Norway</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/disaster-by-choice/202510/crisis-and-risk-psychology-in-norway</link><description>Our new paper examines the psychology of municipal leadership in Norway for avoiding crises and risks from becoming disasters.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 11:48:46 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Liberating Truth About Aging Nobody Mentions</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/raging-with-grace/202510/the-liberating-truth-about-aging-nobody-mentions</link><description>Something fascinating happens as we age. It’s not about becoming careless or rude, but about our emerging priorities and the autheticity that comes along with it.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 11:56:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How a hatter and railroad clerk kickstarted cancer research</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/how-cancer-research-started/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;100 years ago, this unlikely duo discovered the first cancer ‘germ.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/how-cancer-research-started/"&gt;How a hatter and railroad clerk kickstarted cancer research&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Ken Jennings’s Kennections Quiz #187: Can You Guess What These Clues Have in Common?</title><link>https://www.mentalfloss.com/kennections/ken-jennings-kennections-quiz-187?utm_source=RSS</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class="ff-og-image-inserted" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_2667,h_1500/c_fill,w_1440,ar_1440:810,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/voltaxMediaLibrary/mmsport/mentalfloss/01j683szpk2ph1jkceec.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9n q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Welcome to &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/kennections"&gt;Kennections&lt;/a&gt;, a weekly quiz created by &lt;em&gt;Jeopardy! &lt;/em&gt;host and champion &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/authors/ken-jennings"&gt;Ken Jennings&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s how to play: All five answers to the questions below have something in common. Can you figure it out?&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9o q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="mt-[18px] md:mt-0 mb-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-0"&gt;Welcome to &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/kennections"&gt;Kennections&lt;/a&gt;, a weekly quiz created by &lt;em&gt;Jeopardy! &lt;/em&gt;host and champion &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/authors/ken-jennings"&gt;Ken Jennings&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s how to play: All five answers to the questions below have something in common. Can you figure it out?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9q q:key=vcaa:https://www.riddle.com/embed/a/mCS1TK5b?--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9r q:key=SRoa:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9s q:key=EEns:oZ_1--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9u q:key=vcaa:2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9v q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9w q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9x q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9z q:key=vcaa:4--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a0 q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a1 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take Our Latest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/quizzes/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Quizzes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a2 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-5"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take Our Latest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/quizzes/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Quizzes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a4 q:key=vcaa:https://content-enrichment-service.mmsport.minutesvc.com/oembed?url=https://content-enrichment-service.mmsport.minutesvc.com/properties/mentalfloss/embeds/01j6yxa15b2gmq4--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a5 q:key=jBas:mL_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org"&gt;Adblock test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org/acceptable.html"&gt;(Why?)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 16:02:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Research Identifies the Right Way to Write</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/recovery-from-brain-injury/202510/research-identifies-the-right-way-to-write</link><description>Studies reveal that when handwriting automaticity is achieved, it enhances the cognitive and "free-flowing" intellectual potential of creating more complex narratives.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 12:18:08 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>We Joke, We Joke, But Why?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/4000-mondays/202510/we-joke-we-joke-but-why</link><description>Ethical, low-stakes practical jokes are micro-interventions: safe surprises spark shared laughter, bond teams, lower stress, and lift the prankster’s mood. Permission to prank!</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 12:54:37 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Bending The Rules: A Path to Leadership, but at What Cost?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/insight-therapy/202506/bending-the-rules-a-path-to-leadership-but-at-what-cost</link><description>As rule benders gain leadership, they enact a self-reinforcing loop: More influence facilitates further rule bending, including the rules that uphold the social order.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 13:00:55 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Am I Loved Only Because I Perform?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/perfectionism/202510/am-i-loved-only-because-i-perform</link><description>When love is believed to be conditional, based on some form of performance, we may contribute to our mental health struggles in the constant pursuit of that conditional love.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 13:19:49 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Promising Future of Precision Interventional Psychiatry</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/experimentations/202510/the-promising-future-of-precision-interventional-psychiatry</link><description>Precision psychiatry is coming into focus: Real-time brain maps, smarter sensing and neuromodulation, and humane tech hint at a future we can sense—but not yet fully imagine.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 13:58:19 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Thinking Too Much Stressing You Out?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-refugee-experience/202510/is-thinking-too-much-stressing-you-out</link><description>Rumination fuels stress and suffering. Here's a simple 3-step method for stepping away from overthinking and lowering our stress.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 14:17:23 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Succisa Virescit: The Cut That Makes Us Grow</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-digital-self/202510/succisa-virescit-the-cut-that-makes-us-grow</link><description>AI makes thinking effortless, but without friction, we lose the struggle that shapes understanding.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 14:53:26 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How to use iOS 26’s new battery saving mode</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/iphone-battery-saving-mode/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Get more out of your iPhone on a single charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/iphone-battery-saving-mode/"&gt;How to use iOS 26’s new battery saving mode&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Roots and Evolution of Psychological Science</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/raising-resilient-children/202510/the-roots-and-evolution-of-psychological-science</link><description>Psychological science employs empirical methods to comprehend behavior, thought, and society.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 15:37:32 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>9 of the Most Valuable Nintendo 64 Games</title><link>https://www.mentalfloss.com/fun/video-games/most-valuable-nintendo-64-games?utm_source=RSS</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class="ff-og-image-inserted" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_80,w_5000,h_2812/c_fill,w_1440,ar_1440:810,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k6jzcnv8z5nx5z3jt1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9n q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;After its released in 1996, the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/86590/10-game-changing-facts-about-nintendo-64"&gt;Nintendo 64&lt;/a&gt; (N64) quickly became one of the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/posts/best-selling-video-game-consoles"&gt;most popular video game consoles&lt;/a&gt; of all time. It introduced millions of gamers to the 3D world and enjoyed a six-year run until Nintendo launched the GameCube in 2001. (N64 was officially discontinued about a year later.)&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9o q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="mt-[18px] md:mt-0 mb-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-0"&gt;After its released in 1996, the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/86590/10-game-changing-facts-about-nintendo-64"&gt;Nintendo 64&lt;/a&gt; (N64) quickly became one of the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/posts/best-selling-video-game-consoles"&gt;most popular video game consoles&lt;/a&gt; of all time. It introduced millions of gamers to the 3D world and enjoyed a six-year run until Nintendo launched the GameCube in 2001. (N64 was officially discontinued about a year later.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9q q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/504666/bit-bit-inside-rise-retro-gaming"&gt;rise of retro gaming&lt;/a&gt; in recent years, the N64 is having a resurgence. Many Gen X and &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/620786/facts-about-millennials"&gt;Millennial&lt;/a&gt; gamers want to relive their glory days with classic games like &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/posts/lego-mario-kart-sets"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mario Kart 64&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Super Smash Bros.&lt;/em&gt;, and others. This means N64 games are more valuable than ever, with games selling for thousands—and in one case, nearly millions—of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9r q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-1"&gt;With the &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/504666/bit-bit-inside-rise-retro-gaming"&gt;rise of retro gaming&lt;/a&gt; in recent years, the N64 is having a resurgence. Many Gen X and &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/620786/facts-about-millennials"&gt;Millennial&lt;/a&gt; gamers want to relive their glory days with classic games like &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/posts/lego-mario-kart-sets"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mario Kart 64&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Super Smash Bros.&lt;/em&gt;, and others. This means N64 games are more valuable than ever, with games selling for thousands—and in one case, nearly millions—of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9t q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;If you have any of these cartridges sitting in your basement, attic, or storage room, then you might have a fortune on your hands. Below you’ll find the most valuable N64 video games, according to &lt;a href="https://www.ha.com/c/search/results.zx?term=Nintendo+64+Games&amp;amp;si=2&amp;amp;archive_state=5327&amp;amp;sold_status=1526&amp;amp;sb=3&amp;amp;mode=archive&amp;amp;page=48~2&amp;amp;layout=gallery" target="_blank"&gt;Heritage Auctions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9u q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-2"&gt;If you have any of these cartridges sitting in your basement, attic, or storage room, then you might have a fortune on your hands. Below you’ll find the most valuable N64 video games, according to &lt;a href="https://www.ha.com/c/search/results.zx?term=Nintendo+64+Games&amp;amp;si=2&amp;amp;archive_state=5327&amp;amp;sold_status=1526&amp;amp;sb=3&amp;amp;mode=archive&amp;amp;page=48~2&amp;amp;layout=gallery" target="_blank"&gt;Heritage Auctions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9w q:key=vcaa:--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9x q:key=StMp:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=Lf_2--&gt;&lt;ol class="toc text-primary mt-4 flex flex-col gap-y-2.5 ps-10 list-decimal [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/fun/video-games/most-valuable-nintendo-64-games?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt; // $1,560,000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/fun/video-games/most-valuable-nintendo-64-games?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-13"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clay Fighter: Sculptor’s Cut&lt;/em&gt; // $175,000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/fun/video-games/most-valuable-nintendo-64-games?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-17"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time&lt;/em&gt; // $168,000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/fun/video-games/most-valuable-nintendo-64-games?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-21"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mario Kart 64&lt;/em&gt; // $144,000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/fun/video-games/most-valuable-nintendo-64-games?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-25"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transformers: Beast Wars Transmetals&lt;/em&gt; // $37,500&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/fun/video-games/most-valuable-nintendo-64-games?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-28"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kobe Bryant in NBA Courtside&lt;/em&gt; // $33,600&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/fun/video-games/most-valuable-nintendo-64-games?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-31"&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoldenEye 007&lt;/em&gt; // $33,600&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/fun/video-games/most-valuable-nintendo-64-games?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-34"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wave Race 64&lt;/em&gt; // $21,000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/fun/video-games/most-valuable-nintendo-64-games?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-38"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Donkey Kong 64&lt;/em&gt; // $18,000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9z q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt; // $1,560,000&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a0 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt; // $1,560,000&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a2 q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GOmsqDYQ8Ys--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a3 q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a4 q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a6 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;When the N64 came to the United States, only two new titles were available at launch: &lt;em&gt;Pilotwings 64&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt;. And while a mint-condition, sealed copy of &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/pilotwings-64-wata-96-a-sealed-n64-nintendo-1996-usa/a/312230-69087.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilotwings 64&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; sold for $4320 in 2022, that’s nothing compared to the unopened and pristine copy of &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt; that sold for a whopping $1,560,000 through &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/super-mario-64-wata-98-a-sealed-n64-nintendo-1996-usa/a/7261-28137.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515"&gt;Heritage Auctions&lt;/a&gt; in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a7 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-6"&gt;When the N64 came to the United States, only two new titles were available at launch: &lt;em&gt;Pilotwings 64&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt;. And while a mint-condition, sealed copy of &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/pilotwings-64-wata-96-a-sealed-n64-nintendo-1996-usa/a/312230-69087.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilotwings 64&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; sold for $4320 in 2022, that’s nothing compared to the unopened and pristine copy of &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt; that sold for a whopping $1,560,000 through &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/super-mario-64-wata-98-a-sealed-n64-nintendo-1996-usa/a/7261-28137.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515"&gt;Heritage Auctions&lt;/a&gt; in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a9 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt; was the first 3D platformer for Nintendo, and it introduced a new level of gameplay and mechanics that game developers still use today. It’s also the best-selling N64 game of all-time, with nearly &lt;a href="https://data40.com/articles/best-selling-n64-games/" target="_blank"&gt;12 million units&lt;/a&gt; sold between 1996 and 2003, when the gaming console was ultimately discontinued. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aa q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt; was the first 3D platformer for Nintendo, and it introduced a new level of gameplay and mechanics that game developers still use today. It’s also the best-selling N64 game of all-time, with nearly &lt;a href="https://data40.com/articles/best-selling-n64-games/" target="_blank"&gt;12 million units&lt;/a&gt; sold between 1996 and 2003, when the gaming console was ultimately discontinued.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ac q:key=vcaa:8--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ad q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ae q:key=vcaa:&lt;h3&gt;You May Also Like:&lt;/h3&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=af q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h3 class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-9"&gt;You May Also Like:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ah q:key=vcaa:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/fun/most-valuable-dragon-ball-z-cards"&gt;6 of the Most Valuable Dragon Ball Z Cards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/fun/video-games/nintendo-game-boy-history"&gt;When Nintendo’s Game Boy Helped Video Games Grow Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/posts/best-selling-video-game-consoles"&gt;The 20 Best-Selling Video Game Consoles of All Time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ai q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ak q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=al q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-11"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=an q:key=vcaa:12--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ao q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ap q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clay Fighter: Sculptor’s Cut&lt;/em&gt; // $175,000&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aq q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-13"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clay Fighter: Sculptor’s Cut&lt;/em&gt; // $175,000&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=as q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BlprydzYWKY--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=at q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=au q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aw q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Although the fighting game &lt;em&gt;ClayFighter 63⅓&lt;/em&gt; was a commercial and critical flop when it was released in 1997, an updated version retitled &lt;em&gt;Clay Fighter: Sculptor’s Cut&lt;/em&gt; became an instant smash hit a year later. It had a limited distribution in 1998, with the video rental company Blockbuster owning the exclusive rights. Today it’s a rare and highly sought-after title for the N64.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ax q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-15"&gt;Although the fighting game &lt;em&gt;ClayFighter 63⅓&lt;/em&gt; was a commercial and critical flop when it was released in 1997, an updated version retitled &lt;em&gt;Clay Fighter: Sculptor’s Cut&lt;/em&gt; became an instant smash hit a year later. It had a limited distribution in 1998, with the video rental company Blockbuster owning the exclusive rights. Today it’s a rare and highly sought-after title for the N64.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=az q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Reportedly just 20,000 copies were created for Blockbuster so it’s rare to find an intact copy of the game in the wild. A mint condition and unopened copy of&lt;em&gt;Clay Fighter: Sculptor's Cut&lt;/em&gt; sold for $175,000 at &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/clay-fighter-sculptor-s-cut-cgc-94-a-sealed-n64-interplay-1998-usa/a/7382-28078.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515" target="_blank"&gt;Heritage Auctions&lt;/a&gt; in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b0 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-16"&gt;Reportedly just 20,000 copies were created for Blockbuster so it’s rare to find an intact copy of the game in the wild. A mint condition and unopened copy of&lt;em&gt;Clay Fighter: Sculptor's Cut&lt;/em&gt; sold for $175,000 at &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/clay-fighter-sculptor-s-cut-cgc-94-a-sealed-n64-interplay-1998-usa/a/7382-28078.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515" target="_blank"&gt;Heritage Auctions&lt;/a&gt; in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b2 q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time&lt;/em&gt; // $168,000&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b3 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-17"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time&lt;/em&gt; // $168,000&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b5 q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F9ohCKS_LUM--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b6 q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b7 q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b9 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;A near-perfect and factory-sealed copy of &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time&lt;/em&gt; sold for $168,000 at &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/the-legend-of-zelda-ocarina-of-time-wata-98-a-sealed-standard-release-n64-nintendo-1998-usa/a/7284-28096.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515" target="_blank"&gt;Heritage Auctions&lt;/a&gt; in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ba q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-19"&gt;A near-perfect and factory-sealed copy of &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time&lt;/em&gt; sold for $168,000 at &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/the-legend-of-zelda-ocarina-of-time-wata-98-a-sealed-standard-release-n64-nintendo-1998-usa/a/7284-28096.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515" target="_blank"&gt;Heritage Auctions&lt;/a&gt; in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bc q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;The first 3D entry in the Zelda franchise, &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time&lt;/em&gt; was a big hit for Nintendo when it was released in 1998. It’s one of the gaming company’s best-selling N64 games, with more than &lt;a href="https://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/world-records/88161-best-selling-legend-of-zelda-videogame-single-platform" target="_blank"&gt;7 million copies&lt;/a&gt; sold.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bd q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-20"&gt;The first 3D entry in the Zelda franchise, &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time&lt;/em&gt; was a big hit for Nintendo when it was released in 1998. It’s one of the gaming company’s best-selling N64 games, with more than &lt;a href="https://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/world-records/88161-best-selling-legend-of-zelda-videogame-single-platform" target="_blank"&gt;7 million copies&lt;/a&gt; sold.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bf q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mario Kart 64&lt;/em&gt; // $144,000&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bg q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-21"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mario Kart 64&lt;/em&gt; // $144,000&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bi q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9_F4I_3xoCQ--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bj q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bk q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bm q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Produced by Shigeru Miyamoto and directed by Hideki Konno, &lt;em&gt;Mario Kart 64&lt;/em&gt; was the first 3D entry in the Mario Kart franchise. It became the second-most popular game for the N64, selling nearly 10 million copies.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bn q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-23"&gt;Produced by Shigeru Miyamoto and directed by Hideki Konno, &lt;em&gt;Mario Kart 64&lt;/em&gt; was the first 3D entry in the Mario Kart franchise. It became the second-most popular game for the N64, selling nearly 10 million copies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bp q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;In 2022, Heritage Auctions sold the highest graded version (&lt;a href="https://www.watagames.com/"&gt;9.6 out of 10&lt;/a&gt; from Wata Games) of &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/mario-kart-64-wata-96-a-sealed-n64-nintendo-1996-usa/a/7286-28139.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mario Kart 64&lt;/em&gt; for $144,000&lt;/a&gt;. The copy was a “red label” edition of the game, which was an early production run before &lt;em&gt;Mario Kart 64&lt;/em&gt; reached 1 million units sold. After hitting the 1-million-unit mark, Nintendo added a “Player’s Choice” badge to all new copies of the game.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bq q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-24"&gt;In 2022, Heritage Auctions sold the highest graded version (&lt;a href="https://www.watagames.com/"&gt;9.6 out of 10&lt;/a&gt; from Wata Games) of &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/mario-kart-64-wata-96-a-sealed-n64-nintendo-1996-usa/a/7286-28139.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mario Kart 64&lt;/em&gt; for $144,000&lt;/a&gt;. The copy was a “red label” edition of the game, which was an early production run before &lt;em&gt;Mario Kart 64&lt;/em&gt; reached 1 million units sold. After hitting the 1-million-unit mark, Nintendo added a “Player’s Choice” badge to all new copies of the game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bs q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transformers: Beast Wars Transmetals&lt;/em&gt; // $37,500&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bt q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-25"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transformers: Beast Wars Transmetals&lt;/em&gt; // $37,500&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bv q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a-JuQ-SxqUM--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bw q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bx q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bz q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Released in 1999, &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/transformers-beast-wars-transmetals-cgc-94-a-sealed-blockbuster-exclusive-n64-bam-2000-usa/a/7411-28072.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transformers: Beast Wars Transmetals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was another Blockbuster exclusive. That meant you had to rent it from the video store chain to play it on the N64. It’s a collector’s item today, and a complete and sealed copy in mint condition sold for $37,500 at Heritage Auctions in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c0 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-27"&gt;Released in 1999, &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/transformers-beast-wars-transmetals-cgc-94-a-sealed-blockbuster-exclusive-n64-bam-2000-usa/a/7411-28072.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transformers: Beast Wars Transmetals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was another Blockbuster exclusive. That meant you had to rent it from the video store chain to play it on the N64. It’s a collector’s item today, and a complete and sealed copy in mint condition sold for $37,500 at Heritage Auctions in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c2 q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kobe Bryant in NBA Courtside&lt;/em&gt; // $33,600&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c3 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-28"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kobe Bryant in NBA Courtside&lt;/em&gt; // $33,600&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c5 q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ifo85tFLxDw--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c6 q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c7 q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c9 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/kobe-bryant-in-nba-courtside-wata-98-a-sealed-pixel-esrb-early-production-n64-nintendo-1998-usa/a/7286-28135.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kobe Bryant in NBA Courtside&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; debuted in 1998, making the title star the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/athletic/3094234/2022/01/28/forgotten-fridays-how-kobe-bryant-became-the-youngest-player-to-start-an-nba-game-25-years-ago/" target="_blank"&gt;youngest player&lt;/a&gt; in NBA history to have his own video game at age 18. The five-on-five basketball game featured real NBA teams and players from the season (with the exceptions of Michael Jordan and Latrell Sprewell). A copy sold for $33,600 at Heritage Auctions in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ca q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-30"&gt;&lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/kobe-bryant-in-nba-courtside-wata-98-a-sealed-pixel-esrb-early-production-n64-nintendo-1998-usa/a/7286-28135.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kobe Bryant in NBA Courtside&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; debuted in 1998, making the title star the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/athletic/3094234/2022/01/28/forgotten-fridays-how-kobe-bryant-became-the-youngest-player-to-start-an-nba-game-25-years-ago/" target="_blank"&gt;youngest player&lt;/a&gt; in NBA history to have his own video game at age 18. The five-on-five basketball game featured real NBA teams and players from the season (with the exceptions of Michael Jordan and Latrell Sprewell). A copy sold for $33,600 at Heritage Auctions in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cc q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoldenEye 007&lt;/em&gt; // $33,600&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cd q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-31"&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoldenEye 007&lt;/em&gt; // $33,600&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cf q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iZy63vxe5G0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cg q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ch q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cj q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;While it’s the third-most popular game in N64 history, finding an unopened and near-perfect copy of the first-person shooter &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/goldeneye-007-wata-94-a-sealed-n64-nintendo-1997-usa/a/7263-28165.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoldenEye 007&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a rarity. In fact, Heritage Auctions sold one from its original production run for $33,600 in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ck q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-33"&gt;While it’s the third-most popular game in N64 history, finding an unopened and near-perfect copy of the first-person shooter &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/goldeneye-007-wata-94-a-sealed-n64-nintendo-1997-usa/a/7263-28165.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoldenEye 007&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a rarity. In fact, Heritage Auctions sold one from its original production run for $33,600 in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cm q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wave Race 64&lt;/em&gt; // $21,000&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cn q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-34"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wave Race 64&lt;/em&gt; // $21,000&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cp q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WnmEqfgNjkE--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cq q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cr q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ct q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Considered “&lt;em&gt;F-Zero&lt;/em&gt; on water,” &lt;em&gt;Wave Race 64&lt;/em&gt;—which was produced by Shigeru Miyamoto—was a racing game with high-speed boats and jet skis. The game sold for $21,000 at &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/wave-race-64-wata-94-a-sealed-n64-nintendo-1996-usa/a/7288-28150.s" target="_blank"&gt;Heritage Auctions&lt;/a&gt; in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cu q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-36"&gt;Considered “&lt;em&gt;F-Zero&lt;/em&gt; on water,” &lt;em&gt;Wave Race 64&lt;/em&gt;—which was produced by Shigeru Miyamoto—was a racing game with high-speed boats and jet skis. The game sold for $21,000 at &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/wave-race-64-wata-94-a-sealed-n64-nintendo-1996-usa/a/7288-28150.s" target="_blank"&gt;Heritage Auctions&lt;/a&gt; in 2022.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cw q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: While the game was popular on the N64, there hasn’t been a new entry in the series since &lt;em&gt;Wave Race: Blue Storm&lt;/em&gt; for the Nintendo GameCube in 2001.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cx q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-37"&gt;Fun fact: While the game was popular on the N64, there hasn’t been a new entry in the series since &lt;em&gt;Wave Race: Blue Storm&lt;/em&gt; for the Nintendo GameCube in 2001.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cz q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Donkey Kong 64&lt;/em&gt; // $18,000&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d0 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-38"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Donkey Kong 64&lt;/em&gt; // $18,000&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d2 q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=npuuTBlEb1U--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d3 q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d4 q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d6 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;In 2022, Heritage Auction sold an unopened and near-perfect copy of &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/donkey-kong-64-vga-95-mint-uncirculated-sealed-n64-nintendo-1999-usa/a/7288-28130.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Donkey Kong 64&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for $18,000. The item that was put up for sale was actually an “&lt;a href="https://comicsandcrypto.io/blog/the-significance-of-uncirculated-collectibles" target="_blank"&gt;uncirculated&lt;/a&gt;” copy, which means the game was never on sale to the public and never left its original shipping box. The cartridge is as flawless and pristine as it gets.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d7 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-40"&gt;In 2022, Heritage Auction sold an unopened and near-perfect copy of &lt;a href="https://comics.ha.com/itm/video-games/nintendo/donkey-kong-64-vga-95-mint-uncirculated-sealed-n64-nintendo-1999-usa/a/7288-28130.s?ic4=GalleryView-ShortDescription-071515" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Donkey Kong 64&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for $18,000. The item that was put up for sale was actually an “&lt;a href="https://comicsandcrypto.io/blog/the-significance-of-uncirculated-collectibles" target="_blank"&gt;uncirculated&lt;/a&gt;” copy, which means the game was never on sale to the public and never left its original shipping box. The cartridge is as flawless and pristine as it gets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org"&gt;Adblock test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org/acceptable.html"&gt;(Why?)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>These Are the Top Trending Pet Costumes for Halloween</title><link>https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/pets/top-trending-pet-halloween-costumes?utm_source=RSS</link><description>&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9n q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/most-popular-halloween-costumes"&gt;Halloween costumes&lt;/a&gt; are a highlight of the spookiest month of the year, and the cutest versions come in pet form. This year is no different; pet sitter service &lt;a href="https://www.rover.com/blog/halloween-fun-and-safety/" target="_blank"&gt;Rover&lt;/a&gt; surveyed 1000 pet parents in September 2025 to find out which costumes you can expect to see on our four-legged friends.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9o q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="mt-[18px] md:mt-0 mb-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/most-popular-halloween-costumes"&gt;Halloween costumes&lt;/a&gt; are a highlight of the spookiest month of the year, and the cutest versions come in pet form. This year is no different; pet sitter service &lt;a href="https://www.rover.com/blog/halloween-fun-and-safety/" target="_blank"&gt;Rover&lt;/a&gt; surveyed 1000 pet parents in September 2025 to find out which costumes you can expect to see on our four-legged friends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9q q:key=vcaa:--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9r q:key=StMp:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=Lf_2--&gt;&lt;ol class="toc text-primary mt-4 flex flex-col gap-y-2.5 ps-10 list-decimal [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/pets/top-trending-pet-halloween-costumes?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-2"&gt;What Pets Will Be Wearing This Halloween&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/pets/top-trending-pet-halloween-costumes?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-6"&gt;The Top Trending Costume Categories for Cats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/pets/top-trending-pet-halloween-costumes?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-13"&gt;The Top Trending Costume Categories for Dogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/pets/top-trending-pet-halloween-costumes?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-15"&gt;Enter the Rover Costume Contest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9t q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;What Pets Will Be Wearing This Halloween&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9u q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-2"&gt;What Pets Will Be Wearing This Halloween&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9w q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_3834,h_2556,x_0,y_0/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k6n9y4msfz7rvatjdq--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9x q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9y q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=9y q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9z q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=9z q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a0 q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a1 q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a2 q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=a2 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=a1 q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog in squirrel costume" class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="2556" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_3834,h_2556/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k6n9y4msfz7rvatjdq.jpg" title="Dog in squirrel costume" width="3834" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A good boy in a good costume. | Bryant Scannell/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a6 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;The respondents’ top choices for dog and cat costumes are pretty diverse. Traditional Halloween getups, such as witches, spiders, and ghosts, are the favorites for both felines (with 44 percent of cat parents planning costumes in this category) and canines (30 percent). Food-related costumes (think a dachshund in a hot dog bun) are also quite popular for both groups—16 percent for dogs and 14 percent for cats.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a7 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-4"&gt;The respondents’ top choices for dog and cat costumes are pretty diverse. Traditional Halloween getups, such as witches, spiders, and ghosts, are the favorites for both felines (with 44 percent of cat parents planning costumes in this category) and canines (30 percent). Food-related costumes (think a dachshund in a hot dog bun) are also quite popular for both groups—16 percent for dogs and 14 percent for cats.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a9 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Sports-themed costumes, such as those of basketball players and cheerleaders, were another common choice for dogs. Sixteen percent of owners planning to dress their dogs in these outfits. Meanwhile, six percent of people want to dress their cats up as other animals, such as a lion or a bat. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aa q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-5"&gt;Sports-themed costumes, such as those of basketball players and cheerleaders, were another common choice for dogs. Sixteen percent of owners planning to dress their dogs in these outfits. Meanwhile, six percent of people want to dress their cats up as other animals, such as a lion or a bat.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ac q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;The Top Trending Costume Categories for Cats&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ad q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-6"&gt;The Top Trending Costume Categories for Cats&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=af q:key=vcaa:&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Halloween classics &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Food-themed&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Other animals&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ag q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;ol class="!list-decimal ml-5 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-7"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Halloween classics&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Food-themed&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Other animals&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ai q:key=vcaa:8--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aj q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ak q:key=vcaa:&lt;h3&gt;You May Also Like:&lt;/h3&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=al q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h3 class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-9"&gt;You May Also Like:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=an q:key=vcaa:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/holidays/halloween/halloween-party-food-ideas"&gt;9 Deliciously Frightening Food Ideas for Your Halloween Party&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/quizzes/edgar-allan-poe-story-quote-quiz"&gt;Quiz: Can You Match the Edgar Allan Poe Quote to the Short Story?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/posts/national-park-ghosts"&gt;6 Legendary Beings Who Haunt America’s National Parks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ao q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aq q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ar q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-11"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=at q:key=vcaa:12--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=au q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=av q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;The Top Trending Costume Categories for Dogs&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aw q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-13"&gt;The Top Trending Costume Categories for Dogs&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ay q:key=vcaa:&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Halloween classics &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Food-themed&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sports-themed &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=az q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;ol class="!list-decimal ml-5 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-14"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Halloween classics&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Food-themed&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sports-themed &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b1 q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;Enter the Rover Costume Contest&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b2 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-15"&gt;Enter the Rover Costume Contest&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b4 q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_2121,h_1414,x_0,y_0/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k6na1zkf9frhkj5naz--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b5 q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b6 q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=b6 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b7 q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=b7 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b8 q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b9 q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ba q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=ba q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=b9 q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="Dogs are celebrating Halloween outdoor, jack-o-lantern as decoration. Greeting card or poster." class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="1414" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_2121,h_1414/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k6na1zkf9frhkj5naz.jpg" title="Dogs are celebrating Halloween outdoor, jack-o-lantern as decoration. Greeting card or poster." width="2121" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Oh, so scary. | Tatiana Maksimova/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=be q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Rover also has a costume contest in store for those who want to go all out for Halloween. A panel of pet experts will choose winners in these three categories: Best in Boo, Monstrously Scary, and Most Fur-ocious. Each winner will receive a $100 Rover credit for dog walking or pet sitting as well as a gift box. Their pet will also be featured on Rover’s Instagram account.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bf q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-17"&gt;Rover also has a costume contest in store for those who want to go all out for Halloween. A panel of pet experts will choose winners in these three categories: Best in Boo, Monstrously Scary, and Most Fur-ocious. Each winner will receive a $100 Rover credit for dog walking or pet sitting as well as a gift box. Their pet will also be featured on Rover’s Instagram account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bh q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;To enter the contest, all you have to do is:&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bi q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-18"&gt;To enter the contest, all you have to do is:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bk q:key=vcaa:&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Post a photo of your pet in costume to your Instagram feed&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tag @roverdotcom&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Include #RoverCostumeContest in the caption &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bl q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;ol class="!list-decimal ml-5 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-19"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Post a photo of your pet in costume to your Instagram feed&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tag @roverdotcom&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Include #RoverCostumeContest in the caption&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bn q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;You’ll have until October 20, 2025, to sign up. Winners will be announced the next day.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bo q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-20"&gt;You’ll have until October 20, 2025, to sign up. Winners will be announced the next day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bq q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;If you’re planning to dress up your pet, ensure that the costume is safe and comfortable. The &lt;a href="https://www.animalhumanesociety.org/resource/seven-tips-safe-pet-costumes" target="_blank"&gt;Animal Humane Society&lt;/a&gt; advises against costumes with small pieces that can be swallowed. It’s also best to let your pet sniff the costume before having them wear it to help them acclimate. You can also offer treats while your pet wears the costume and play with them so they can build positive associations with it. If the animal shows no sign of getting used to the outfit, though, don’t force them to wear it. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=br q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-21"&gt;If you’re planning to dress up your pet, ensure that the costume is safe and comfortable. The &lt;a href="https://www.animalhumanesociety.org/resource/seven-tips-safe-pet-costumes" target="_blank"&gt;Animal Humane Society&lt;/a&gt; advises against costumes with small pieces that can be swallowed. It’s also best to let your pet sniff the costume before having them wear it to help them acclimate. You can also offer treats while your pet wears the costume and play with them so they can build positive associations with it. If the animal shows no sign of getting used to the outfit, though, don’t force them to wear it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org"&gt;Adblock test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org/acceptable.html"&gt;(Why?)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 22:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>These Ecovacs robot vacuums are already up to 53% off for Amazon Prime Big Deal Days</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/ecovacs-robot-vacuum-window-cleaner-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Let the robots do the work of cleaning your home. Ecovacs robot vacuums and mops are on sale along with automatic window cleaners for Prime Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/ecovacs-robot-vacuum-window-cleaner-prime-day-deals/"&gt;These Ecovacs robot vacuums are already up to 53% off for Amazon Prime Big Deal Days&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 20:38:14 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Universities can turn AI from a threat to an opportunity by teaching critical thinking</title><link>https://theconversation.com/universities-can-turn-ai-from-a-threat-to-an-opportunity-by-teaching-critical-thinking-266187</link><description>Employers and societies demand graduates who can evaluate information and make sound judgments.</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 04:03:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>