<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/merged-feed/merged.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS from multiple sources</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/merged-feed/merged.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 18:21:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Why do smart people get hooked on wellness trends? Personality traits may play a role</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-do-smart-people-get-hooked-on-wellness-trends-personality-traits-may-play-a-role-263041</link><description>Certain personality traits may help explain why some educated, well-intentioned people sometimes reject conventional medicine in favour of fringe practices.</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:35:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Are you really an ISFJ? The truth about personality tests – and why we keep taking them</title><link>https://theconversation.com/are-you-really-an-isfj-the-truth-about-personality-tests-and-why-we-keep-taking-them-261183</link><description>Tests such as Myers-Briggs promise self-discovery – but here’s why you shouldn’t take them too seriously.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 05:11:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1 in 3 teens has thought about suicide this year. Here’s what to look for – and where to get help</title><link>https://theconversation.com/1-in-3-teens-has-thought-about-suicide-this-year-heres-what-to-look-for-and-where-to-get-help-263422</link><description>A suicide attempt doesn’t always involve prior planning or thinking. But there are warnings signs.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 05:18:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why people embrace conspiracy theories: it’s about community, not gullibility</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-people-embrace-conspiracy-theories-its-about-community-not-gullibility-262276</link><description>Far from being isolated outsiders, conspiracy theorists enjoy thriving communities that recruit and organise activism.</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 12:09:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eating disorder symptoms in teens can be traced back to family hardship, new study shows</title><link>https://theconversation.com/eating-disorder-symptoms-in-teens-can-be-traced-back-to-family-hardship-new-study-shows-263529</link><description>It’s a stereotype that eating disorders mainly affect people from wealthy backgrounds.</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 01:28:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Burnt out and radicalised: how workplace exhaustion breeds extremist thinking – new study</title><link>https://theconversation.com/burnt-out-and-radicalised-how-workplace-exhaustion-breeds-extremist-thinking-new-study-261123</link><description>Our research found a link between burnout and support for extremist violence.</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 08:28:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Defendants in sexual assault cases are just as likely to misremember the event as alleged victims – new study</title><link>https://theconversation.com/defendants-in-sexual-assault-cases-are-just-as-likely-to-misremember-the-event-as-alleged-victims-new-study-262841</link><description>In court, scrutiny is normally focused on the alleged victim’s ability to recall details from the event.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 10:05:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Phubbing’: why ignoring your partner for your phone infuriates certain people – and causes them to retaliate</title><link>https://theconversation.com/phubbing-why-ignoring-your-partner-for-your-phone-infuriates-certain-people-and-causes-them-to-retaliate-263963</link><description>Research shows that ‘phubbing’ – ignoring a partner to look at your phone – can lower relationship satisfaction and spark retaliation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 10:50:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why scammers fake illness for cash, according to a psychologist</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-scammers-fake-illness-for-cash-according-to-a-psychologist-263264</link><description>What type of person lies to friends and family about having cancer?</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 20:03:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What does it mean to become an adult? In Namibia, it’s caring for others</title><link>https://theconversation.com/what-does-it-mean-to-become-an-adult-in-namibia-its-caring-for-others-263223</link><description>There is no single way of becoming an adult in the world.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 13:53:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>65,000 Pennsylvania kids have a parent in prison or jail − here’s what research says about the value of in-person visits</title><link>https://theconversation.com/65-000-pennsylvania-kids-have-a-parent-in-prison-or-jail-heres-what-research-says-about-the-value-of-in-person-visits-262185</link><description>In-person visits in prisons and jails can strengthen family relationships and reduce recidivism.</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 12:28:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What we’ve learned about narcissism over the past 30 years</title><link>https://theconversation.com/what-weve-learned-about-narcissism-over-the-past-30-years-258505</link><description>Narcissism is a picture that includes insecurity, emotional sensitivity and surprising fragility.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 14:27:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mass hysteria at Heathrow airport – how social contagion works</title><link>https://theconversation.com/mass-hysteria-at-heathrow-airport-how-social-contagion-works-264900</link><description>Heathrow’s Terminal 4 evacuation shows the power of social contagion.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:02:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How our minds trick us into thinking we are being greener than we really are</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-our-minds-trick-us-into-thinking-we-are-being-greener-than-we-really-are-263959</link><description>Adding “green” products to your food basket doesn’t reduce its carbon footprint – even though we think it does.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:37:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Racism isn’t innate – here are five psychological stages that may lead to it</title><link>https://theconversation.com/racism-isnt-innate-here-are-five-psychological-stages-that-may-lead-to-it-264391</link><description>There is no genetic or biological basis for dividing the human race into distinct “races.”</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The real scientific insights from Bryan Johnson’s immortality quest</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495156-the-real-scientific-insights-from-bryan-johnsons-immortality-quest/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Tech millionaire turned longevity pioneer Bryan Johnson devotes more than 6 hours a day to trialling different methods to turn back the clock. Can the rest of us learn anything from his radical approach?</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:01 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What’s the secret to living well beyond the average life expectancy?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495136-whats-the-secret-to-living-well-beyond-the-average-life-expectancy/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Many of us know people who live into their 90s, but hardly anyone makes it to 100. Studies are now revealing that factors that really make a difference</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:11 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How to nurture the right mindset for living to 100</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495108-how-to-nurture-the-right-mindset-for-living-to-100/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>It’s not just diet and exercise that governs how well you age. Your mindset, social connections and sense of purpose make a big difference, and it’s never too late to start working on them</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:13 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Why caring for your microbiome is crucial if you want to live to 100</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494981-why-caring-for-your-microbiome-is-crucial-if-you-want-to-live-to-100/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Our friendly – and not so friendly – gut bacteria lie at the core of healthy ageing. Research is now revealing what it takes to maintain a youthful microbiome</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:48 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The exercises you need to do to reach 100 in great shape</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494852-the-exercises-you-need-to-do-to-reach-100-in-great-shape/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>To be truly fit in older age, you need to work on specific aspects of your fitness – and research shows that it’s never too late to reap the benefits</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The science revealing how the right diet can add a decade to your life</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494953-the-science-revealing-how-the-right-diet-can-add-a-decade-to-your-life/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Evidence shows that eating a longevity diet can dramatically lengthen your lifespan – and the sooner you start, the more of a difference it makes</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:00:57 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Serious mental illness often brings rapid weight gain – but support is missing</title><link>https://theconversation.com/serious-mental-illness-often-brings-rapid-weight-gain-but-support-is-missing-264842</link><description>People with schizophrenia and bipolar disorder gain 5kg in five years. The average person gains 1.5kg.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 09:24:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Impostor syndrome: the cost of being ‘superwoman’ at work and beyond</title><link>https://theconversation.com/impostor-syndrome-the-cost-of-being-superwoman-at-work-and-beyond-265218</link><description>Female leaders are under pressure to excel, professionally and personally, without showing weakness or strain. The emergence of neoliberal feminism helps explain why, and a milestone in psychology describes what can result.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 10:22:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ian McEwan’s new novel weaves climate change into literary mystery</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735610-500-ian-mcewans-new-novel-weaves-climate-change-into-literary-mystery/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Ian McEwan’s excellent What We Can Know is set in a UK largely swallowed up by rising seas. Emily H. Wilson explores the story of a scholar hunting a great lost poem – which may have something to with climate change</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Three simple rules for a great post-workout meal</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735610-800-three-simple-rules-for-a-great-post-workout-meal/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Taking care of your body’s nutritional needs after training doesn't have to be a headache. Grace Wade sums up three key pillars she uses to refuel with confidence</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Dramatic photos show bid to save the Javan slow loris</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735612-000-dramatic-photos-show-bid-to-save-the-javan-slow-loris/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The photos tell an unusual rescue story – the release of the critically endangered Javan slow lorises into Ujung Kulon National Park on Java Island, Indonesia, last month.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Curious kids: why do we dream?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/curious-kids-why-do-we-dream-264817</link><description>Why scientists still can’t agree what dreams are for.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 12:09:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Some viruses like to cheat – and that may be good for our health</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496881-some-viruses-like-to-cheat-and-that-may-be-good-for-our-health/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Mutations can result in viruses that infect cells, but can't copy themselves without help from other viruses - now it seems these cheats may outnumber normal viruses in a third of influenza cases, reducing the severity of infections</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:00:41 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Stunning amber deposits hold insects from the time of the dinosaurs</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496954-stunning-amber-deposits-hold-insects-from-the-time-of-the-dinosaurs/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A sand quarry in Ecuador has yielded South America’s first amber with bio-inclusions, including a spider's web and a collection of mosquitoes, beetles, flies, wasps and biting midges that lived 112 million years ago</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:00:23 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Starting HRT in early menopause may reduce women's risk of Alzheimer's</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496596-starting-hrt-in-early-menopause-may-reduce-womens-risk-of-alzheimers/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Hormone replacement therapy used within five years of the onset of menopause is associated with a lower risk of Alzheimer’s disease, while starting it later in life is associated with an increased risk</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:36:30 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Does ASMR really help with anxiety? A psychology expert explains the evidence</title><link>https://theconversation.com/does-asmr-really-help-with-anxiety-a-psychology-expert-explains-the-evidence-252181</link><description>The autonomous sensory meridian response may be linked to certain personality types and traits such as introversion.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:26:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Quantum computers have finally achieved unconditional supremacy</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496944-quantum-computers-have-finally-achieved-unconditional-supremacy/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>For the first time, researchers have mathematically proven that a quantum computer needs less computational power to solve a particular task than an ordinary computer, in a way that can never be beaten</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:00:46 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Naming and categorizing objects is part of how young kids develop executive function skills – new research</title><link>https://theconversation.com/naming-and-categorizing-objects-is-part-of-how-young-kids-develop-executive-function-skills-new-research-255943</link><description>Kids with good executive function tend to grow up to be financially stable, healthy, productive adults. Past attempts to teach these skills have flopped. New brain research on language may change that.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 12:39:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Where you store fat may influence the effect it has on your brain</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496947-where-you-store-fat-may-influence-the-effect-it-has-on-your-brain/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Data from more than 18,000 people suggests that where excess fat is stored in the body influences its effects on brain structure, activity and health</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:55:22 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Atmospheric hydrogen is rising, which may be a problem for the climate</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497053-atmospheric-hydrogen-is-rising-which-may-be-a-problem-for-the-climate/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Ice core records of atmospheric hydrogen reveal a huge rise in concentration since the Industrial Revolution which has contributed to global warming – and could sway the debate over hydrogen as a fuel</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:31:33 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>One blood sample could reveal the age of 11 of your organs and systems</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497154-one-blood-sample-could-reveal-the-age-of-11-of-your-organs-and-systems/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The rate that our heart or liver ages may differ from that of our immune or hormonal systems, and now it seems that a single blood test could break that down</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 17:00:24 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Unforgeable quantum money can be stored in an ultracold ‘debit card’</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497081-unforgeable-quantum-money-can-be-stored-in-an-ultracold-debit-card/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Using the quantum states of particles of light as currency could make for unforgeable transactions, and a new experiment has added a way to save some of that quantum money for future use, too</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Is reading always better for your brain than listening to audiobooks?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497112-is-reading-always-better-for-your-brain-than-listening-to-audiobooks/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Reading books and listening to audiobooks tap into different elements of cognition, each with their own benefits. So which one should you choose, and when?</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:00:40 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Cutting down the Amazon will bring extreme rain, wind and heat</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497158-cutting-down-the-amazon-will-bring-extreme-rain-wind-and-heat/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>We used to think that deforestation in the Amazon would dry out the local climate, but the effects may be even more extreme and varied</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:28:43 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How users can make their AI companions feel real – from picking personality traits to creating fan art</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-users-can-make-their-ai-companions-feel-real-from-picking-personality-traits-to-creating-fan-art-265442</link><description>The strong bonds that users are forming with their AI chatbots rest on the human imagination at work.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 12:17:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A deeper understanding of endometriosis is suggesting new treatments</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496240-a-deeper-understanding-of-endometriosis-is-suggesting-new-treatments/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The revelation that&amp;nbsp;endometriosis is linked to autoimmune disorders is opening up a whole new way to treat this painful and poorly understood condition</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:00:29 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Venus has lava tubes, and they're weird</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497220-venus-has-lava-tubes-and-theyre-weird/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>It has been suggested that lava tubes - underground tunnels carved out by molten rock - might be on Venus, and now we have direct evidence that this is the case</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:36:36 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>AI use by UK justice system risks papering over the cracks caused by years of underfunding</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-use-by-uk-justice-system-risks-papering-over-the-cracks-caused-by-years-of-underfunding-264749</link><description>The justice system is suffering from underfunding and AI won’t solve all the problems.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:16:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI and credit: How can we keep machines from reproducing social biases?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-and-credit-how-can-we-keep-machines-from-reproducing-social-biases-257756</link><description>Can we move from algorithmic discrimination to inclusive finance?</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Close relatives of emperor penguins lived in NZ some 3 million years ago. What caused their extinction?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/close-relatives-of-emperor-penguins-lived-in-nz-some-3-million-years-ago-what-caused-their-extinction-265585</link><description>Great penguins once lived in much warmer waters, but then retreated to the Southern Ocean. In a warming world, they might be able to shift their range again.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 23:27:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fish ‘fingerprints’ in the ocean reveal which species are moving homes due to climate change</title><link>https://theconversation.com/fish-fingerprints-in-the-ocean-reveal-which-species-are-moving-homes-due-to-climate-change-264683</link><description>Tracking these shifts is crucial for understanding how climate change is transforming our oceans.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 23:47:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What happens when AI comes to the cotton fields</title><link>https://theconversation.com/what-happens-when-ai-comes-to-the-cotton-fields-261526</link><description>AI can help farmers be more effective and sustainable, but its use varies from state to state. A project in Georgia aims to bring the technology to the state’s cotton farmers.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 12:49:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air quality analysis reveals minimal changes after xAI data center opens in pollution-burdened Memphis neighborhood</title><link>https://theconversation.com/air-quality-analysis-reveals-minimal-changes-after-xai-data-center-opens-in-pollution-burdened-memphis-neighborhood-265152</link><description>Analysis of the air quality data available for southwest Memphis finds that pollution has long been quite bad, but the turbines powering an xAI data center have not made it much worse.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 12:50:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hints of exotic dark matter particles could be hiding in LHC data</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497100-hints-of-exotic-dark-matter-particles-could-be-hiding-in-lhc-data/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Particles similar to axions, the leading candidate for dark matter that has long eluded detection, may have already been created in particle colliders – and remained hidden in the data</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:00:17 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The truth about narcissists: How to handle them, and can they change?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496324-the-truth-about-narcissists-how-to-handle-them-and-can-they-change/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Although narcissistic personality disorder is rarer than you might think, psychological research suggests it can come in two different types, one of which may be underdiagnosed</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:00:23 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Dinosaur found with a crocodile in its jaws named as new species</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497299-dinosaur-found-with-a-crocodile-in-its-jaws-named-as-new-species/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A fossil from about 66 million years ago reveals a species of dinosaur that is new to science, with claws that would have ripped through its prey's flesh</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:00:45 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The US-UK tech prosperity deal carries promise but also peril for the general public</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-us-uk-tech-prosperity-deal-carries-promise-but-also-peril-for-the-general-public-265728</link><description>The deliberate alignment of AI systems with the values of corporations and individuals could sour the investment.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 16:17:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mapping the structure of the brain doesn't fully explain its function</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497291-mapping-the-structure-of-the-brain-doesnt-fully-explain-its-function/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Comparing a map of the neurons in a nematode worm - the connectome - with a map of how signals travel across those neurons has revealed a surprising number of differences, suggesting that the structure of the brain alone doesn't explain how it works</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 19:00:37 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What we know, and don't, about the link between painkillers and autism</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497384-what-we-know-and-dont-about-the-link-between-painkillers-and-autism/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Scientific evidence is lacking to support the US government’s decisions to caution against using a common painkiller in pregnancy and fast-track the approval of an experimental medication for autism</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 21:30:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Spectacle, weirdness and novelty: what early cinema tells us about the appeal of ‘AI slop’</title><link>https://theconversation.com/spectacle-weirdness-and-novelty-what-early-cinema-tells-us-about-the-appeal-of-ai-slop-265071</link><description>Just as the gimmicky first films evolved into a sophisticated medium, will we look back on today’s AI-generated video as the beginnings of a new art form?</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 01:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mary Roach’s New Book Replaceable You Explores Challenges in Replacing Body Parts</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/mary-roachs-new-book-replaceable-you-explores-challenges-in-replacing-body/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mary Roach unpacks the millennia-long effort to replace failing body parts&amp;mdash;and the reasons that modern medicine still struggles to match the original designs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquakes Release Energy Mostly Through Heat, Not Ground Shaking</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/earthquakes-release-energy-mostly-through-heat-not-ground-shaking/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Up to 98 percent of the energy of an earthquake goes into flash heating rocks, not shaking the ground, new research shows. The finding could help yield better earthquake forecasts&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Ganges River is drying faster than ever – here’s what it means for the region and the world</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-ganges-river-is-drying-faster-than-ever-heres-what-it-means-for-the-region-and-the-world-265891</link><description>Climate change and overuse are creating a crisis for south Asia’s most important river.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:10:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How researchers are making precision agriculture more affordable</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-researchers-are-making-precision-agriculture-more-affordable-265366</link><description>Researchers have developed a tool that allows farmers to quickly and affordably test soil samples, get results in real-time, and obtain fertilizer recommendations.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 15:55:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World’s oldest person had a young microbiome and 'exceptional genome'</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497328-worlds-oldest-person-had-a-young-microbiome-and-exceptional-genome/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Scientists have studied the genetics and lifestyle factors that enabled María Branyas Morera, officially the oldest person in the world until she died last year, to reach 117 years old</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:00:05 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How faster-than-light explosions could reveal the universe’s secrets</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495828-how-faster-than-light-explosions-could-reveal-the-universes-secrets/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Some things we see in space appear to outpace light. Now we are learning to harness these bizarre optical illusions to understand the mysteries of neutron stars, gamma ray bursts and more</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:00:24 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Device with 6100 qubits is a step towards largest quantum computer yet</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497439-device-with-6100-qubits-is-a-step-towards-largest-quantum-computer-yet/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>An array of 6100 ultracold caesium atoms controlled by lasers is the largest collection of qubits ever assembled, and researchers hope they can soon turn it into the world's most advanced quantum computer</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:00:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>We can avoid the agonising wait for advances in women's healthcare</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735623-000-we-can-avoid-the-agonising-wait-for-advances-in-womens-healthcare/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Simply listening to the experiences of women with conditions such as endometriosis will help to end the long-standing inequalities they face when it comes to medical progress</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Two climate scientists on how to use emotion in the climate crisis</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735620-400-two-climate-scientists-on-how-to-use-emotion-in-the-climate-crisis/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>From anger to hope, Kate Marvel and Tim Lenton explain how to tackle the tricky feelings aroused by climate change and harness them to take action</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Are you an introvert or extrovert? Surprisingly, the answer is neither</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735622-700-are-you-an-introvert-or-extrovert-surprisingly-the-answer-is-neither/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>We are quick to place ourselves on the extremes of the social spectrum, but the truth is that personality is more malleable than you think, says Claudia Canavan</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How Taylor Swift is helping botany gain celebrity status</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735622-900-how-taylor-swift-is-helping-botany-gain-celebrity-status/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Feedback is delighted to learn that researchers have discovered what Taylor Swift is accidentally doing to rescue the science of plants from mid-ness. Just take a look at her videos – sorry, botany teaching aids</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What made solar power the most desirable energy source on the planet?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735622-800-what-made-solar-power-the-most-desirable-energy-source-on-the-planet/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>In this latest instalment of Future Chronicles, an imagined history of future inventions, Rowan Hooper explains how the creation of living solar panels transformed their impact on the world</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A compelling book about the end of the Neanderthals is a rare treat</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735620-500-a-compelling-book-about-the-end-of-the-neanderthals-is-a-rare-treat/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Forget the tropes about how violence or maybe volcanic eruptions killed off our ancient cousins, The Last Neanderthal by Ludovic Slimak offers a very different take on how they died out</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazing images expose inner world of mind-blowing plants and fungi</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735620-300-amazing-images-expose-inner-world-of-mind-blowing-plants-and-fungi/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Surreal images from a new book, Microcosms, show how confocal microscopy that uses laser scanning creates a super-sharp new journey around mind-altering plants and fungi</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>If you feel you don't really belong, here is some science-based advice</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735621-000-if-you-feel-you-dont-really-belong-here-is-some-science-based-advice/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Thinking you don’t fit in is agonising, whether you are starting at university or changing jobs. Our advice columnist, David Robson, shares some tips to change how you feel</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>We finally found the hot wind coming out of our black hole</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497671-we-finally-found-the-hot-wind-coming-out-of-our-black-hole/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Since the 1970s, astronomers have predicted that Sagittarius A*, the supermassive black hole at the centre of the Milky Way, should be sending out hot wind – they have just caught the first glimpse of it</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 20:01:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What Is Leucovorin, the Unproven Autism Drug Backed by Trump Officials?</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/what-is-leucovorin-the-unproven-autism-drug-backed-by-trump-officials/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration is backing leucovorin as a treatment for autism, despite limited evidence. Some doctors and researchers are concerned&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Goodbye petrostates, hello ‘electrostates’: how the clean energy shift is reshaping the world order</title><link>https://theconversation.com/goodbye-petrostates-hello-electrostates-how-the-clean-energy-shift-is-reshaping-the-world-order-264267</link><description>The global shift toward renewable energy is challenging old geopolitical power structures. So where does Australia stand?</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:31:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Huntington’s disease breakthrough: what to know about the gene therapy</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497677-huntingtons-disease-breakthrough-what-to-know-about-the-gene-therapy/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Huntington’s disease has been successfully treated for the first time using a gene therapy, which may be available in the US as soon as next year</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 22:07:17 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Nightmare Bacteria’ Infections Spiking, Leaving Key Carbapenem Antibiotics Useless, CDC Warns</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/nightmare-bacteria-infections-spiking-leaving-key-carbapenem-antibiotics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The infection rate of one type of carbapenem-resistant Enterobacterales bacteria has risen by more than 460 percent in recent years. Scientists say people receiving treatment in hospitals are at highest risk&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Could we have cracked one of the world's toughest climate problems?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497594-could-we-have-cracked-one-of-the-worlds-toughest-climate-problems/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>It is almost impossible to make cement without emissions, but carbon-capture-and-storage technology is finally being deployed to decarbonise the sector</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 01:01:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Digital brains’ that ‘think’ and ‘feel’: why do we personify AI models, and are these metaphors actually helpful?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/digital-brains-that-think-and-feel-why-do-we-personify-ai-models-and-are-these-metaphors-actually-helpful-265883</link><description>Metaphors help us understand complexity, but they can also be dangerous, or even misleading.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 08:49:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate change is making trees grow larger in the Amazon rainforest</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497707-climate-change-is-making-trees-grow-larger-in-the-amazon-rainforest/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Rising carbon dioxide levels have boosted the growth of trees in the Amazon rainforest over the past few decades, but it is unclear if this trend will continue</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 11:00:04 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Grattan on Friday: As the government rejects Trump’s stands, Liberal leadership aspirant Andrew Hastie sounds decidedly Trumpian</title><link>https://theconversation.com/grattan-on-friday-as-the-government-rejects-trumps-stands-liberal-leadership-aspirant-andrew-hastie-sounds-decidedly-trumpian-265860</link><description>The prime minister avoided any major pitfalls during his week in the US. Back at home, the Liberal party’s infighting has shown no signs of stopping.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:06:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bird Flu and Human Flu Viruses Could Mix in Cow Udders and Spark a Pandemic</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/bird-flu-and-human-flu-viruses-could-mix-in-cow-udders-and-spark-a-pandemic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Cells in cow udders could act as a site for human flu and bird flu viruses to swap genes and generate dangerous novel strains&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Good Conversations Don’t Require Everybody to Agree, Neuroscience Shows</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/good-conversations-dont-require-everybody-to-agree-neuroscience-shows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Brain imaging is illuminating the patterns linked to productive, positive dialogue&lt;b&gt;,&lt;/b&gt; and those insights could help people connect with others&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cheetahs naturally turned into mummies in caves in Saudi Arabia</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497320-cheetahs-naturally-turned-into-mummies-in-caves-in-saudi-arabia/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The constant temperature and low humidity of a cave network in Saudi Arabia turned cheetahs, some of which died thousands of years ago, into mummies</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:00:12 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Rivers are heating up faster than the air − that’s a problem for aquatic life and people</title><link>https://theconversation.com/rivers-are-heating-up-faster-than-the-air-thats-a-problem-for-aquatic-life-and-people-263718</link><description>River heat waves are rising faster than the pace of air heat waves. That’s a problem for fish, drinking water quality, and food and energy production.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:19:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks retreat from climate change commitments – but it’s business more than politics</title><link>https://theconversation.com/banks-retreat-from-climate-change-commitments-but-its-business-more-than-politics-265176</link><description>The Net-Zero Banking Alliance, intended to curb lending to carbon-intensive sectors, wasn’t effective and more importantly never made much business sense.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:20:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The science of defiance: A psychology researcher explains why people comply – and how to resist</title><link>https://theconversation.com/the-science-of-defiance-a-psychology-researcher-explains-why-people-comply-and-how-to-resist-264567</link><description>You don’t need to be a rebel to defy. Defiance isn’t about personality, it’s a practice – one that’s becoming essential in workplaces, politics and everyday life.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:22:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4 films that show how humans can fortify – or botch – their relationship with AI</title><link>https://theconversation.com/4-films-that-show-how-humans-can-fortify-or-botch-their-relationship-with-ai-263603</link><description>From 1980s sci-fi films to today’s blockbusters, filmmakers have wrestled with questions about what happens when humans rely on intelligent machines.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:23:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI in Africa: 5 issues that must be tackled for digital equality</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-in-africa-5-issues-that-must-be-tackled-for-digital-equality-265611</link><description>Policy-makers must grapple with an uncomfortable truth: without deliberate action, AI will magnify global divides.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:36:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nanoparticles may be the secret ingredient in making ultimate plastics</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497683-nanoparticles-may-be-the-secret-ingredient-in-making-ultimate-plastics/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Mixing nanoparticles into some common plastics made them harder to break and possibly easier to process, pointing towards a way to make better materials or packaging</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:41:37 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelensky says a destructive drone arms race looms – but dystopia isn’t inevitable</title><link>https://theconversation.com/zelensky-says-a-destructive-drone-arms-race-looms-but-dystopia-isnt-inevitable-263644</link><description>The new age of drones and AI may be terrifying, but there are reasons for thinking the dystopian possibilities of future war will be contained.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:24:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Punch Cards, Pipeline Problems, and the Future of Women in Computing</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/punch-cards-pipeline-problems-and-the-future-of-women-in-computing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Carla Brodley, founding executive director of the Center for Inclusive Computing at Northeastern University, explains how to make computer science education more accessible to everyone&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alaska’s Fat Bear Week is more than a bit of fun – for the animals, size is a matter of survival</title><link>https://theconversation.com/alaskas-fat-bear-week-is-more-than-a-bit-of-fun-for-the-animals-size-is-a-matter-of-survival-266099</link><description>Bears need to put on fat in order to survive the harsh Alaskan winters.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:31:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vanishing waters in a warming world</title><link>https://theconversation.com/vanishing-waters-in-a-warming-world-266001</link><description>Bad news for the rivers and the lakes that we’re used to.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:31:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taylor Swift’s Speech Pattern Changed over Time, Linguistics Study Shows</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/taylor-swift-speech-pattern-changed-over-time-linguistics-study-shows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An analysis of Taylor Swift&amp;rsquo;s interviews suggests her speech pattern has changed over her career&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WWI-Era Shipwrecks in Mallows Bay Form Ecological Sanctuary</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/wwi-era-shipwrecks-in-mallows-bay-form-ecological-sanctuary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly 100 years ago dozens of ships were abandoned in a shallow bay in the Potomac River. Today plants and animals are thriving on the skeletons of these vessels&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reconstructed skull gives surprising clues to our enigmatic Ancestor X</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497765-reconstructed-skull-gives-surprising-clues-to-our-enigmatic-ancestor-x/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The shared ancestor of our species, the Neanderthals and the Denisovans may be far older than we thought – which could completely change our understanding of humanity's evolution</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 20:00:46 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>AI systems can easily lie and deceive us – a fact researchers are painfully aware of</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-systems-can-easily-lie-and-deceive-us-a-fact-researchers-are-painfully-aware-of-263531</link><description>In stress-testing AI models, it’s not hard to push them to the brink and make them threaten to harm humans.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:40:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Warn, hide or stand out? How colour in the animal world is a battle for survival</title><link>https://theconversation.com/warn-hide-or-stand-out-how-colour-in-the-animal-world-is-a-battle-for-survival-265670</link><description>A global experiment has helped explain why some animals use stealthy patterns to hide from predators, while others use warning colours to avoid being eaten.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Neuroscience and Art Collide in a Posthumous ‘Composition’ by Alvin Lucier in Revivification</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/neuroscience-and-art-collide-in-a-posthumous-composition-by-alvin-lucier-in/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A museum exhibit in Australia lets visitors hear music generated by brain cells derived from the blood of a dead composer.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asteroid ‘Families’ Reveal Solar System’s Secret History</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/asteroid-families-reveal-solar-systems-secret-history/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Many asteroids are related, but their family trees can be hard to trace&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Smallmouth Bass Evolve to Evade Electric Culling in Adirondack Lake</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/smallmouth-bass-evolve-to-evade-electric-culling-in-adirondack-lake/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists electrically culled invasive fish in a 20-year battle&amp;mdash;but the fish fought back with rapid evolution&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How fast you age may be controlled by a DNA repair boss in your cells</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497492-how-fast-you-age-may-be-controlled-by-a-dna-repair-boss-in-your-cells/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>When a key protein regulator dials down DNA repair mechanisms, our cells accumulate more mutations, which may cause us to age faster</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 12:00:17 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Atmospheric chaos has sent temperatures soaring in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497898-atmospheric-chaos-has-sent-temperatures-soaring-in-antarctica/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Stratospheric temperatures in Antarctica are spiking, which could see strange weather unfold across the southern hemisphere in the coming months</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 13:00:56 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk and the making of an AI-generated martyr</title><link>https://theconversation.com/charlie-kirk-and-the-making-of-an-ai-generated-martyr-265834</link><description>In a polarized environment, the elevation of a figure into a saint does more than honor the individual. It turns a political struggle into a sacred one.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 12:31:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Babies' brains 'tick' more slowly than ours, which may help them learn</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497755-babies-brains-tick-more-slowly-than-ours-which-may-help-them-learn/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The rhythm of an infant's brain activity seems to put them in constant learning mode, whereas that of an adult may allow them to retrieve conceptual knowledge</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Did a star blow up and hit Earth 10 million years ago?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497946-did-a-star-blow-up-and-hit-earth-10-million-years-ago/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>There are signs deep beneath the Pacific Ocean that an exploding star once sent cosmic rays blasting out towards Earth, and now we have an idea of which stars may be to blame</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:09:42 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The Comey Indictment Is an Embarrassment</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/comey-indictment-trump-doj/684381/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The Justice Department should never have brought such a shoddy case.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:26:17 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How water fuels conflict in Pakistan</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-water-fuels-conflict-in-pakistan-262628</link><description>The potential of water to cause conflict is a live issue in Pakistan, with climate change only making matters worse.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:08:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novels with a certain structure are more likely to be classics</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497589-novels-with-a-certain-structure-are-more-likely-to-be-classics/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Novels need a gripping story to stay popular as the decades pass, but it seems that other less-obvious factors may also contribute to their lasting success</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 18:00:52 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Lung inflammation may make traumatic events harder to forget</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497888-lung-inflammation-may-make-traumatic-events-harder-to-forget/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Severe lung inflammation has been linked to symptoms resembling post-traumatic stress disorder in mice, which could help us better treat and prevent the mental health condition</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 19:00:07 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The Emptiness of Attacking Critics for Their Hypocrisy</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/free-speech-cancel-culture-republicans/684382/?utm_source=feed</link><description>It’s hard to defend crackdowns on free speech. It’s easier to simply claim everyone’s doing it.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:17:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NIH Funds New Autism Studies on Genes and Environment as Trump Focuses on Tylenol</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/nih-funds-new-autism-studies-on-genes-and-environment-as-trump-focuses-on/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The National Institutes of Health is investing $50 million into research on genetic and environmental factors underlying autism&amp;mdash;news that was eclipsed by President Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s recent controversial claims about acetaminophen&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hurricane Humberto and Potential Tropical Storm Imelda Complicate Forecasts</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/hurricane-humberto-and-potential-tropical-storm-imelda-complicate-forecasts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hurricane Humberto and a system that may become Tropical Storm Imelda in the coming days are swirling quite close to each other in the western Atlantic Ocean&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 21:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nexstar and Sinclair Lost Their Game of Chicken</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/kimmel-response-local-tv-stations-abc-conflict/684388/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Broadcast-media companies may be growing, but they still couldn’t afford to reject Jimmy Kimmel forever.</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Lab-Grown Organoids Could Transform Female Reproductive Medicine</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/lab-grown-organoids-could-transform-female-reproductive-medicine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial tissues that mimic the placenta, endometrium, ovary and vagina could point to treatments for common conditions such as preeclampsia and endometriosis&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two-in-one inhalers slash asthma attacks among young children</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497635-two-in-one-inhalers-slash-asthma-attacks-among-young-children/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Inhalers that combine relieving breathlessness with preventing it seem to be the most effective option for reducing asthma attacks in young children</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 07:00:54 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>People Are More Likely to Cheat When They Use AI</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/people-are-more-likely-to-cheat-when-they-use-ai/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Participants in a new study were more likely to cheat when delegating to AI&amp;mdash;especially if they could encourage machines to break rules without explicitly asking for it&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Politicized Prosecutions May Hit a Roadblock</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/nullify-political-prosecution/684378/?utm_source=feed</link><description>When the president puts his political enemies on trial on pretextual grounds, jurors have the option of refusing to convict.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 07:31:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How to take every kind of photo on your iPhone</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/how-to-take-every-kind-of-photo-on-your-iphone/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple's phones are more versatile than you might have thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/how-to-take-every-kind-of-photo-on-your-iphone/"&gt;How to take every kind of photo on your iPhone&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>This humanoid robot can cartwheel surprisingly well</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/humanoid-robot-cartwheel/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Fourier’s N1 is an open-source bot designed to boost collaboration between universities, labs, and hobbyists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/humanoid-robot-cartwheel/"&gt;This humanoid robot can cartwheel surprisingly well&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Taking Tylenol While Pregnant Is Safer Than Untreated Fevers, Doctors Say</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/taking-tylenol-while-pregnant-is-safer-than-untreated-fevers-doctors-say/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Untreated fevers during pregnancy can cause more harm than taking acetaminophen will&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Generative AI might end up being worthless — and that could be a good thing</title><link>https://theconversation.com/generative-ai-might-end-up-being-worthless-and-that-could-be-a-good-thing-266046</link><description>GenAI does some neat, helpful things, but it’s not yet the engine of a new economy — and it might not ever be.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 17:03:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>You should wash your clothes with cold water</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/wash-your-clothes-with-cold-water/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Modern laundry detergents work better in cold water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/wash-your-clothes-with-cold-water/"&gt;You should wash your clothes with cold water&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>More people are using AI in court, not a lawyer. It could cost you money – and your case</title><link>https://theconversation.com/more-people-are-using-ai-in-court-not-a-lawyer-it-could-cost-you-money-and-your-case-264340</link><description>Researchers found more than 80 cases of generative AI use in Australian courts so far – mostly by people representing themselves. That comes with serious risks.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 19:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Transport will make or break Australia’s new climate plan – and time is running out to fix it</title><link>https://theconversation.com/transport-will-make-or-break-australias-new-climate-plan-and-time-is-running-out-to-fix-it-265986</link><description>Unless transport emissions are tackled head-on, Australia’s new climate target cannot be met.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 19:02:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Illiberal America, MAGA Edition</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/maga-cancel-culture-revenge-tactics/684296/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Republicans had real grievances with progressive orthodoxy—and are using them to justify drastic reprisals.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Endangered Sharks Caught in Rare Mating Ritual beneath the Waves</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/endangered-sharks-caught-in-rare-mating-ritual-beneath-the-waves/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Food and Drug Administration plans to update the safety label for acetaminophen products, and the strongest storm on Earth this year struck several countries in East and Southeast Asia.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Extraordinary pictures show what a common antibiotic does to E. coli</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498016-extraordinary-pictures-show-what-a-common-antibiotic-does-to-e-coli/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A commonly used class of antibiotics seems to kill bacteria like E. coli by breaking down their tough armour</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:33:29 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Weaver Ants Form Complex Chains to Pull More Than 100 Times Their Weight</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/weaver-ants-form-complex-chains-to-pull-more-than-100-times-their-weight/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When more humans are added to a team, each member accomplishes less work&amp;mdash;but teams of weaver ants do better and better as more join&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When the wheels come off: Lessons from Sonoma on racing, resilience, and engine oil</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/valvoline-restore-and-protect-nascar-f1-ev-data-center-performance-fluids/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I went to Sonoma for a NASCAR race and found out heat is the bad guy, fluids are the secret weapon, and Valvoline’s engineers are basically mad scientists with pit passes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/valvoline-restore-and-protect-nascar-f1-ev-data-center-performance-fluids/"&gt;When the wheels come off: Lessons from Sonoma on racing, resilience, and engine oil&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 07:55:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Ultracold clocks could reveal how quantum physics alters time</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497886-ultracold-clocks-could-reveal-how-quantum-physics-alters-time/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The world’s best clocks may be sensitive to an odd mix of quantum and relativistic effects that would stretch time and test the boundaries of physics</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:00:34 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Will AI make cheaper personalized insurance premiums possible? Here’s why it’s a slippery slope</title><link>https://theconversation.com/will-ai-make-cheaper-personalized-insurance-premiums-possible-heres-why-its-a-slippery-slope-262787</link><description>In this age of algorithms, personalized insurance is encountering legal limits, especially the ban on discrimination. Can we balance accurate pricing, solidarity, and fairness?</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:20:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EcoFlow DELTA 3 portable power station series first impressions: More power, more versatile</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/ecoflow-delta-3-max-plus-ultra-plus-portable-power-station-first-impressions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The EcoFlow Delta 3 Ultra Plus and Delta 3 Max Plus deliver plenty of power for camping and home backup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/ecoflow-delta-3-max-plus-ultra-plus-portable-power-station-first-impressions/"&gt;EcoFlow DELTA 3 portable power station series first impressions: More power, more versatile&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 08:55:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The radioactive ‘miracle water’ that killed its believers</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/radioactive-water/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the 1920s, Radithor promised to cure everything from wrinkles to leukemia, but its unintended results were deadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/radioactive-water/"&gt;The radioactive &amp;#8216;miracle water&amp;#8217; that killed its believers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Wild chimps consume the equivalent of two glasses of wine a day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/chimps-alcohol-study/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The 'drunken monkey hypothesis' could explain why humans like alcohol so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/chimps-alcohol-study/"&gt;Wild chimps consume the equivalent of two glasses of wine a day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 09:45:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The most important mathematician you’ve (probably) never heard of</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497097-the-most-important-mathematician-youve-probably-never-heard-of/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Alexander Grothendieck was a titan in his field, making deep connections that fuelled a revolution in mathematics, before giving it all up and disappearing. Jacob Aron explores what his work meant</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:24:37 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Sunken WWII bombs make a surprising home for sea life</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/wwii-bombs-sea-life-baltic-sea/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new study finds algae, mussels, and starfish flock to munitions dumped in the Baltic Sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/wwii-bombs-sea-life-baltic-sea/"&gt;Sunken WWII bombs make a surprising home for sea life&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Lifelong Star Wars fan builds the droids of his childhood dreams</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/kurt-zimmerman-star-wars-droids/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Kurt Zimmerman brought Star Wars from a galaxy far, far away to … Michigan.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/kurt-zimmerman-star-wars-droids/"&gt;Lifelong Star Wars fan builds the droids of his childhood dreams&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:15:47 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Fully MAGA-fied Christianity</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/charlie-kirk-christian-trump/684394/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Politics, especially culture-war politics, now provides many fundamentalists and evangelicals with a sense of community and a common enemy.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:16:31 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Cannabis extract found to be effective for lower back pain</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498064-cannabis-extract-found-to-be-effective-for-lower-back-pain/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A clinical trial has found that VER-01, a drug derived from cannabis, eases chronic lower back pain without serious side effects or signs of addiction</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:00:16 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Do black holes exist and, if not, what have we really been looking at?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496031-do-black-holes-exist-and-if-not-what-have-we-really-been-looking-at/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Black holes are so strange that physicists have long wondered if they are quite what they seem. Now we are set to find out if they are instead gravastars, fuzzballs or something else entirely</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:00:19 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Our brain 'swivels' to focus on sounds from different directions</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498050-our-brain-swivels-to-focus-on-sounds-from-different-directions/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Many mammals physically pivot their ears to hone in on a particular sound, and now it seems that a similar action takes place in our brain</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:00:32 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A second runway at Gatwick airport could improve efficiency and bring down fares – an economist’s view</title><link>https://theconversation.com/a-second-runway-at-gatwick-airport-could-improve-efficiency-and-bring-down-fares-an-economists-view-265995</link><description>Planes circling over busy airports waiting for a landing slot waste fuel and drive up costs.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:18:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New broccoli hybrid can thrive in colder climates</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/new-broccoli/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;90 percent of broccoli in the US is grown in California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/new-broccoli/"&gt;New broccoli hybrid can thrive in colder climates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:35:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How Hurricane Humberto Is Pulling Tropical Storm Imelda Away from the U.S.</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-hurricane-humberto-is-pulling-tropical-storm-imelda-away-from-the-u-s/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a version of the Fujiwhara effect, Hurricane Humberto is pulling Tropical Storm Imelda eastward and away from the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World’s first mushroom-powered toilet could replace stinky porta-potties</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/first-mushroom-powered-toilet/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Fungi flush out the odor in this pilot program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/first-mushroom-powered-toilet/"&gt;World&amp;#8217;s first mushroom-powered toilet could replace stinky porta-potties&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Marsh Will-o’-the-Wisps Sparked by Strange Chemistry</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/marsh-will-o-the-wisps-sparked-by-strange-chemistry/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A phenomenon called microlightning may explain ghostly blue marsh lights&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out Samsonite luggage, backapacks, and accessories for ridiculously low prices before Prime Day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/samsonite-suitcase-backpack-deals-amazon/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Grab some high-end luggage that will last for years with these absurdly cheap deals on Samsonite bags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/samsonite-suitcase-backpack-deals-amazon/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out Samsonite luggage, backapacks, and accessories for ridiculously low prices before Prime Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:15:22 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>We may finally know what causes will-o’-the-wisps</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498087-we-may-finally-know-what-causes-will-o-the-wisps/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Mysterious flashes of light seen in swamps and bogs could be caused by burning methane or other gases, ignited by sparks that fly between bubbles in water</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 21:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>15 gorgeous images from the 2025 Bird Photographer of the Year awards</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/2025-bird-photographer-of-the-year-awards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A soaring solar eclipse, a bloodied petrel, and a resilient raven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/2025-bird-photographer-of-the-year-awards/"&gt;15 gorgeous images from the 2025 Bird Photographer of the Year awards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 19:01:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>AI in the classroom is hard to detect – time to bring back oral tests</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-in-the-classroom-is-hard-to-detect-time-to-bring-back-oral-tests-265955</link><description>A chatbot can produce text, but it can’t sustain a probing conversation about your reasoning. Our work suggests oral assessment has a role in the age of AI.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venus fly traps’ death-grip trigger discovered</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/how-venus-fly-trap-close/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The carnivorous plants know when it's time to snatch their prey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/how-venus-fly-trap-close/"&gt;Venus fly traps’ death-grip trigger discovered&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Six New Gecko Species Discovered by Loud Barking Mating Calls</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/six-new-gecko-species-discovered-by-loud-barking-mating-calls/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists found new gecko species hidden in plain sight in pristine deserts of southern Africa, thanks to their loud, barking mating calls&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Myth of the Campus Snowflake</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/college-students-free-speech/684352/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The students I encounter as a university president aren’t afraid of free speech—quite the contrary.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Astronomers captured an incredible view of M87’s black hole jet</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498113-astronomers-captured-an-incredible-view-of-m87s-black-hole-jet/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The black hole at the centre of a galaxy more than 50 million light years away is spewing out a jet of extremely hot plasma – though we have studied it for a century, we are only now seeing it in great detail</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The Judaism I Thought I Knew</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/jewish-identity-anti-semitism/684397/?utm_source=feed</link><description>“I’m just a cultural Jew,” I would tell people, knowing nothing about Jewish culture.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How China’s New Emissions Pledge Could Radically Alter Climate Change</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-chinas-new-emissions-pledge-could-radically-alter-climate-change/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s plan to reduce greenhouse gases will largely determine the world&amp;rsquo;s emissions trajectory, researchers say&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Garmin fitness trackers and smartwatches are up to 45% off during Amazon’s early Prime Day deals</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/garmin-fitness-tracker-smartwatch-early-prime-day-deal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Whether you want an intense adventure watch or a simple fitness tracker, many of Garmin's most popular models are deeply discounted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/garmin-fitness-tracker-smartwatch-early-prime-day-deal/"&gt;Garmin fitness trackers and smartwatches are up to 45% off during Amazon&amp;#8217;s early Prime Day deals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:57:07 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>October Stargazing: A supermoon, new comet, and a whole lot of meteors</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/stargazing-guide-october-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Comet C/2025 A6 (Lemmon) was only discovered in January 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/stargazing-guide-october-2025/"&gt;October Stargazing: A supermoon, new comet, and a whole lot of meteors&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Why we should be skeptical of the hasty global push to test 15-year-olds’ AI literacy in 2029</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-we-should-be-skeptical-of-the-hasty-global-push-to-test-15-year-olds-ai-literacy-in-2029-263695</link><description>Canada and other OECD countries’ plans to test students’ AI literacy in 2029 threatens to obscure essential questions about the marketing of AI.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 13:31:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Are We Alone? NASA’s Habitable Worlds Observatory Aims to Find Out</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/are-we-alone-nasas-habitable-worlds-observatory-aims-to-find-out/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Habitable Worlds Observatory is poised to tell us whether Earth-like planets are common&amp;mdash;if it can get off the ground&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Camels depicted in 12,000-year-old rock art</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/camels-rock-art-cave-saudi-arabia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The 'incredibly beautiful' cave carvings show how humans thrived in the Arabian desert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/camels-rock-art-cave-saudi-arabia/"&gt;Camels depicted in 12,000-year-old rock art&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Rock Art Discovery Reveals Unknown Arabian Nomads from 12,000 Years Ago</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/rock-art-discovery-reveals-unknown-arabian-nomads-from-12-000-years-ago/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Camels in ancient Arabia may have led hunter-gatherers through deserts once thought uninhabitable&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sea sponges may have been Earth’s first living creatures</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/earth-first-animal-sea-sponge/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The prehistoric invertebrates likely arrived about 541 million years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/earth-first-animal-sea-sponge/"&gt;Sea sponges may have been Earth’s first living creatures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:50:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The exceptionally tasty new fermented foods being cooked up in the lab</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496986-the-exceptionally-tasty-new-fermented-foods-being-cooked-up-in-the-lab/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Fermented foods make up a third of what we eat and were mostly discovered by accident centuries ago. Now a fermentation revolution is promising extraordinary new flavours and novel ways to boost gut health</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Ancient artists created giant camel engravings in the Arabian desert</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498144-ancient-artists-created-giant-camel-engravings-in-the-arabian-desert/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Almost 200 engravings created around 12,000 years ago have been discovered in Saudi Arabia, including depictions of camels etched into cliff faces over 40 metres high</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 17:00:44 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>'Funny' videos of stressed and frightened pets are no laughing matter</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498164-funny-videos-of-stressed-and-frightened-pets-are-no-laughing-matter/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Social media is awash with videos of cats and dogs getting startled or hurt for our entertainment. We should all be more alert to poor animal welfare, says Christa Lesté-Lasserre</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 17:54:42 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Egg cells made with DNA from human skin fertilised in the lab</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498183-egg-cells-made-with-dna-from-human-skin-fertilised-in-the-lab/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>An innovative use of skin cells could provide a route for same-sex couples or women with fertility problems to have children that both partners are genetically related to</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:05:44 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A Prophet’s Diagnosis</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/michigan-shooting-mormon-prophet-peace/684408/?utm_source=feed</link><description>With violence and strife erupting all around us, can Russell Nelson’s message of hope, humility, and peace elevate us above that?</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 14:39:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Buy a vintage military airplane for $25</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/buy-vintage-airplane-wyoming/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Just don’t expect to fly any of these Cold War relics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/buy-vintage-airplane-wyoming/"&gt;Buy a vintage military airplane for $25&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 14:54:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>When China makes a climate pledge, the world should listen</title><link>https://theconversation.com/when-china-makes-a-climate-pledge-the-world-should-listen-266346</link><description>Beijing has a track record of only promising what it plans to deliver. But too often the world’s attention is elsewhere.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:20:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1,500th discovered bat species is a ‘god of the island’</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/new-bat-species-bioko-island/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What better way to kick off Bat Appreciation Month?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/new-bat-species-bioko-island/"&gt;1,500th discovered bat species is a ‘god of the island’&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:03:55 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>We now know why a belly button becomes an 'innie'</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498288-we-now-know-why-a-belly-button-becomes-an-innie/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Scientists have discovered a new abdominal structure called the umbilical sheath, which anchors the remnant of the umbilical cord to deep abdominal tissues and helps determine the shape of your navel</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 21:27:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Tylenol Safe for Children? What Research Shows About Acetaminophen</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/is-tylenol-safe-for-children-what-research-shows-about-acetaminophen/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President Trump says Tylenol is not safe for young children. Here&amp;rsquo;s what the science says about acetaminophen&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Breville early Amazon Prime Day deals: Treat yourself to a high-end espresso machine or smart oven</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/breville-smart-oven-espresso-machine-early-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Invest in a new espresso machine, smart oven, or other kitchen appliances from Breville and you won't want to eat out anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/breville-smart-oven-espresso-machine-early-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Breville early Amazon Prime Day deals: Treat yourself to a high-end espresso machine or smart oven&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>We teach young people to write. In the age of AI, we must teach them how to see</title><link>https://theconversation.com/we-teach-young-people-to-write-in-the-age-of-ai-we-must-teach-them-how-to-see-259283</link><description>Generative AI changes how we see – and how we decide what’s real.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 23:44:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pete Hegseth Is Living the Dream</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/pete-hegseth-quantico/684423/?utm_source=feed</link><description>A man who retired as a major lectures hundreds of generals about the need to meet his standards.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 21:45:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Life inside Enceladus? Cassini Uncovers Complex Organic Chemistry in Saturn’s Ocean Moon</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/is-life-inside-enceladus-cassini-uncovers-complex-organic-chemistry-in/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A fresh analysis of old data has found rich organic chemistry within the hidden ocean of Saturn&amp;rsquo;s moon Enceladus&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The best new science fiction books of October 2025</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497314-the-best-new-science-fiction-books-of-october-2025/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Science fiction legend Ursula K. Le Guin is honoured with a new collection out this month, and sci-fi fans can also look forward to fiction from astronaut Chris Hadfield and award-winning authors Ken Liu and Mary Robinette Kowal</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Should We Bring the Dead Back to Life?</title><link>https://nautil.us/should-we-bring-the-dead-back-to-life-1239968/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The hidden dangers of virtual ghosts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/should-we-bring-the-dead-back-to-life-1239968/"&gt;Should We Bring the Dead Back to Life?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New Life for Rotting Seaweed</title><link>https://nautil.us/new-life-for-rotting-seaweed-1238008/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Problematic piles of &lt;i&gt;Sargassum&lt;/i&gt; could serve as useful raw material for a variety of products&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/new-life-for-rotting-seaweed-1238008/"&gt;New Life for Rotting Seaweed&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Demetre Daskalakis on RFK, Jr., Vaccine Schedule Changes and CDC’s Future</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/demetre-daskalakis-on-rfk-jr-vaccine-schedule-changes-and-cdcs-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The former director of a CDC center reveals how political ideology is undermining science, threatening vaccine policy and endangering public health across the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Engineered Microbes Pull Critical Minerals from Mining Waste</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/engineered-microbes-pull-critical-minerals-from-mining-waste/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Biomining uses engineered microbes to harvest critical minerals&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Plants are incredibly sensitive – what we learned about their response system could help protect humans</title><link>https://theconversation.com/plants-are-incredibly-sensitive-what-we-learned-about-their-response-system-could-help-protect-humans-264937</link><description>A new study created a detailed map of how plants respond to cues in the world around them.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:05:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How WWII made Hershey and Mars Halloween candy kings</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/hershey-mars-wwii/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From sugar shortages to military contracts, World War II helped make M&amp;#38;Ms and Hershey’s bars into symbols of American abundance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/hershey-mars-wwii/"&gt;How WWII made Hershey and Mars Halloween candy kings&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How brain organoids are revealing what truly makes humans unique</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498307-how-brain-organoids-are-revealing-what-truly-makes-humans-unique/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Madeline Lancaster created the first brain organoids, which have revolutionised our understanding of how the brain works - but also raised ethical questions</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:00:55 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A life-long car lover recreated the Griswold’s famous station wagon</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/griswold-car-lake-george/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A Q&amp;#38;A with Tom Dittus, the man behind the Lake George Family Truckster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/griswold-car-lake-george/"&gt;A life-long car lover recreated the Griswold&amp;#8217;s famous station wagon&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:05:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How Genetics and Diet Helped the World’s Oldest Woman Live to 117</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-genetics-and-diet-helped-the-worlds-oldest-woman-live-to-117/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Maria Branyas Morera was the oldest person in the world when she died. Scientists analysed her genes, metabolism and more&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cat-sized Jurassic reptile had the jaws of a python</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/jurassic-snake-ancestor-scotland/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;'Breugnathair elgolensis' also sported stubby gecko legs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/jurassic-snake-ancestor-scotland/"&gt;Cat-sized Jurassic reptile had the jaws of a python&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>U.S. Military Continues mRNA Vaccine Research after RFK, Jr., Cuts Funding</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/u-s-military-continues-mrna-vaccine-research-after-rfk-jr-cuts-funding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Department of Defense funds biomedical research to ensure military and pandemic preparedness. This includes mRNA vaccine projects that RFK, Jr., recently defunded&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NASA's asteroid deflection test had unexpected and puzzling outcome</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498319-nasas-asteroid-deflection-test-had-unexpected-and-puzzling-outcome/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The DART mission achieved its goal of changing one asteroid’s orbit around another, but questions remain about why the orbit continued to alter over the following month</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:00:43 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An AI tool is trying to predict your risk of getting many diseases years in advance – here’s how it works</title><link>https://theconversation.com/an-ai-tool-is-trying-to-predict-your-risk-of-getting-many-diseases-years-in-advance-heres-how-it-works-265909</link><description>Delphi-2M is the first open source, large-scale model for predicting a patient’s disease risk and when it may occur.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:31:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is clearing out its most popular Kindle eReaders with these early Prime Day deals</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/amazon-kindle-ereader-early-prime-day-deals-paperwhite-scribe/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;These are the lowest prices we have seen on Kindles across the board since the beginning of the year. That means money left over for books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/amazon-kindle-ereader-early-prime-day-deals-paperwhite-scribe/"&gt;Amazon is clearing out its most popular Kindle eReaders with these early Prime Day deals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:52:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>'We're precipitating an extermination rather than an extinction event'</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495980-were-precipitating-an-extermination-rather-than-an-extinction-event/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Broadcaster and campaigner Chris Packham is on a mission to cut overconsumption, take on fossil fuel giants and create a fairer world</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:00:33 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The mystery of highly reactive oxygen has finally been solved</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498273-the-mystery-of-highly-reactive-oxygen-has-finally-been-solved/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Singlet oxygen can be damaging in both cells and batteries but it has taken almost 60 years to work out exactly when it shows up in chemical reactions within both</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:00:42 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Autism may have subtypes that are genetically distinct from each other</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498323-autism-may-have-subtypes-that-are-genetically-distinct-from-each-other/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Autism may exist in multiple forms, with the condition's genetics and signs differing according to the age at diagnosis</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:00:53 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Daydream Your Way to Life-Changing Insights</title><link>https://nautil.us/daydream-your-way-to-life-changing-insights-1240109/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Certain kinds of mind wandering can lead to powerful epiphanies &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/daydream-your-way-to-life-changing-insights-1240109/"&gt;Daydream Your Way to Life-Changing Insights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First Treatment that Slows Huntington's Disease Comes after Years of Heartbreak</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/first-treatment-that-slows-huntingtons-disease-comes-after-years-of/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After years of heartbreak, researchers have found an experimental treatment that can slow the progression of Huntington&amp;rsquo;s disease, according to early results from a small clinical trial&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Women really do live longer than men. Here’s why.</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/why-women-live-longer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Female mammals live 12 percent longer than males, on average. It's a different story for birds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/why-women-live-longer/"&gt;Women really do live longer than men. Here&amp;#8217;s why.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Why abandoning psychedelic research in the 1970s was a blow to science</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735630-100-why-abandoning-psychedelic-research-in-the-1970s-was-a-blow-to-science/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Work on medical uses of mind-altering substances was sidelined for decades by the political backlash against drugs, a misstep that has echoes in today’s intolerance of some fields of study</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What might the humble house mouse be trying to tell us?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735632-800-what-might-the-humble-house-mouse-be-trying-to-tell-us/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Feedback is amazed to find that the audible vocalisations of the house mouse is all but unstudied in favour of the ultrasonic sounds humans can’t hear. SQUEAK!</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Why 'beauty factories' could solve two massive cosmological mysteries</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735630-200-why-beauty-factories-could-solve-two-massive-cosmological-mysteries/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Facilities that make particles called B mesons may seem obscure, but they could help explain why there is more matter than antimatter and what dark matter is, says Chanda Prescod-Weinstein</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Exploring PMS is a great idea, but The Period Brain can be simplistic</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735630-500-exploring-pms-is-a-great-idea-but-the-period-brain-can-be-simplistic/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Premenstrual syndrome and its symptoms is neglected by science, so Sarah Hill's new book is welcome. But it needs more on genetics, not just lifestyle changes, says Alexandra Thompson</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Endearing photos of bats show clever adaptations like long tongues</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735630-300-endearing-photos-of-bats-show-clever-adaptations-like-long-tongues/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>In his book The Genius Bat, ecologist Yossi Yovel explains why these mammals are a vital part of ecosystems, pollinating plants and keeping insect populations in check</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Disturbing Netflix mystery explores a world out to 'solve' adolescence</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735630-700-disturbing-netflix-mystery-explores-a-world-out-to-solve-adolescence/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Set at a strange academy in small-town Vermont, Netflix’s Wayward aims to pacify unruly teens by master manipulation. Bethan Ackerley finds a creepy, troubled world</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>New Scientist recommends Chris Hadfield's Final Orbit</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735630-600-new-scientist-recommends-chris-hadfields-final-orbit/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The books, TV, games and more that New Scientist staff have enjoyed this week</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prepare to enjoy four spectacular supermoons in a row</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg26735631-200-prepare-to-enjoy-four-spectacular-supermoons-in-a-row/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>If you are a fan of the moon, then the next four months will give you something special to watch out for, says Abigail Beall</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Americans receive the most scam calls in the world</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/spam-calls-worse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No, it's not just you AND it's getting worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/spam-calls-worse/"&gt;Americans receive the most scam calls in the world&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>PR firms are spreading climate misinformation on behalf of fossil fuel companies. Could Australia stop them?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/pr-firms-are-spreading-climate-misinformation-on-behalf-of-fossil-fuel-companies-could-australia-stop-them-266353</link><description>This week, Australian policymakers heard about the real and growing problem of climate misinformation. Stopping it would mean regulating the PR industry.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:37:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jane Goodall, Conservationist Who Transformed Our Understanding of Chimpanzees, Dies at 91</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/jane-goodall-conservationist-who-transformed-our-understanding-of/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The anthropologist was famous for her pioneering research with chimpanzees and her influence on conservation&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Evolution may explain why women live longer than men</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498396-evolution-may-explain-why-women-live-longer-than-men/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>In most mammals, females live longer than males, but in birds the trend goes the other way – a study of over 1000 species points to possible reasons for these differences</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 20:00:28 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientists predict the universe will end in ‘big crunch’</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/universe-ends-big-crunch/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Starts with a bang, ends with a crunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/universe-ends-big-crunch/"&gt;Scientists predict the universe will end in &amp;#8216;big crunch&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:43:16 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Bail Out Argentina</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/argentina-trump-milei-bailout/684427/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The Trump administration got this one right.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:06:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Jane Goodall, dogged advocate for the natural world, has died aged 91</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498629-jane-goodall-dogged-advocate-for-the-natural-world-has-died-aged-91/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Acclaimed conservationist and chimpanzee expert Jane Goodall has died, leaving behind a legacy of empathy for primates and the natural world</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 21:30:19 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>What Made Horses Rideable</title><link>https://nautil.us/what-made-horses-rideable-1240132/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How horse genetics and human culture co-evolved&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/what-made-horses-rideable-1240132/"&gt;What Made Horses Rideable&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Get an Elephant’s Attention</title><link>https://nautil.us/how-to-get-an-elephants-attention-1240180/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The secret lies in our shared language of gestures&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/how-to-get-an-elephants-attention-1240180/"&gt;How to Get an Elephant’s Attention&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Many People Have Ever Lived on Earth?</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-many-people-have-ever-lived-on-earth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Is it really possible that half of all people who have ever been age 65 or older are still alive today? We explore the amazing mathematics of demography to find out&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How playing a musical instrument helps children learn to read</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498314-how-playing-a-musical-instrument-helps-children-learn-to-read/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Learning to play an instrument has long been linked to improved reading skills among children, and we may finally understand why</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:00:57 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How Jane Goodall changed the way we see animals – and the world</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498651-how-jane-goodall-changed-the-way-we-see-animals-and-the-world/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Jane Goodall, who chronicled the social lives of chimps, has died, but she leaves a lasting legacy on how we view the natural world</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:02:18 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Bad Bunny’s Super Bowl</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/bad-bunny-super-bowl/684411/?utm_source=feed</link><description>MAGA isn’t going to like this halftime show.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:37:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Most of your actions are driven by habit, not thought – here’s why that’s not a bad thing</title><link>https://theconversation.com/most-of-your-actions-are-driven-by-habit-not-thought-heres-why-thats-not-a-bad-thing-266277</link><description>And how you can use psychology to help you break out of the habits you want to lose.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:58:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How VR and AI could help the next generation grow kinder and more connected</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-vr-and-ai-could-help-the-next-generation-grow-kinder-and-more-connected-263181</link><description>Virtual reality might seem like an unlikely way to help kids develop empathy, but the right VR environment can do just that.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:43:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swap your boiler for a money-saving heat pump</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/heat-pump-benefits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Heat pumps can save you about $370 per year and are good for the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/heat-pump-benefits/"&gt;Swap your boiler for a money-saving heat pump&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Rogue planet gains 6 billion tonnes per second in record growth spurt</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498489-rogue-planet-gains-6-billion-tonnes-per-second-in-record-growth-spurt/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A free-floating planet has been seen devouring astonishing amounts of matter, hinting that stars and planets are more alike than we thought</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:00:51 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>iOS 26 adds a new app to your iPhone. Here’s how to use it.</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/preview-app-iphone/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You're not imagining it—there is a new app on your iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/preview-app-iphone/"&gt;iOS 26 adds a new app to your iPhone. Here&amp;#8217;s how to use it.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Is China a climate goodie or baddie – or both?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/is-china-a-climate-goodie-or-baddie-or-both-266502</link><description>The country is a key driver of both emissions and solutions.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:53:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Truth About Amelia Earhart</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/amelia-earhart-truth-conspiracy/684430/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Conspiracy theories about her disappearance do a disservice to the pilot’s remarkable, flawed legacy.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:57:44 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Antarctica may have crossed a tipping point that leads to rising seas</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498509-antarctica-may-have-crossed-a-tipping-point-that-leads-to-rising-seas/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Scientists are beginning to understand the sudden loss of sea ice in Antarctica – and there is growing evidence that it represents a permanent shift with potentially catastrophic consequences</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:00:44 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The safest way to use a chainsaw, according to science</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/chainsaw-safety-tips/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Training and wearing the same material in bulletproof vests are key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/chainsaw-safety-tips/"&gt;The safest way to use a chainsaw, according to science&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:03:21 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Mind-Altering Effect of a Good Workout Routine</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/happiness-exercise-routine-emotions/684409/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Few things lift your mood more than going to the gym. Exercise your body, and your mind will thank you.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Other Martyr</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/george-floyd-charlie-kirk-martyr/684434/?utm_source=feed</link><description>MAGA has found its George Floyd.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:44:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Extreme fear of the dentist linked to childhood trauma</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/dental-fear-trauma/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A study of over 5,000 teens found a strong connection between childhood stress and dental anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/dental-fear-trauma/"&gt;Extreme fear of the dentist linked to childhood trauma&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:20:37 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>This U.S. Government Shutdown Is Very Bad for Science</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/this-u-s-government-shutdown-is-very-bad-for-science/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President Trump&amp;rsquo;s budget office lays out guidelines for mass federal lay-offs as the U.S. government grinds to a halt&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Should we worry AI will create deadly bioweapons? Not yet, but one day</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498478-should-we-worry-ai-will-create-deadly-bioweapons-not-yet-but-one-day/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>AI tools are being used to design proteins and even viruses, leading to fears these could eventually be used to evade bioweapon controls</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 20:00:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Jane Goodall’s Legacy of Challenging What It Means to Be a Scientist</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/jane-goodall-legacy-of-challenging-what-it-means-to-be-a-scientist/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Here are three big ways that Jane Goodall transformed science&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 20:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Luxury jet replaces cabin windows with video screens</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/private-jet-no-windows-otto-aerospace/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;HD cameras beam panoramic images inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/private-jet-no-windows-otto-aerospace/"&gt;Luxury jet replaces cabin windows with video screens&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Divers Who Stretch the Limits of Human Biology</title><link>https://nautil.us/the-divers-who-stretch-the-limits-of-human-biology-1240106/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The most dangerous job on Earth is at the bottom of the sea&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/the-divers-who-stretch-the-limits-of-human-biology-1240106/"&gt;The Divers Who Stretch the Limits of Human Biology&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 21:11:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Indomitable Jane Goodall</title><link>https://nautil.us/the-indomitable-jane-goodall-1240427/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Reflections from those who knew the primatologist best&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/the-indomitable-jane-goodall-1240427/"&gt;The Indomitable Jane Goodall&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 23:20:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia’s new food security strategy: what’s on the table, and what’s missing?</title><link>https://theconversation.com/australias-new-food-security-strategy-whats-on-the-table-and-whats-missing-264791</link><description>A government inquiry has made 35 recommendations to improve Australia’s food security, but there are some key gaps.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 01:05:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why coral reefs damaged by blast fishing struggle to recover — even after decades</title><link>https://theconversation.com/why-coral-reefs-damaged-by-blast-fishing-struggle-to-recover-even-after-decades-265733</link><description>Blast-fished reefs are unlikely to recover naturally without human intervention.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:36:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Our verdict on ‘The Dispossessed’: A tricky but rewarding novel</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498143-our-verdict-on-the-dispossessed-a-tricky-but-rewarding-novel/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The New Scientist Book Club has just finished reading Ursula K. Le Guin’s The Dispossessed. Most of our members enjoyed it, even if the sheer volume of ideas in the book made it a challenging read</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:00:32 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Read an extract from Our Brains, Our Selves by Masud Husain</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496548-read-an-extract-from-our-brains-our-selves-by-masud-husain/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>In this passage from Our Brains, Our Selves, winner of the Royal Society Trivedi Science Book Prize, neuroscientist Masud Husain recounts how novelist Marcel Proust became convinced, wrongly, that he'd had a stroke</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:00:36 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Our Brains, Our Selves won the Royal Society science book prize</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497944-why-our-brains-our-selves-won-the-royal-society-science-book-prize/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Sandra Knapp, chair of the judging panel for the 2025 Royal Society Trivedi Science Book Prize, explains why neurologist Masud Husain’s collection of case studies is such an enlightening, compassionate book</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:00:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An Anechoic Chamber at Nokia Bell Labs Reveals the Hidden Sounds of Your Body</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/an-anechoic-chamber-at-nokia-bell-labs-reveals-the-hidden-sounds-of-your/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Step into a room so quiet you can hear your own heartbeat&amp;mdash;and your nervous system.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kids as young as 4 innately use sorting algorithms to solve problems</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498204-kids-as-young-as-4-innately-use-sorting-algorithms-to-solve-problems/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>It was previously thought that children younger than 7 couldn't find efficient solutions to complex problems, but new research suggests that much earlier, children can happen upon known sorting algorithms used by computer scientists</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:00:11 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>20 bird species can understand each other’s anti-cuckoo call</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498809-20-bird-species-can-understand-each-others-anti-cuckoo-call/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Several species of birds from different continents use and understand similar alarm calls when they see an invader that might lay an egg in their nest – this shared call hints at the origin of language</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:00:45 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How Can Galaxies Recede from Us Faster Than the Speed of Light?</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-can-galaxies-recede-from-us-faster-than-the-speed-of-light/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When space itself expands, weird things can happen&amp;mdash;like galaxies breaking the universe&amp;rsquo;s ultimate speed limit&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What is Knot Theory? Solve These Puzzles to Find Out</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/what-is-knot-theory-solve-these-puzzles-to-find-out/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Learn the fundamentals of the burgeoning field of knot theory while solving some puzzles along the way&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ocean Acidification Threshold Pushes Earth Past Another Planetary Boundary</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/ocean-acidification-threshold-pushes-earth-past-another-planetary-boundary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earth has breached a critical boundary for ocean acidification, with potentially grim effects for ocean ecosystems and human livelihoods&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Multi-generational vulture nests hold 700 years of human artifacts</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/bearded-vulture-nest-archaeology/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Crossbow bolts, sandals, slingshots, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/bearded-vulture-nest-archaeology/"&gt;Multi-generational vulture nests hold 700 years of human artifacts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 08:33:20 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘AI actor’ Tilly Norwood is dividing Hollywood – but real acting requires humanity</title><link>https://theconversation.com/ai-actor-tilly-norwood-is-dividing-hollywood-but-real-acting-requires-humanity-266525</link><description>The outcry from established actors was immediate and heartfelt.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 12:37:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Children can be systematic problem-solvers at younger ages than psychologists had thought – new research</title><link>https://theconversation.com/children-can-be-systematic-problem-solvers-at-younger-ages-than-psychologists-had-thought-new-research-266438</link><description>By cranking up the difficulty on the test task, researchers found that children are capable of finding systematic solutions to complex problems far earlier than psychologists had believed.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 12:39:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What past education technology failures can teach us about the future of AI in schools</title><link>https://theconversation.com/what-past-education-technology-failures-can-teach-us-about-the-future-of-ai-in-schools-265172</link><description>It can take years to collect evidence that shows effective uses of new technologies in schools. Unfortunately, early guesses sometimes go seriously wrong.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 12:40:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The search for Cleopatra’s long-lost tomb leads to sunken seaport</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/cleopatra-lost-tomb-documentary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new documentary explores this 2,000-year-old mystery and a connection to the RMS 'Titanic.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/cleopatra-lost-tomb-documentary/"&gt;The search for Cleopatra’s long-lost tomb leads to sunken seaport&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out iRobot Roomba vacuums for as low as $149 with these early Prime Day deals</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/roomba-robot-vacuum-cleaner-early-amazon-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You've always wanted a robotic butler, but a Roomba is as close as you're going to get. These are the lowest Roomba prices we have seen this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/roomba-robot-vacuum-cleaner-early-amazon-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out iRobot Roomba vacuums for as low as $149 with these early Prime Day deals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:28:47 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Ants can be used to make ‘tangy’ yogurt</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/ant-yogurt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An old family recipe from Bulgaria goes under the microscope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/ant-yogurt/"&gt;Ants can be used to make &amp;#8216;tangy&amp;#8217; yogurt&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Exceptional star is the most pristine object known in the universe</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498843-exceptional-star-is-the-most-pristine-object-known-in-the-universe/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>A star found in the Large Magellanic Cloud is remarkably unpolluted by heavier elements, suggesting it is descended from the universe’s earliest stars</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:00:12 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan’s favorite beer is in peril</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/asahi-beer-cyber-attack/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Asahi Super Dry's manufacturer is suffering from a major cyberattack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/asahi-beer-cyber-attack/"&gt;Japan&amp;#8217;s favorite beer is in peril&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:22:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>There is an odd streak in the universe – and we still don’t know why</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498128-there-is-an-odd-streak-in-the-universe-and-we-still-dont-know-why/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Astronomers have long thought the universe should look generally the same in every direction, but an anomaly in the radiation from the big bang persists even after a new analysis from radio telescopes</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:00:27 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Your happiness in life may not be U-shaped - here's how it could vary</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498760-your-happiness-in-life-may-not-be-u-shaped-heres-how-it-could-vary/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>We thought happiness peaked at the beginning and end of life, but a study from Germany suggests a more pessimistic outlook for our later years</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:54:51 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Researchers are reanimating 40,000-year-old microbes</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/permafrost-microbes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;They're alive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/permafrost-microbes/"&gt;Researchers are reanimating 40,000-year-old microbes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 14:06:38 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Google’s latest AI photo-editing tool means you might not need Photoshop</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/google-ai-photo-editing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gemini 2.5 Flash Image is a major image editing upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/google-ai-photo-editing/"&gt;Google&amp;#8217;s latest AI photo-editing tool means you might not need Photoshop&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Periscope: Book Weeding, Fact-Checking, and Imperiled Fruit Fly Data</title><link>https://nautil.us/the-periscope-book-weeding-fact-checking-and-imperiled-fruit-fly-data-1240588/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What &lt;i&gt;Nautilus&lt;/i&gt; executive editor Katherine Courage has been tuning into recently&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/the-periscope-book-weeding-fact-checking-and-imperiled-fruit-fly-data-1240588/"&gt;The Periscope: Book Weeding, Fact-Checking, and Imperiled Fruit Fly Data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 20:28:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kash Patel’s Challenge Coin Is Perfect for Him</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/kash-patel-military-memento-internet/684456/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The FBI director has created a memento that symbolizes his unfitness.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:09:09 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Purge of Terrorism Prosecutors</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/terrorism-prosecutors-fired-trump-doj/684447/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The politicization of the Justice Department is making Americans less safe.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:32:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>কানাকুয়ো আর পাখির কুসংস্কার</title><link>https://www.tbsnews.net/bangla/Easel/news-details-396796</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 08:17:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Dark Energy Born inside Black Holes?</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/is-dark-energy-born-inside-black-holes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A controversial prediction about black holes and the expansion force of the universe could explain a cosmology mystery&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5 low back stretches to relieve aches and pains</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/low-back-stretches-for-aches-and-pains/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Simple moves to build strength and help prevent injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/low-back-stretches-for-aches-and-pains/"&gt;5 low back stretches to relieve aches and pains&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The ‘Best’ Colleges Aren’t the Best Forever</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/ivy-league-schools-prestige/684454/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Prestige isn’t permanent.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>A Deal That Would End Universities’ Independence</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/higher-education-compact-trump-deal/684457/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The free-speech provisions of the so-called compact are an exercise in contradiction.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>13 inspiring photos of thriving deep-sea animals</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/13-inspiring-photos-of-thriving-deep-sea-animals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A recent Schmidt Ocean Institute expedition off the coast of Uruguay discovered at least 30 suspected new species and explored a sunken warship. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/13-inspiring-photos-of-thriving-deep-sea-animals/"&gt;13 inspiring photos of thriving deep-sea animals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How a hatter and railroad clerk kickstarted cancer research</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/how-cancer-research-started/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;100 years ago, this unlikely duo discovered the first cancer ‘germ.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/how-cancer-research-started/"&gt;How a hatter and railroad clerk kickstarted cancer research&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How to use iOS 26’s new battery saving mode</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/diy/iphone-battery-saving-mode/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Get more out of your iPhone on a single charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/diy/iphone-battery-saving-mode/"&gt;How to use iOS 26’s new battery saving mode&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>These Ecovacs robot vacuums are already up to 53% off for Amazon Prime Big Deal Days</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/ecovacs-robot-vacuum-window-cleaner-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Let the robots do the work of cleaning your home. Ecovacs robot vacuums and mops are on sale along with automatic window cleaners for Prime Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/ecovacs-robot-vacuum-window-cleaner-prime-day-deals/"&gt;These Ecovacs robot vacuums are already up to 53% off for Amazon Prime Big Deal Days&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 20:38:14 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Universities can turn AI from a threat to an opportunity by teaching critical thinking</title><link>https://theconversation.com/universities-can-turn-ai-from-a-threat-to-an-opportunity-by-teaching-critical-thinking-266187</link><description>Employers and societies demand graduates who can evaluate information and make sound judgments.</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 04:03:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>অভিধানের দিন কি তবে ফুরাল?</title><link>https://www.tbsnews.net/bangla/Easel/news-details-392576</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 12:26:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Explore a bird database with 11,500 species</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/big-bird-database/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Twenty-six years ago, a PhD student's unanswered question sparked a bird data revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/big-bird-database/"&gt;Explore a bird database with 11,500 species&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Rogue planet is gobbling up 6.6 billion tons of dust per second</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/young-rogue-planet/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The cosmic oddities experience their own growth spurts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/young-rogue-planet/"&gt;Rogue planet is gobbling up 6.6 billion tons of dust per second&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 14:15:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Does AI pose an existential risk? We asked 5 experts</title><link>https://theconversation.com/does-ai-pose-an-existential-risk-we-asked-5-experts-266345</link><description>While we’re at the peak of AI hype, some people are concerned it will wipe out humanity.</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 19:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Intense rain, landslides and potholes everywhere: how climate change is trashing Australia’s roads</title><link>https://theconversation.com/intense-rain-landslides-and-potholes-everywhere-how-climate-change-is-trashing-australias-roads-264328</link><description>If you’ve noticed Australia’s roads are worse for wear, you’re not alone. Extreme weather and climate change are already taking their toll.</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 19:17:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump Is Successfully Bullying Netanyahu</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/trump-netanyahu-gaza/684462/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The more the president puts the prime minister in his place, the more likely it is that the Gaza war will end.</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 20:28:08 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Would a ban on genetic engineering of wildlife hamper conservation?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498841-would-a-ban-on-genetic-engineering-of-wildlife-hamper-conservation/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Some conservation groups are calling for an effective ban on genetic modification, but others say these technologies are crucial for preserving biodiversity</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:00:14 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The Power Grid Is Struggling. Can AI Fix It?</title><link>https://nautil.us/the-power-grid-is-struggling-can-ai-fix-it-1238071/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Renewables, EVs, and AI itself are straining the grid. These researchers have ideas to evolve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/the-power-grid-is-struggling-can-ai-fix-it-1238071/"&gt;The Power Grid Is Struggling. Can AI Fix It?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ernest Shackleton knew ‘Endurance’ had shortcomings, new study says</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/shackleton-endurance-ship-problems/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Issues with the ship's hull, deck beams, and more show the ship was no match for Antarctic sea ice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/shackleton-endurance-ship-problems/"&gt;Ernest Shackleton knew ‘Endurance’ had shortcomings, new study says&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Saturn’s Moon Enceladus May Harbor Life. Study Finds Complex Organic Molecules</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcast/episode/saturns-moon-enceladus-may-harbor-life-study-finds-complex-organic-molecules/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Saturn&amp;rsquo;s moon Enceladus shows signs of life-supporting chemistry, fungi may have shaped Earth before plants, and repeat COVID infections raise long-term health risks for kids.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2025 Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine Awarded for Discoveries Key to Treating Autoimmune Disease</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/2025-nobel-prize-in-physiology-or-medicine-awarded-for-discoveries-key-to/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mary E. Brunkow, Fred Ramsdell and Shimon Sakaguchi shared the Nobel prize for their work on peripheral immune tolerance, a process that is key to organ transplants and treatment of autoimmune diseases&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mathematicians Discover Prime Number Pattern in Fractal Chaos</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/mathematicians-discover-prime-number-pattern-in-fractal-chaos/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mathematicians have found a new way to predict how prime numbers behave&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nobel prize for medicine goes to trio for work on immune tolerance</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498910-nobel-prize-for-medicine-goes-to-trio-for-work-on-immune-tolerance/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The 2025 Nobel prize in physiology or medicine has gone to Mary Brunkow, Fred Ramsdell and Shimon Sakaguchi for their discoveries around how we keep our immune system under control</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:42:21 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How Far Does Trump’s Immunity Go?</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/trump-presidential-immunity/684413/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The Supreme Court’s 2024 decision threatens the system of international justice.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Stunning Cat Photos Reveal Feline Science</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/stunning-cat-photos-reveal-feline-science/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tim Flach captures his fascination with the science of cats in stunning photographs from his new book &lt;i&gt;Feline&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fired CDC Director Susan Monarez Speaks Out on Contentious Tenure under RFK, Jr.</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/fired-cdc-director-susan-monarez-speaks-out-on-contentious-tenure-under-rfk/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I would never do that, as a scientist,&amp;rdquo; Susan Monarez says of being asked to approve changes to vaccine recommendations without knowing the details&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shackleton knew his doomed ship wasn’t the strongest before sailing</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497696-shackleton-knew-his-doomed-ship-wasnt-the-strongest-before-sailing/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Endurance, the wooden ship that Ernest Shackleton took to Antarctica in 1915, wasn't built to withstand frozen seas – and the famous explorer knew it</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:00:13 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>We surveyed British MPs – most don’t know how urgent climate action is</title><link>https://theconversation.com/we-surveyed-british-mps-most-dont-know-how-urgent-climate-action-is-266703</link><description>New study finds both MPs and the public underestimate how quickly global emissions must be cut.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:02:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How WWI and WWII revolutionized period products</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/period-product-history/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For centuries, menstruation was managed with homemade solutions—until the world changed in a hurry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/period-product-history/"&gt;How WWI and WWII revolutionized period products&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:24:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Stephen Miller Is Going for Broke</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/miller-insurrection/684463/?utm_source=feed</link><description>The White House aide equates opposition to Trump’s agenda with terrorism—and pushes for the use of state power to suppress it.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:49:31 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>A rare coin treasure hunt kicks off in 4 American cities</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/rare-coin-treasure-hunt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Coin collectors, go dust off those running shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/rare-coin-treasure-hunt/"&gt;A rare coin treasure hunt kicks off in 4 American cities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:18:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Supreme Court Is Giving Liberals an Opportunity</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/mahmoud-taylor-liberal-pluralism/684464/?utm_source=feed</link><description>Religious accommodation is central to living in a pluralist society.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:47:21 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Annoyed by tap-to-pay? Try shaking your credit card.</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/touchless-pay-nfc-gestures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers pinpointed nine gestures that may make the technology actually touchless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/touchless-pay-nfc-gestures/"&gt;Annoyed by tap-to-pay? Try shaking your credit card.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Earth has a space tornado problem</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/space-tornado-study/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;'This is a matter of national security.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/space-tornado-study/"&gt;Earth has a space tornado problem&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>What’s my Alzheimer’s risk, and can I really do anything to change it?</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2497851-whats-my-alzheimers-risk-and-can-i-really-do-anything-to-change-it/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Can you escape your genetic inheritance, and do lifestyle changes actually make a difference? Daniel Cossins set out to understand what the evidence on Alzheimer’s really means for him</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:00:12 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>General relativity might save some planets from death</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498970-general-relativity-might-save-some-planets-from-death/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>Some habitable worlds orbiting dead stars could be kept alive for aeons thanks to a quirk of Einstein’s theory of gravity</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 18:00:29 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How extreme temperatures strain minds and bodies: a Karachi case study</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-extreme-temperatures-strain-minds-and-bodies-a-karachi-case-study-262983</link><description>Sleeplessness, anxiety and invisible care work show why extreme heat is a public-health emergency.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:31:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vast ancient Egyptian temple dated to Old Kingdom</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/science/karnak-temple-age-egypt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Karnak Temple's age has stumped archaeologists for decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/science/karnak-temple-age-egypt/"&gt;Vast ancient Egyptian temple dated to Old Kingdom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:10:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>From the telegraph to AI, our communications systems have always had hidden environmental costs</title><link>https://theconversation.com/from-the-telegraph-to-ai-our-communications-systems-have-always-had-hidden-environmental-costs-263811</link><description>The telegraph was hailed for its revolutionary ability to span distance. Now AI is being hailed as a great leap forward. But both came with environmental costs.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 19:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Review of "Fragile Minds"</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/chemically-imbalanced/202510/review-of-fragile-minds</link><description>"Fragile Minds" is a book that reveals uncomfortable truths about the nature and purpose of mental health services.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:11:07 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Newly discovered deep-sea lanternshark glows in the waters near Australia</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/deep-sea-lantern-shark/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The tiny shark and a ghost-like crab are two of the latest species uncovered in a yearslong expedition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/deep-sea-lantern-shark/"&gt;Newly discovered deep-sea lanternshark glows in the waters near Australia&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:15:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>AI Literacy Is Just Digital and Media Literacy in Disguise</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/raising-humans-in-a-digital-world/202510/ai-literacy-is-just-digital-and-media-literacy-in</link><description>AI—with its billions in investments, immense potential, and profound risks—has made policymakers finally pay attention to what students have needed all along.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:28:50 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Galaxies fling out matter much more violently than we thought</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2498905-galaxies-fling-out-matter-much-more-violently-than-we-thought/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>An analysis of the afterglow of the big bang sheds light on how black holes distribute mass in the universe, and why some matter previously seemed to have been missing</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 20:44:38 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Up your content creation game with these discounted DJI action cameras during Amazon’s Big Deal Days sale</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/dji-action-camera-gimbal-deals-amazon-prime-day/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Whether you're an aspiring YouTuber or just want better home movies, these DJI filmmaking tools are worth the investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/dji-action-camera-gimbal-deals-amazon-prime-day/"&gt;Up your content creation game with these discounted DJI action cameras during Amazon&amp;#8217;s Big Deal Days sale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 16:33:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>10 Ways You May Have Been Emotionally Invalidated as a Child</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/childhood-emotional-neglect/202510/10-ways-you-may-have-been-emotionally-invalidated-as-a</link><description>If your childhood feelings were ignored or dismissed, the effects may linger today. Learn the hidden ways this shows up and how to start healing.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:10:51 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out Ninja air fryers, blenders, indoor grills, and other kitchen essentials during its Prime Day sale</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/ninja-kitchen-appliance-air-fryer-blender-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Air fryers, blenders, cookware, cutlery, and more kitchen equipment is deeply discounted during Amazon's annual Prime Day sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/ninja-kitchen-appliance-air-fryer-blender-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out Ninja air fryers, blenders, indoor grills, and other kitchen essentials during its Prime Day sale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:32:20 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Scars, Anger, and the Songs that Carry Us</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/resonant-minds/202509/scars-anger-and-the-songs-that-carry-us</link><description>Anger can destroy—or sustain. Here's how fury, music, and gratitude turned one woman's cancer scars into symbols of resilience and love.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:35:12 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Tourists Sometimes Struggle to “Do the Right Thing”</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/culture-conscious/202510/why-tourists-sometimes-struggle-to-do-the-right-thing</link><description>Planning to visit a foreign country soon? Intercultural communications experts have helpful advice about how to navigate unfamiliar territory.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:40:49 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>A WNBA Star Goes Scorched-Earth</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/wnba-commissioner-problem/684460/?utm_source=feed</link><description>With the league more popular than ever, players know their worth—and they aren’t afraid to let leadership know it.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Get faster, more reliable internet with these Prime Day deals on TP-Link routers and networking gear</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/tp-link-router-networking-deals-amazon-prime-day/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Save money while you upgrade your home or office WiFi with these steep Amazon Prime Big Deal Days deals on TP-Link gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/tp-link-router-networking-deals-amazon-prime-day/"&gt;Get faster, more reliable internet with these Prime Day deals on TP-Link routers and networking gear&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 18:00:30 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Finding Generosity and Compassion in the Crevices of Life</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-art-of-now/202510/finding-generosity-and-compassion-in-the-crevices-of-life</link><description>Can random acts of kindness help us cope with difficulty? Here are some lessons we can learn from the writer Franz Kafka.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 18:40:40 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Treat yourself to these Prime Day deals on Breville espresso machines and juicers</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/breville-smart-oven-coffee-machine-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Breville's high-end kitchen appliances don't go on sale often, but these Prime Day deals are a great time to upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/breville-smart-oven-coffee-machine-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Treat yourself to these Prime Day deals on Breville espresso machines and juicers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 19:01:01 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Don’t Kill Spotted Lanternflies</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/human-bureaucracy/202510/dont-kill-spotted-lanternflies</link><description>Personal Perspective: In a world that rewards harshness and control, pausing before an act of aggression, even to a bug, can protect something deeper: our capacity to care.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 19:06:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaslighters Target Our Brains' Dependence on Others</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-bullied-brain/202510/gaslighters-target-our-brains-dependence-on-others</link><description>Our brains evolved with a need to belong and a dependence on trusted others to co-create reality. This dependence puts us all at risk for gaslighting.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 19:54:06 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>These De’Longhi coffee and espresso machine Prime Day deals are worth splurging on</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/delonghi-coffee-espresso-machine-prime-day-deals-amazon/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;De'Longhi makes some of our very favorite coffee and espresso machines and these Prime Day deals have them at their lowest prices of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/delonghi-coffee-espresso-machine-prime-day-deals-amazon/"&gt;These De&amp;#8217;Longhi coffee and espresso machine Prime Day deals are worth splurging on&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 22:51:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon Prime Day is happening now and these 100+ deals are worth checking out</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/best-early-prime-day-deals-apple-samsung-october/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Check out our updating list of deals from Apple, Samsung, Ninja, LG, and tons more. These are the lowest prices of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/best-early-prime-day-deals-apple-samsung-october/"&gt;Amazon Prime Day is happening now and these 100+ deals are worth checking out&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 23:28:21 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Extreme weather now costs Australians $4.5b a year. Better insurance options and loans would help us adapt</title><link>https://theconversation.com/extreme-weather-now-costs-australians-4-5b-a-year-better-insurance-options-and-loans-would-help-us-adapt-266886</link><description>Nearly eight in ten homes facing severe to extreme flood risk are now not insured. We need to rethink how to keep communities safe.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:35:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>হারানো অভিধানের জন্য এলিজি</title><link>https://www.tbsnews.net/bangla/Easel/news-details-397606</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 05:31:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Day deals on Amazon devices: Kindles, Fire TVs, and more at their lowest prices of the year</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/amazon-devices-kindle-fire-tv-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon has almost every device in its stable substantially on sale during the Prime Big Deal Days shopping holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/amazon-devices-kindle-fire-tv-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Prime Day deals on Amazon devices: Kindles, Fire TVs, and more at their lowest prices of the year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:01:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Save up to 43% off popular DeWalt tools with these Amazon Prime Day deals</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/dewalt-amazon-prime-day-tool-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Whether you're an aspiring DIYer or a seasoned pro builder, these DeWalt tool deals deserve a spot in your kit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/dewalt-amazon-prime-day-tool-deals/"&gt;Save up to 43% off popular DeWalt tools with these Amazon Prime Day deals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:01:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon has Celestron telescopes for clearance prices during its Prime Day sales</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/celestron-telescope-prime-day-deals-amazon/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Whether you're an aspiring star gazer or an experienced observer, save on a new telescope during Amazon Prime Big Deal Days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/celestron-telescope-prime-day-deals-amazon/"&gt;Amazon has Celestron telescopes for clearance prices during its Prime Day sales&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:02:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Your furnace probably needs a new filter and almost every Filtrete model is on clearance during Amazon Prime Day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/filtrete-filter-amazon-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Replacing the filter in your furnace or AC unit will improve your air quality and make your equipment last longer. Stock up during Amazon's annual sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/filtrete-filter-amazon-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Your furnace probably needs a new filter and almost every Filtrete model is on clearance during Amazon Prime Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:03:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Just about every Anker gadget and accessory is on sale during Amazon Prime Big Deal Days</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/anker-charger-headphone-vacuum-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Save up to half off chargers, portable power stations, projectors, headphones, robot vacuums, and tons of other Anker products during Amazon's annual sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/anker-charger-headphone-vacuum-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Just about every Anker gadget and accessory is on sale during Amazon Prime Big Deal Days&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:04:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Don’t miss these limited-time Dyson vacuum and haircare deals during Amazon Prime Day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/dyson-vacuum-haircare-amazon-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dyson gear is great, but it's not cheap. These Amazon Prime Big Deal Days discounts make it much more affordable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/dyson-vacuum-haircare-amazon-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t miss these limited-time Dyson vacuum and haircare deals during Amazon Prime Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:05:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out Logitech mice, keyboards, and accessories for clearance prices during Prime Day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/logitech-pc-keyboard-mouse-streaming-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Grab a new keyboard, mouse, webcam, and pretty much everything else you need for a killer PC setup at steep Prime Day discounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/logitech-pc-keyboard-mouse-streaming-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out Logitech mice, keyboards, and accessories for clearance prices during Prime Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:06:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out Greenworks electric mowers, blowers, and other yard tools during its Prime Day sale</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/greenworks-electric-yard-tool-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Greenworks makes electric tools more powerful than their gas-powered counterparts and they're all on sale during Prime Big Deal Days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/greenworks-electric-yard-tool-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out Greenworks electric mowers, blowers, and other yard tools during its Prime Day sale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:08:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Get TREBLAB Bluetooth speakers, headphones, and earbuds at unbeatable prices during Big Deal Days</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/treblab-speaker-headphone-amazon-prime-deal-days/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;TREBLAB’s already-affordable audio gets even easier to grab, with Bluetooth speakers, headphones, and earbuds on sale for Amazon Prime Days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/treblab-speaker-headphone-amazon-prime-deal-days/"&gt;Get TREBLAB Bluetooth speakers, headphones, and earbuds at unbeatable prices during Big Deal Days&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:11:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Do some adulting and grab a NOCO portable car jump starter on sale for Amazon Prime Day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/noco-portable-car-starter-deal-amazon-prime-day/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Consider a portable jump starter an essential part of your car's emergency kit. It might literally save you in an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/noco-portable-car-starter-deal-amazon-prime-day/"&gt;Do some adulting and grab a NOCO portable car jump starter on sale for Amazon Prime Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:15:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Save money and get crafty with these Prime Day deals on Cricut machines and supplies</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/cricut-vinyl-cutter-machine-supplies-amazon-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Score a discounted Cricut vinyl cutter during Amazon Prime Day and make your own stickers, shirts, and anything else you can think of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/cricut-vinyl-cutter-machine-supplies-amazon-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Save money and get crafty with these Prime Day deals on Cricut machines and supplies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:40:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Finally get your desk and gadgets organized with these Prime Day deals on Belkin chargers and accessories</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/belkin-charger-accessories-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon's annual Prime Day sale has Belkin chargers and accessories on sale for clearance prices across the board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/belkin-charger-accessories-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Finally get your desk and gadgets organized with these Prime Day deals on Belkin chargers and accessories&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:45:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Stock up on Sennheiser’s affordable audiophile accessories during Amazon’s Prime Day sale</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/sennheiser-headphone-audio-amazon-prime-big-deal-days/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For anyone craving lush, audiophile-grade listening without a luxury price tag, now’s your moment to save up to 43% on Sennheiser headphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/sennheiser-headphone-audio-amazon-prime-big-deal-days/"&gt;Stock up on Sennheiser&amp;#8217;s affordable audiophile accessories during Amazon&amp;#8217;s Prime Day sale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:47:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Stay hydrated with CamelBak packs and drinkware for clearance prices during Amazon Prime Big Deal Days</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/camelbak-hydration-pack-drinkware-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;These are the lowest prices of the year on Camelbak's entire collection of hydration packs and drinkware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/camelbak-hydration-pack-drinkware-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Stay hydrated with CamelBak packs and drinkware for clearance prices during Amazon Prime Big Deal Days&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:51:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>This 189-piece Craftsman Mechanics tool kit is only $142 with this Amazon Prime Day deal</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/craftsman-tool-kit-amazon-prime-day-deal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Get ready for DIY home improvement projects and other builds with these steep Prime Day discounts on Craftsman tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/craftsman-tool-kit-amazon-prime-day-deal/"&gt;This 189-piece Craftsman Mechanics tool kit is only $142 with this Amazon Prime Day deal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 04:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Stock up on GE Cync LED and smart light bulbs for up to 52% off during Amazon’s Prime Day sale</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/ge-sync-led-lighting-deals-amazon-prime-day/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Prime Day is a perfect opportunity to replace your current light bulbs with GE Sync or LED bulbs on a budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/ge-sync-led-lighting-deals-amazon-prime-day/"&gt;Stock up on GE Cync LED and smart light bulbs for up to 52% off during Amazon&amp;#8217;s Prime Day sale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 04:04:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out Homedics massagers, aromatherapy, and more during Amazon Prime Day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/homedics-self-care-health-fitness-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Homedics makes self-care devices for just about every part of your body. Treat yourself to these deep Prime Day discounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/homedics-self-care-health-fitness-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out Homedics massagers, aromatherapy, and more during Amazon Prime Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 04:15:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Build a smart home security system on a budget with these Amazon Prime Day deals on Arlo cameras</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/arlo-security-camera-smart-home-prime-day-deal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You can create a comprehensive home security system with these high-end security cameras from Arlo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/arlo-security-camera-smart-home-prime-day-deal/"&gt;Build a smart home security system on a budget with these Amazon Prime Day deals on Arlo cameras&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 04:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out Hydro Flask drinkware in every size and color during Amazon’s Prime Day sale</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/hydro-flask-drink-ware-water-bottle-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Everything tastes better out of a Hydro Flask. Right now, you can save 25 percent off of a wide variety of drinkware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/hydro-flask-drink-ware-water-bottle-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out Hydro Flask drinkware in every size and color during Amazon&amp;#8217;s Prime Day sale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 04:42:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Audio-Technica turntables, headphones, and microphones are deeply discounted for Prime Day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/audio-technica-turntables-headphones-microphones-amazon-prime-deal-days/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Whether cueing up a classic, laying down vocals, or slipping into a mix, A-T makes the moment sound right at the right price during Deal Days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/audio-technica-turntables-headphones-microphones-amazon-prime-deal-days/"&gt;Audio-Technica turntables, headphones, and microphones are deeply discounted for Prime Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 04:44:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Was Jesus a Shaman?</title><link>https://nautil.us/was-jesus-a-shaman-1240964/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Three questions for Manvir Singh, author of &lt;i&gt;Shamanism: The Timeless Religion&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://nautil.us/was-jesus-a-shaman-1240964/"&gt;Was Jesus a Shaman?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://nautil.us"&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>These are the best Prime Day deals on power tools this year</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/best-tool-deals-amazon-prime-day-october/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Save on brands like DeWalt, Worx, Craftsman, Greenworks, and more during Amazon's Prime Big Deal Days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/best-tool-deals-amazon-prime-day-october/"&gt;These are the best Prime Day deals on power tools this year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 06:37:12 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>South Africa’s Coast Is Rising—And Scientists Have a New Explanation Why</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/south-africas-coast-is-rising-and-scientists-have-a-new-explanation-why/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Human water management contributes to sinking land across the globe, and it may also be responsible for an unexpected rise&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out JBL speakers, headphones, earbuds, and more during the Amazon Prime Day sale</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/jbl-speaker-earbud-headphone-amazon-prime-deal-days/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Whether you're looking to upgrade your personal audio or get a giant party speaker to bother your neighbors, grab a JBL Prime Day deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/jbl-speaker-earbud-headphone-amazon-prime-deal-days/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out JBL speakers, headphones, earbuds, and more during the Amazon Prime Day sale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 06:56:08 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Nobel prize for physics goes to trio behind quantum computing chips</title><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2499053-nobel-prize-for-physics-goes-to-trio-behind-quantum-computing-chips/?utm_campaign=RSS%7CNSNS&amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_content=home</link><description>The 2025 Nobel prize in physics has gone to John Clarke, Michel Devoret and John Martinis, whose work has led to the development of today's quantum computers</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:58:15 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Anything Could Happen in Iran</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/10/iran-us-israel-sanctions-response/684471/?utm_source=feed</link><description>At most, Iran can hope to wound America or Israel when attacked. But its own weapons can never win a war.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Pretent little ones from becoming iPad kids with these Prime Day deals on Melissa &amp; Doug toys</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/melissa-and-doug-toys-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Melissa &amp;#38; Doug's simple, beautiful toys make fantastic gifts and they're on steep sale during Amazon Prime Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/melissa-and-doug-toys-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Pretent little ones from becoming iPad kids with these Prime Day deals on Melissa &amp;amp; Doug toys&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:01:13 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is blowing out Legos (including Star Wars sets) during Prime Day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/buy-everyone-on-your-shopping-list-legos-during-these-amazon-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Everybody loves Legos. Save 30 percent or more off of popular building sets during Amazon Prime Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/buy-everyone-on-your-shopping-list-legos-during-these-amazon-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Amazon is blowing out Legos (including Star Wars sets) during Prime Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:07:45 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>2025 Nobel Prize in Physics Goes to Researchers Who Brought Quantum Mechanics into the Macroscale World</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/2025-nobel-prize-in-physics-goes-to-researchers-who-brought-quantum/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;John Clarke, Michel H. Devoret and John M. Martinis shared the 2025 Nobel Prize in Physics for their work showing how bizarre microscopic quantum effects can infiltrate our large-scale, everyday world&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First-of-Its-Kind Kidney Transplant Could Lead to More Cross-Blood Type Donations</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/first-of-its-kind-kidney-transplant-could-lead-to-more-cross-blood-type/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Recipient diagnosed with brain death received a type-O organ, which is compatible with all blood types&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The 10 Most Relaxing TV Shows to Help You Unwind at Night</title><link>https://www.mentalfloss.com/entertainment/tv/most-relaxing-tv-shows?utm_source=RSS</link><description>&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9n q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Finding the perfect show to help you relax before hitting the hay can be more challenging than it seems. Episodes of true crime staples like &lt;em&gt;Forensic Files&lt;/em&gt; may render you too anxious to sleep, while the drama on the latest episodes of &lt;em&gt;Grey’s Anatomy&lt;/em&gt; might have you riveted until your alarm goes off. But if you still want to watch &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; before turning in for the night, the anxiety experts at &lt;a href="https://www.amberwillo.com/" target="_blank"&gt;AmberWillo&lt;/a&gt; have you covered.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9o q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="mt-[18px] md:mt-0 mb-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-0"&gt;Finding the perfect show to help you relax before hitting the hay can be more challenging than it seems. Episodes of true crime staples like &lt;em&gt;Forensic Files&lt;/em&gt; may render you too anxious to sleep, while the drama on the latest episodes of &lt;em&gt;Grey’s Anatomy&lt;/em&gt; might have you riveted until your alarm goes off. But if you still want to watch &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; before turning in for the night, the anxiety experts at &lt;a href="https://www.amberwillo.com/" target="_blank"&gt;AmberWillo&lt;/a&gt; have you covered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9q q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;In a recent analysis, they ranked the most soothing TV series based on six criteria, including content rating, episode length, genre, and the presence of frightening scenes. Each show was awarded a score out of 100—the closer to that number, the more soothing the show.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9r q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-1"&gt;In a recent analysis, they ranked the most soothing TV series based on six criteria, including content rating, episode length, genre, and the presence of frightening scenes. Each show was awarded a score out of 100—the closer to that number, the more soothing the show.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9t q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;The programs that made the list offer comfort, familiarity, and just the right rhythm to help you drift off to sleep. The research highlights how television can shape nighttime routines, noting that light, low-stakes entertainment often creates the best conditions for relaxation compared to darker or more dramatic programming.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9u q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-2"&gt;The programs that made the list offer comfort, familiarity, and just the right rhythm to help you drift off to sleep. The research highlights how television can shape nighttime routines, noting that light, low-stakes entertainment often creates the best conditions for relaxation compared to darker or more dramatic programming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9w q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Here are the top 10 shows you should put on as you drift off at night, ranked. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9x q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-3"&gt;Here are the top 10 shows you should put on as you drift off at night, ranked. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9z q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bluey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a0 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bluey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a2 q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8nv1m-aTCZI--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a3 q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a4 q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a6 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;At the top of the list is children’s show &lt;em&gt;Bluey&lt;/em&gt;. The animated Australian program—which features the titular Blue Heeler pup and her family—has become a phenomenon, capturing the hearts of both adults and children. Its family-friendly tone, brief runtime, and gentle humor earned it a score of 93.69 out of 100.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a7 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-6"&gt;At the top of the list is children’s show &lt;em&gt;Bluey&lt;/em&gt;. The animated Australian program—which features the titular Blue Heeler pup and her family—has become a phenomenon, capturing the hearts of both adults and children. Its family-friendly tone, brief runtime, and gentle humor earned it a score of 93.69 out of 100.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a9 q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aa q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ac q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_1024,h_682,x_0,y_0/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k5yqsdr67723g74are--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ad q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ae q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=ae q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=af q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=af q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ag q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ah q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ai q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=ai q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=ah q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="The Cast of Seinfeld" class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="682" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_1024,h_682/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k5yqsdr67723g74are.jpg" title="The Cast of Seinfeld" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The Cast of ‘Seinfeld.’ | David Turnley/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=am q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Close behind is&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/66049/25-yada-yada-yada-facts-about-seinfeld"&gt; &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which received a score of 84.37 out of 100. The classic “show about nothing” has 20-minute episodes and timeless storylines that still hold up in 2025, making it a dependable choice before bedtime. (Fun fact: &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; was never intended to be a show about nothing. As star Jerry Seinfeld said in 2014, “The pitch for the show, the real pitch, when Larry and I went to NBC in 1988, was ‘We want to show how a comedian gets his material.’ The show about nothing was just a joke in an episode many years later, and Larry and I to this day are surprised that it caught on as a way that people describe the show, because to us it’s the opposite of that.”) &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=an q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-9"&gt;Close behind is&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/66049/25-yada-yada-yada-facts-about-seinfeld"&gt; &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which received a score of 84.37 out of 100. The classic “show about nothing” has 20-minute episodes and timeless storylines that still hold up in 2025, making it a dependable choice before bedtime. (Fun fact: &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; was never intended to be a show about nothing. As star Jerry Seinfeld said in 2014, “The pitch for the show, the real pitch, when Larry and I went to NBC in 1988, was ‘We want to show how a comedian gets his material.’ The show about nothing was just a joke in an episode many years later, and Larry and I to this day are surprised that it caught on as a way that people describe the show, because to us it’s the opposite of that.”)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ap q:key=vcaa:10--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aq q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ar q:key=vcaa:&lt;h3&gt;You Might Also Like ...&lt;/h3&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=as q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h3 class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-11"&gt;You Might Also Like ...&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=au q:key=vcaa:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/military-sleep-method"&gt;This Military Technique Can Help You Fall Asleep in 2 Minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/entertainment/movie-tv-adaptations-better-than-books"&gt;These Movie and TV Adaptations Were Better Than the Books, According to Audiences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/quizzes/guess-the-tv-show-based-on-a-synonym-quiz"&gt;Quiz: Can You Guess the TV Show Based on a Synonym?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=av q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ax q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ay q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-13"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b0 q:key=vcaa:14--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b1 q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b2 q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mr. Bean&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b3 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-15"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mr. Bean&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b5 q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_1024,h_682,x_0,y_0/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k5yqv590yvkd2dy8zh--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b6 q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b7 q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=b7 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b8 q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=b8 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=b9 q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ba q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bb q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=bb q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=ba q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="Rowan Atkinson, Matilda Ziegler" class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="682" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_1024,h_682/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k5yqv590yvkd2dy8zh.jpg" title="Rowan Atkinson, Matilda Ziegler" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A Mr. Bean sketch from Comic Relief. | Comic Relief/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bf q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;In third place with a score of 84.2 out of 100 is&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/62455/15-things-you-might-not-know-about-mr-bean"&gt; &lt;em&gt;Mr. Bean&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the British comedy starring Rowan Atkinson. The series—which started as a stage show—is renowned for its physical humor and easy viewing. There are only 14 episodes, but if you’re still craving more Bean, you can always put on one of the movies or the animated series.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bg q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-17"&gt;In third place with a score of 84.2 out of 100 is&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/62455/15-things-you-might-not-know-about-mr-bean"&gt; &lt;em&gt;Mr. Bean&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the British comedy starring Rowan Atkinson. The series—which started as a stage show—is renowned for its physical humor and easy viewing. There are only 14 episodes, but if you’re still craving more Bean, you can always put on one of the movies or the animated series.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bi q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pride and Prejudice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bj q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-18"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pride and Prejudice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bl q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P5MmcT_vcBU--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bm q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bn q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bp q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Fourth place goes to the 1995 BBC miniseries&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/92938/20-fastidious-facts-about-bbcs-pride-and-prejudice"&gt; &lt;em&gt;Pride and Prejudice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, celebrated for its romantic tone and soothing period drama atmosphere. It scored 81.96 out of 100. The series’ sexiest scene—which sees Colin Firth as Mr. Darcy emerge sopping wet from a pond—wasn’t in the novel, and Andrew Davies, who adapted the novel, meant it to be funny, not steamy. “When women started pinning Colin’s picture on their walls, it was a puzzle and a surprise,” he later said. (The shirt Firth wore in the scene sold at auction for &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/entertainment-arts-68415018" target="_blank"&gt;25,000 pounds&lt;/a&gt; in 2024.)&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bq q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-20"&gt;Fourth place goes to the 1995 BBC miniseries&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/92938/20-fastidious-facts-about-bbcs-pride-and-prejudice"&gt; &lt;em&gt;Pride and Prejudice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, celebrated for its romantic tone and soothing period drama atmosphere. It scored 81.96 out of 100. The series’ sexiest scene—which sees Colin Firth as Mr. Darcy emerge sopping wet from a pond—wasn’t in the novel, and Andrew Davies, who adapted the novel, meant it to be funny, not steamy. “When women started pinning Colin’s picture on their walls, it was a puzzle and a surprise,” he later said. (The shirt Firth wore in the scene sold at auction for &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/entertainment-arts-68415018" target="_blank"&gt;25,000 pounds&lt;/a&gt; in 2024.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bs q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;(U.S.)&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bt q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-21"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;(U.S.)&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bv q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uyIVAm9PVrI--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bw q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bx q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=bz q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Rounding out the top five is the U.S. version of&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/60370/21-things-you-might-not-have-known-about-office"&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Office&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which scored 80.11 out of 100 thanks to its comedic tone, extensive episode catalog, and absence of violent or frightening content. With hundreds of episodes available, the series offers endless opportunities for casual rewatching that can ease viewers into rest. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c0 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-23"&gt;Rounding out the top five is the U.S. version of&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/60370/21-things-you-might-not-have-known-about-office"&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Office&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which scored 80.11 out of 100 thanks to its comedic tone, extensive episode catalog, and absence of violent or frightening content. With hundreds of episodes available, the series offers endless opportunities for casual rewatching that can ease viewers into rest.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c2 q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Friends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c3 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-24"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Friends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c5 q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_713,h_475,x_0,y_56/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k5yqzw21c7wym00r7x--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c6 q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c7 q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=c7 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c8 q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=c8 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=c9 q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ca q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cb q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=cb q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=ca q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="1996 THE CAST OF THE TV HIT SERIES &amp;quot;FRIENDS&amp;quot;" class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="475" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_56,w_713,h_475/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k5yqzw21c7wym00r7x.jpg" title="1996 THE CAST OF THE TV HIT SERIES &amp;quot;FRIENDS&amp;quot;" width="713" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The cast of ‘Friends.’ | Getty Images/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cf q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Coming in sixth was&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/56565/25-things-you-might-not-know-about-friends"&gt; &lt;em&gt;Friends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with 79.98 out of 100. The sheer number of episodes—235 over 10 seasons—means the series lends itself to multiple rewatches. Fun fact: The series was originally called &lt;em&gt;Insomnia Café.&lt;/em&gt; (An issue of Mental Floss magazine also makes an appearance in the episode “The One With the Soap Opera Party.”) &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cg q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-26"&gt;Coming in sixth was&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/56565/25-things-you-might-not-know-about-friends"&gt; &lt;em&gt;Friends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with 79.98 out of 100. The sheer number of episodes—235 over 10 seasons—means the series lends itself to multiple rewatches. Fun fact: The series was originally called &lt;em&gt;Insomnia Café.&lt;/em&gt; (An issue of Mental Floss magazine also makes an appearance in the episode “The One With the Soap Opera Party.”)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ci q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fawlty Towers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cj q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-27"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fawlty Towers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cl q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_1024,h_682,x_0,y_0/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k5yr0qr5dtavysj169--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cm q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cn q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=cn q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=co q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=co q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cp q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cq q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cr q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=cr q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=cq q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="John Cleese, Prunella Scales, Connie Booth, Andrew Sachs - Actor" class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="682" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_1024,h_682/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k5yr0qr5dtavysj169.jpg" title="John Cleese, Prunella Scales, Connie Booth, Andrew Sachs - Actor" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The cast of ‘Fawlty Towers.’ | Bryn Colton/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cv q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;The 1975 series&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/80111/13-high-strung-facts-about-fawlty-towers"&gt; &lt;em&gt;Fawlty Towers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;—which was co-created by and starred John Cleese—was ranked seventh with a score of 78.53 out of 100 thanks to its short episodes. Cleese based Basil Fawlty on Donald Sinclair, owner of the Gleneagles Hotel in Torquay, where he and the rest of the Monty Python cast stayed while making &lt;em&gt;Monty Python’s Flying Circus.&lt;/em&gt; Cleese called Sinclair “the rudest man I’ve ever come across in my life.” &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cw q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-29"&gt;The 1975 series&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/80111/13-high-strung-facts-about-fawlty-towers"&gt; &lt;em&gt;Fawlty Towers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;—which was co-created by and starred John Cleese—was ranked seventh with a score of 78.53 out of 100 thanks to its short episodes. Cleese based Basil Fawlty on Donald Sinclair, owner of the Gleneagles Hotel in Torquay, where he and the rest of the Monty Python cast stayed while making &lt;em&gt;Monty Python’s Flying Circus.&lt;/em&gt; Cleese called Sinclair “the rudest man I’ve ever come across in my life.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cy q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Haikyuu!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=cz q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-30"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Haikyuu!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d1 q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JOGp2c7-cKc--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d2 q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d3 q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d5 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;This anime, which ran between 2014 and 2020, came in eighth with a score of 78.35 out of 100 thanks to its short, 20-minute-long episodes and soothing style of animation. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d6 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-32"&gt;This anime, which ran between 2014 and 2020, came in eighth with a score of 78.35 out of 100 thanks to its short, 20-minute-long episodes and soothing style of animation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d8 q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes Minister&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=d9 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-33"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes Minister&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=db q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DGscoaUWW2M--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dc q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dd q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=df q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Yet another British show, the political satire &lt;em&gt;Yes Minister&lt;/em&gt;, was ranked ninth with a score of 78.09 out of 100. It ran from 1986 to 1988.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dg q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-35"&gt;Yet another British show, the political satire &lt;em&gt;Yes Minister&lt;/em&gt;, was ranked ninth with a score of 78.09 out of 100.&amp;nbsp;It ran from 1986 to 1988.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=di q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arrested Development&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dj q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-36"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arrested Development&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dl q:key=vcaa:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zsxdrHgyJtc--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dm q:key=S4yS:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dn q:key=EEns:AJ_0--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dp q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;The final spot in the top 10 was nabbed by the comedy &lt;em&gt;Arrested Development&lt;/em&gt;, which received a score of 78.04 out of 100. If you’re watching it before heading off to sleep, keep your eyes peeled for these&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/50644/20-hidden-jokes-arrested-development"&gt; brilliant hidden jokes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dq q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-38"&gt;The final spot in the top 10 was nabbed by the comedy &lt;em&gt;Arrested Development&lt;/em&gt;, which received a score of 78.04 out of 100. If you’re watching it before heading off to sleep, keep your eyes peeled for these&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/50644/20-hidden-jokes-arrested-development"&gt; brilliant hidden jokes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ds q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;The 10 Least Relaxing Shows&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dt q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-39"&gt;The 10 Least Relaxing Shows&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dv q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_2303,h_1295,x_0,y_0/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k5yqpaxdgty750wjdg--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dw q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dx q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=dx q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dy q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=dy q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=dz q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=e0 q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=e1 q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=e1 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=e0 q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="Couple watch horror movies on the bed with blanket to cover their heads" class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="1295" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_2303,h_1295/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k5yqpaxdgty750wjdg.jpg" title="Couple watch horror movies on the bed with blanket to cover their heads" width="2303" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Avoid these shows if you want to get in a sleepy mood. | WC.GI/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=e5 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;The study also highlighted shows that may not be the best option before bed. The three-season-long &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/554250/facts-about-hannibal-bryan-fuller-mads-mikkelsen"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hannibal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which starred Hugh Dancy, was rated as the least relaxing due to its graphic violence and intense subject matter. Here are the top 10 least relaxing shows in order:&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=e6 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-41"&gt;The study also highlighted shows that may not be the best option before bed. The three-season-long &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/554250/facts-about-hannibal-bryan-fuller-mads-mikkelsen"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hannibal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which starred Hugh Dancy, was rated as the least relaxing due to its graphic violence and intense subject matter. Here are the top 10 least relaxing shows in order:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=e8 q:key=vcaa:&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hannibal&lt;/em&gt;: 5.72/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/524151/10-wild-facts-about-sons-anarchy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sons of Anarchy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: 8.57/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Daredevil&lt;/em&gt;: 10.99/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/557337/facts-about-boardwalk-empire-steve-buscemi"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Boardwalk Empire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: 11.49/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peaky Blinders&lt;/em&gt;: 13.02/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/503229/10-killer-facts-about-dexter"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dexter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: 13.57/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spartacus&lt;/em&gt;: 13.78/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Boys&lt;/em&gt;: 13.91/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/em&gt;: 14.02/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/em&gt;: 15.10/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=e9 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;ol class="!list-decimal ml-5 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-42"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hannibal&lt;/em&gt;: 5.72/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/524151/10-wild-facts-about-sons-anarchy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sons of Anarchy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: 8.57/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Daredevil&lt;/em&gt;: 10.99/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/557337/facts-about-boardwalk-empire-steve-buscemi"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Boardwalk Empire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: 11.49/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peaky Blinders&lt;/em&gt;: 13.02/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/503229/10-killer-facts-about-dexter"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dexter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: 13.57/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spartacus&lt;/em&gt;: 13.78/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Boys&lt;/em&gt;: 13.91/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/em&gt;: 14.02/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/em&gt;: 15.10/100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org"&gt;Adblock test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org/acceptable.html"&gt;(Why?)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:03:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What are ultra-processed foods and are they bad for me?</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/health/ultra-processed-foods-explainer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From frozen pizza to lactose-free milk, food processing takes many forms. Here’s how to tell when it’s helping or hurting us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/health/ultra-processed-foods-explainer/"&gt;What are ultra-processed foods and are they bad for me?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Tory plan to scrap net zero target puts UK climate leadership at risk</title><link>https://theconversation.com/tory-plan-to-scrap-net-zero-target-puts-uk-climate-leadership-at-risk-266853</link><description>The country has enjoyed a unique period of consensus and stability under the Climate Change Act, which the Tories now want to scrap.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:01:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Children are capable of extreme bravery from a young age – a psychologist explains how</title><link>https://theconversation.com/children-are-capable-of-extreme-bravery-from-a-young-age-a-psychologist-explains-how-265523</link><description>Empathy develops earlier than you may realise.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:01:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Virtues of Horror and Gore</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/this-is-america/202510/the-virtues-of-horror-and-gore</link><description>A new book asks: Are morbidly curious people more empathetic and resilient?</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:01:54 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>3 Benefits of "Predictable Warmth" in a Relationship</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/social-instincts/202510/3-benefits-of-predictable-warmth-in-a-relationship</link><description>Ways to build love that takes root, and never leaves easily.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:18:23 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Deception and Desire: How Dark Triad Faces Fool You</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/finding-a-new-home/202506/deception-and-desire-how-dark-triad-faces-fool-you</link><description>A series of studies reveals the secret behind how people with dark personality traits succeed in gaining others’ trust.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:31:18 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>In a Cage: The Inner Life of the Chronically Ill</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/modern-world-modern-mind/202510/in-a-cage-the-inner-life-of-the-chronically-ill</link><description>A Personal Perspective: When chronically ill, you may try to join others in the world, but you will likely be separate from them.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:31:53 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Survive as a Modern-Day Therapist</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/brainstorm/202509/how-to-survive-as-a-modern-day-therapist</link><description>Two psychologists speak on the pressing concerns for the contemporary therapist.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:41:12 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>In Health AI, Explainability Does Not Drive Trust</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/patient-trust-matters/202510/in-health-ai-explainability-does-not-drive-trust</link><description>“Explainability of artificial intelligence (AI) is a foundation of trust" is a frequently heard claim. This may mischaracterize user behaviors and lead AI developers in the wrong direction.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:54:44 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Deal With Grief and Other Difficult Emotions</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-well-being-toolkit/202510/how-to-deal-with-grief-and-other-difficult-emotions</link><description>If you're experiencing grief or other difficult emotions, these 4 strategies can help you through.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:56:04 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Work Hard, Graze Hard: Vermont Ski Resort Hires Goat and Sheep Landscapers</title><link>https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/ski-resort-hires-goat-landscapers?utm_source=RSS</link><description>&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9n q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;The first snowfall in Vermont is expected to arrive within a few months, meaning it’s almost time for skiing season. But the overgrown vegetation at Jay Peak Resort creates less than ideal conditions for the activity. What are the property owners to do? &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/goats-landscaping-ski-vermont-d588be2f8395d35f364b8261292f83a2" target="_blank"&gt;Hire hungry goat and sheep&lt;/a&gt; landscapers, of course.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9o q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="mt-[18px] md:mt-0 mb-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-0"&gt;The first snowfall in Vermont is expected to arrive within a few months, meaning it’s almost time for skiing season. But the overgrown vegetation at Jay Peak Resort creates less than ideal conditions for the activity. What are the property owners to do? &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/goats-landscaping-ski-vermont-d588be2f8395d35f364b8261292f83a2" target="_blank"&gt;Hire hungry goat and sheep&lt;/a&gt; landscapers, of course.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9q q:key=vcaa:--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9r q:key=StMp:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=Lf_2--&gt;&lt;ol class="toc text-primary mt-4 flex flex-col gap-y-2.5 ps-10 list-decimal [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/ski-resort-hires-goat-landscapers?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-2"&gt;Hungry Helpers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/ski-resort-hires-goat-landscapers?utm_source=RSS#inline-text-11"&gt;An Eco-Friendly Alternative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9t q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;Hungry Helpers&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9u q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-2"&gt;Hungry Helpers&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9w q:key=vcaa:https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,w_2119,h_1191,x_0,y_0/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k6nsf28appfh4s7tdm--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9x q:key=VjqC:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9y q:key=deAA:7d_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=9y q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9z q:key=deAA:7d_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=9z q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a0 q:key=cHU9:7d_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a1 q:key=deAA:e2_0--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a2 q:key=B0c2:SZ_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=a2 q:key=--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:s q:sref=a1 q:key=--&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-hidden bg-lightGrey undefined"&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 719px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(max-width: 1079px)" /&gt;&lt;source media="(min-width: 1080px)" /&gt;&lt;img alt="Sheeps in the middle of meadow in the mountains." class="undefined w-full w-full blur-[5px]" height="1191" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_2119,h_1191/c_fill,w_16,ar_16:9,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/GettyImages/mmsport/mentalfloss/01k6nsf28appfh4s7tdm.jpg" title="Sheeps in the middle of meadow in the mountains." width="2119" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;div class="flex items-center gap-4 text-grey font-group-tiny m-3"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Leave it to these guys to level out grass. | Beerpixs/GettyImages&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a6 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Over the course of five weeks, dozens of the hoofed animals will be unleashed on the slopes of Jay Peak where they will eat as many plants as possible before the ski season begins. Resort operators are hoping the sheep and goats clear at least 25 of the 300 acres. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a7 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-4"&gt;Over the course of five weeks, dozens of the hoofed animals will be unleashed on the slopes of Jay Peak where they will eat as many plants as possible before the ski season begins. Resort operators are hoping the sheep and goats clear at least 25 of the 300 acres.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a9 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;The herd belongs to Adam Ricci, owner of the targeted vegetation removal company &lt;a href="https://www.cloudbrook-vegetation.com/"&gt;Cloud Brook Grazing&lt;/a&gt;. He keeps the animals within the designated areas by equipping them with specialized collars that emit noises and deliver mild shocks when they stray outside the boundary. The collars also allow him to monitor their whereabouts and activity levels.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aa q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-5"&gt;The herd belongs to Adam Ricci, owner of the targeted vegetation removal company &lt;a href="https://www.cloudbrook-vegetation.com/"&gt;Cloud Brook Grazing&lt;/a&gt;. He keeps the animals within the designated areas by equipping them with specialized collars that emit noises and deliver mild shocks when they stray outside the boundary. The collars also allow him to monitor their whereabouts and activity levels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ac q:key=vcaa:6--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ad q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ae q:key=vcaa:&lt;h3&gt;You May Also Like:&lt;/h3&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=af q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h3 class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-7"&gt;You May Also Like:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ah q:key=vcaa:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/birds/blue-jay-green-jay-bird-hybrid"&gt;For the First Time, Wild Blue Jay and Green Jay Produce Colorful Hybrid Offspring in Texas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/birds/vulture-nests-contain-centuries-old-artifacts"&gt;Bearded Vulture Nests Found to Contain Clothes and Weapons Dating Back Centuries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/animals/pets/most-popular-pet-names-2025"&gt;The Top 50 Pet Names of 2025, From Bella to Ziggy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ai q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ak q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=al q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=an q:key=vcaa:10--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ao q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ap q:key=vcaa:&lt;h2&gt;An Eco-Friendly Alternative&lt;/h2&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aq q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;h2 class="scroll-mt-24 my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-11"&gt;An Eco-Friendly Alternative&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=as q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;One of the primary goals of the experiment is to reduce the use of gas-powered mechanical mowers. Ricci told the &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/goats-landscaping-ski-vermont-d588be2f8395d35f364b8261292f83a2"&gt;Associated Press&lt;/a&gt; that his animals have been mowing backyards, clearing out abandoned farmland, eating invasive species, and even devouring poison ivy.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=at q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-12"&gt;One of the primary goals of the experiment is to reduce the use of gas-powered mechanical mowers. Ricci told the &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/goats-landscaping-ski-vermont-d588be2f8395d35f364b8261292f83a2"&gt;Associated Press&lt;/a&gt; that his animals have been mowing backyards, clearing out abandoned farmland, eating invasive species, and even devouring poison ivy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=av q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;In addition to being more cost-effective, the goats and sheep are environmentally friendly. The practice, known as “goatscaping,” mitigates the carbon emissions of landscaping, prevents soil erosion, and enhances an area’s ability to retain water. In return the animals get an all-you-can-eat buffet. The only downside is that the rate at which they eat is much slower compared to the speed of traditional machinery.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aw q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-13"&gt;In addition to being more cost-effective, the goats and sheep are environmentally friendly. The practice, known as “goatscaping,” mitigates the carbon emissions of landscaping, prevents soil erosion, and enhances an area’s ability to retain water. In return the animals get an all-you-can-eat buffet. The only downside is that the rate at which they eat is much slower compared to the speed of traditional machinery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ay q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Regardless, the owner of the herd hopes to eventually work on a larger scale, taking his livestock to other ski resorts where they can chow down on as much vegetation as they please. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=az q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-14"&gt;Regardless, the owner of the herd hopes to eventually work on a larger scale, taking his livestock to other ski resorts where they can chow down on as much vegetation as they please.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org"&gt;Adblock test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org/acceptable.html"&gt;(Why?)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:02:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Get a Sonos soundbar or headphones for their lowest price of the year during Amazon Prime Day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/sonos-speaker-amazon-prime-big-deal-days/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Get an immersive home theater experience for less with up to 26% off Sonos soundbars &amp;#038; more during Amazon's annual Prime Big Deal Days sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/sonos-speaker-amazon-prime-big-deal-days/"&gt;Get a Sonos soundbar or headphones for their lowest price of the year during Amazon Prime Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:05:05 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon is clearing out Ego battery-powered yard tools during its Prime Big Deal Days sale</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/ego-battery-powered-yard-tool-prime-day-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Grab a new lawn mower, leave blower, trimmer, snow blower, and pretty much anything else you need to care for your space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/ego-battery-powered-yard-tool-prime-day-deals/"&gt;Amazon is clearing out Ego battery-powered yard tools during its Prime Big Deal Days sale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:08:40 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Your Brain's CEO and the Full Life</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/platonic-psychology/202510/your-brains-ceo-and-the-full-life</link><description>Productivity isn't enough. Discover how your brain's executive function helps determine whether you live a meaningful life or an empty one.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:10:32 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How Arguments Go Wrong—and How Bad Arguments Can Go Right</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/critical-thinking-corner/202510/how-arguments-go-wrong-and-how-bad-arguments-can-go-right</link><description>An introduction to the structure of deductive arguments, how to evaluate them, and why a bad argument doesn’t necessarily mean the conclusion is false.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:10:48 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>California turns down the volume on streaming ads</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/loud-tv-ads-ban-california/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SB 576 expands on 2010's CALM Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/loud-tv-ads-ban-california/"&gt;California turns down the volume on streaming ads&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:28:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Brain's Need for Friends</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-innovator-next-door/202510/the-brains-need-for-friends</link><description>Many people may associate the brain with internal processes, such as thinking. Yet social health also relates to the brain, with interactions being rewarding.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:29:49 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Polk Audio is offering room-filling sound at reasonable prices during Amazon’s Big Deal Days</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/polk-audio-speaker-amazon-prime-big-deal-days/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are top-notch Polk components at deeply discounted prices during the Amazon Prime Big Deal Days sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/polk-audio-speaker-amazon-prime-big-deal-days/"&gt;Polk Audio is offering room-filling sound at reasonable prices during Amazon&amp;#8217;s Big Deal Days&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:30:09 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Would You Risk Your Well-Being to Help Someone You Hate?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/fulfillment-at-any-age/202510/would-you-risk-your-well-being-to-help-someone-you-hate</link><description>People may like to think of themselves as selfless, but a new international study of ingroup bias shows just how hard it is to overcome the factors that divide us.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:31:34 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Children's Defiance Makes Couples Fight—and How to Stop It</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/challenging-kids/202510/why-childrens-defiance-makes-couples-fight-and-how-to-stop-it</link><description>Your child defies. Your partner yells. Suddenly, you're fighting. Here's why it happens and how to break the cycle.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:51:14 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>What True Couple Communication Really Means</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-psychology-of-relationships-and-emotional-intelligence/202510/what-true-couple</link><description>We argue, blame, and scream, and think we've "communicated enough." But true communication is the active, ongoing search for common ground, and many couples avoid it.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:58:48 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How billiard balls led to plastic everywhere</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/plastic-ivory-billard-balls/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The drive to save elephants had some unforeseen conservation consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/plastic-ivory-billard-balls/"&gt;How billiard balls led to plastic everywhere&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Can You Decipher These Translated Song Lyrics? Tune Twist Quiz #61</title><link>https://www.mentalfloss.com/quizzes/tune-twist-quiz-61?utm_source=RSS</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class="ff-og-image-inserted" src="https://images2.minutemediacdn.com/image/upload/c_crop,x_0,y_0,w_3840,h_2160/c_fill,w_1440,ar_1440:810,f_auto,q_auto,g_auto/images/voltaxMediaLibrary/mmsport/mentalfloss/01jpjgsgkfs5ges2cm3g.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9n q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;In Tune Twist, we run the lyrics of a hit song through multiple languages, then translate them back into English. All October long, we’re featuring songs that wouldn’t be out of place on your Halloween party playlist. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9o q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="mt-[18px] md:mt-0 mb-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-0"&gt;In Tune Twist, we run the lyrics of a hit song through multiple languages, then translate them back into English. All October long, we’re featuring songs that wouldn’t be out of place on your Halloween party playlist. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9q q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Here’s a hint to help you figure out this week’s quiz: The music video for this 2009 song features a dancing werewolf dressed like Michael Jackson. The song was also part of a mashup with a Jackson song on the TV show &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/posts/glee-tv-show-facts"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Glee&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 2011. &lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9r q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-1"&gt;Here’s a hint to help you figure out this week’s quiz: The music video for this 2009 song features a dancing werewolf dressed like Michael Jackson. The song was also part of a mashup with a Jackson song on the TV show &lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/posts/glee-tv-show-facts"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Glee&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 2011. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9t q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;Can you figure out what the song is, or who performed it? Test your deciphering skills and your musical knowledge below.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9u q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-2"&gt;Can you figure out what the song is, or who performed it? Test your deciphering skills and your musical knowledge below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9w q:key=vcaa:https://www.riddle.com/embed/a/u0ywxQg9?--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9x q:key=SRoa:mL_1--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=9y q:key=EEns:oZ_1--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a0 q:key=vcaa:4--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a1 q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a2 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a3 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Mental Floss as a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=mentalfloss.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;preferred news source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a5 q:key=vcaa:6--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a6 q:key=fOK1:mL_1--&gt;&lt;hr class="w-full border-0 my-4 bg-lightGrey h-1" /&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a7 q:key=vcaa:&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take Our Latest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/quizzes/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Quizzes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=a8 q:key=lY4S:mL_1--&gt;&lt;p class="my-[18px] [&amp;amp;_a]:text-primary my-f-1" id="inline-text-7"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take Our Latest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/quizzes/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Quizzes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:key=QW_2--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=aa q:key=vcaa:https://content-enrichment-service.mmsport.minutesvc.com/oembed?url=https://content-enrichment-service.mmsport.minutesvc.com/properties/mentalfloss/embeds/01j6yxa15b2gmq4--&gt;&lt;!--qv q:id=ab q:key=jBas:mL_1--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;!--/qv--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org"&gt;Adblock test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blockads.fivefilters.org/acceptable.html"&gt;(Why?)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:03:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The most popular Bose headphones and speakers are at their lowest prices of the year for Prime Day</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/bose-headphone-earbud-speaker-amazon-prime-big-deal-days/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Save up to 45% off Bose headphones, earbuds, and speakers during Amazon's annual Prime Big Deal Days sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/bose-headphone-earbud-speaker-amazon-prime-big-deal-days/"&gt;The most popular Bose headphones and speakers are at their lowest prices of the year for Prime Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:35:25 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Trolling a Cry for Attachment?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/our-devices-our-selves/202510/is-trolling-a-cry-for-attachment</link><description>Do you have a troll in your life? It may be a bid for connection.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:35:46 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Babies’ Brains Recognize Foreign Languages They Heard before Birth</title><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/babies-brains-recognize-foreign-languages-they-heard-before-birth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Babies process foreign languages they heard in utero much like their mother tongue, researchers find&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Where Are the Boundaries of Consciousness When the Brain Can Be Connected to AI?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-behavioral-microbiome/202510/where-are-the-boundaries-of-consciousness-when-the-brain-can</link><description>A new wearable device connects AI directly to the brain, enabling a silent dialogue. This could redefine our identity, consciousness, and agency. Where does the self end, and the machine begin?</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:52:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Our Collective Mood Contagious?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/a-buoyant-life/202510/is-our-collective-mood-contagious</link><description>How shared stress is syncing our emotions — and six simple practices that will spark a seismic shift toward civility, compassion, and connection.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:09:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Turn Self-Criticism Into Self-Compassion: A Path to Healing</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/making-change/202510/turn-self-criticism-into-self-compassion-a-path-to-healing</link><description>Your inner critic doesn’t have to define you. Learn how to shift self-doubt into compassion and begin a journey of healing and self-love.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:10:53 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>A Teen’s Death and What It Says About AI</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/understanding-suicide/202510/a-teens-death-and-what-it-says-about-ai</link><description>A 14-year-old boy’s suicide after chatting with an AI companion reveals how easily technology can imitate empathy—and how dangerously humans can believe it.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:25:34 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Surgical tools could get a bug-inspired upgrade</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/environment/sawfly-inspired-surgical-tools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Female sawflies can cut into a plant's tissue without destroying the rest of the plant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/environment/sawfly-inspired-surgical-tools/"&gt;Surgical tools could get a bug-inspired upgrade&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Our pick for best value powered bookshelf speakers are on sale for Amazon Prime Big Deal Days</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/edifier-powered-desktop-speakers-amazon-prime-big-deal-days/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Edifier’s MR5 2.0 is a true crossover pick—musical enough for hi-fi listening, but neutral enough for creators who need an affordable entry point into production. And it's 20% off for a limited time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/edifier-powered-desktop-speakers-amazon-prime-big-deal-days/"&gt;Our pick for best value powered bookshelf speakers are on sale for Amazon Prime Big Deal Days&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:35:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>No More Sour Grapes: Mourning for Personal Continuity Through Life</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/finding-mind/202510/no-more-sour-grapes-mourning-for-personal-continuity-through-life</link><description>Staying connected to our desires for an alternate reality while moving forward with the reality that is helps to keep us whole and healthy.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:42:42 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Perfectionism Is a Poor Defense for Emotional Vulnerability</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/perfectionism/202510/perfectionism-is-a-poor-defense-for-emotional-vulnerability</link><description>Perfectionism, at bottom, is a defense against one's sense of emotional vulnerability, which, counterintuitively, often aids in one's development, relationships, and health.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:02:43 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>A Path of Empathy—One Mother’s Choice to Forgive</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/esprit/202510/a-path-of-empathy-one-mothers-choice-to-forgive</link><description>Learn how Scarlett Lewis transcended loss to create a social-emotional curriculum that teaches love, belonging, and peace worldwide.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:37:20 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>70+ hand-picked Prime Day deals you should shop right now: Tools, electronics, home goods, and more</title><link>https://www.popsci.com/gear/best-amazon-prime-day-october-deals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We're spending the week seeking out the absolute best Prime Day deals across every category to make your shopping experience simpler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/gear/best-amazon-prime-day-october-deals/"&gt;70+ hand-picked Prime Day deals you should shop right now: Tools, electronics, home goods, and more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com"&gt;Popular Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:38:56 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Hidden Cost of Resistance</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-subplot/202510/the-hidden-cost-of-resistance</link><description>When we fight reality, we keep ourselves stuck. Learning to accept what we resist is the first step toward freedom.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:14:05 -0400</pubDate></item></channel></rss>